Chapter 567

The battle was over and the victorious Huo Qiang rose up from the watery depths. The gravitational area that reached up to a hundred meters shrunk down to a tiny air bubble that only encompassed his body. He was certainly drained and any further fighting would result in injury. Luckily he wasn’t alone here and Zhang Zhi was quick to appear next to the victorious Qiang.

“Senior Qiang, leave the rest to me.”

“Ha, I shall do that, I don’t want to admit it but that took out more from me then I expected… nevertheless, senior brother Dong is truly unfathomable.”

“That he is, without the Patriarch the sect truly would have been lost.”

“That is true…”

The two warriors exchange meaningful glances while the man they were discussing was listening to their conversation. He wasn’t sure how he should react and while it didn’t affect him when people outside of his friend circle praised him, it was different when someone like Qiang did.

‘Those two will make me blush if they continue and they should really find a better moment to praise me…’

While Huo Qiang had been victorious and the general had turned into a fish, this was not over. The army of mermen and their sea beasts was still there. Their leader agreed to surrender if he lost but it didn’t seem that the rest agreed with him. The next in line wasn’t having it and the battle was underway.

‘Both the leaders are out but Qiang shouldn’t take that long to recover and I can boost his recovery rate.’

With the help of the improved faction system and the prestige unit function, he could insert spirit points to recover Qiangs and Zhi’s lost Qi. To not let this fight drag on too much and to minimize the loss of life, he decided to use some of those spirit points that were gained by Qiang to recover his lost stamina.

It was quite fun to see the grown man be surprised by the sudden alleviation of Qi depletion. With him back to full health and the vastness of his army the battle continued. His side had an advantage but not to the point of not suffering any damage. However, thanks to Qiang’s returned vigor victory was assured and in a few hours, the entire area was filled with the corpses of sea creatures.

‘I can really leave it up to my troops with this one…’

Zhang Dong’s biggest issue in the past was the weak state of his clan and sect. Without him around to take out several of the top cultivators they never had a chance of winning anything. Now on the other hand his people had caught up and could finally count themselves among the truly powerful. Even the forces from the invading Empire couldn’t count them out anymore.

‘This system is truly a tremendous help, without the enhancement to the faction system this wouldn’t have been possible…’

Everyone that was in his faction and around the Golden Palace was receiving a large buff to their power. Every time a battle took place his forces would be given it. The more his faction grew the more points he would receive and the more he could spend on improvements. It was like a snowball tumbling down a cliff, it had grown to a size that it could not be stopped anymore.

‘I should have the two clear up any of the enemy armies in the sea to get more points, then distribute them accordingly…’

Two of his prestige units were now working almost full-time to get him more spirit points. With how many of the clones the Cerulean Empire produced this came easy. There were also a lot of those turtle islands left over that could be now reclaimed. His scientists were also working on adapting the cloning technology to their beasts. If they could produce battle tigers or dragons to aid them further then he could stop worrying about losing human lives as much.

‘Maybe I should dump some points into the tamer side of things, I’m not sure if we can quite copy the way these sea people are controlling their armies.’

He believed that the armies of the Cerulean Empress were controlled either by her or some other powerful cultivator. They were like one unit and never bickered over anything, the only person he saw with a glimpse of self-thought was that one general. Perhaps the control she had over her people dwindled depending on their power level.

‘Maybe those generals are like my prestige units and she can only control a set number of them at a time…’

This somewhat made sense as with the cloning technology that those people possessed there was no reason not to make more high-quality soldiers. That is if there weren’t any drawbacks, one of them could be limited control and another lack of proper materials. Either the general-level mermen required rare treasures to produce or the more there were of them the harder it became to keep them in check. The one Qiang faced seemed to at least have his own ego.

Thus after the battle was won he continued to only monitor the situation while sending out orders here and there. Instead of being directly involved in the battles, his people were more than eager to show their worth. After seeing the increase in power that Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang went through, everyone was motivated.

Words of the massive victories that his forces were achieving reached the furthest reaches of the Azure Empire. This coupled with the passive approach of the Azure Emperor and the Heavenly Crane Sect put more faith in the Golden Dragon. Would this however be let to continue or would someone try to break this rise to power?

…

‘That about does it… but is it a bit, what’s the word… risque?’

What he was looking at was a thin dress that was made for his wife. This thing took a lot more time to make than the sword for Zhi or the armor for Qiang. One reason was the various rare materials that it was made from and another was the design. He could not decide on one over the other but could also not ask his wife for input as it was supposed to be a present.

The end product was very flowy and would make Liena look like a dancing nymph if she flew around in the sky. At first, he wanted to add a window for her chest but decided that his wife’s parts were meant for him and him alone. This dress could change forms as well, if Liena was forced into close-range combat she could quickly transform into a more fitting appearance.

Then there were the two emerald battle fans. The right one was jade green and had a phoenix image on the back. The other one was someone more golden and had a dragon to represent himself. Together they would combine his and her Daos to help her achieve a similar level of power as Huo Qiang.

‘She had trailed a bit behind him but with these, they should be about equal. If I give it to her now, however… there might be a problem…’

While the treasures were ready and he just needed to spend the ever-increasing spirit points to make Liena part of his prestige units, he was a bit afraid. He feared that his wife would see the power increase as a chance to use it. His intention was to protect her and his children but in this case, she would endanger her own life.

“It’s still better if she is stronger and a closer part of the system…”

There was a little theory he was working on. If it came out true then having Liena be one of his prestige units was a good move. This he would only figure out after the Overseer confronted him again. Thus after contemplating again he activated the teleportation function and appeared back at his home, New Spirit Spring City.

“Hah, haven’t been here in a while…”

His original home where he spent his early marriage days had been destroyed by Wang Long. For a short time, he had to move his family to a separate villa but now his old home had been restored. The whole city was back to the way it was and it was as if the attack never happened.

In fact, the number of citizens had been steadily increasing. Even though just recently the whole place had been almost flattened everyone quickly returned to rebuild. Then after the consecutive victories against the demi-humans and merpeople, the fame of the city continued to increase.

Everyone wanted to be a part of the new world order that his sect was shaping up to be. Merchants crowded to be the first ones to trade in the new wares. Young martial artists were preparing for the coming sect trials for outer disciples, everyone wanted to be part of this new faction that was shaping up to overtake the old powers.

The teleportation spot was in the secret room he appeared while Wang Long was terrorizing the city. This structure that was used as a flying fortress had been buried under his home yet again but this time around his wife had access to it. Even now he remembered her chewing him out over the development. Luckily she let it slide due to the fact that he managed to actually survive and come back.

“Everything seems peaceful and everyone is moving on with their lives…”

When straining his senses just a bit he could hear the citizens going about their days. Everyone was busy living their life as best as they could. New relationships and goals were forming even as he walked through these spacious halls. His home was large but not many people were allowed to come in. He liked the silence, no one besides some personal maids and servants were allowed to be here.

Just like before his home was raised up into the sky. Perhaps after all of this was over he would replace his old home with the Golden Palace. At least for now he preferred this place as it did have more memories. The sound of his daughter's voice entered his ear which made him stop and smile.

“When is daddy coming back home?”

‘I guess I shouldn’t keep them waiting, no telling when I will need to leave again.’

With a spring in his step, he moved toward the room where both his children and wife were staying. When opening the door the sight on their faces brought nothing but joy and reminded him why he was doing all of this in the first place. Those bright smiles were the reason he could move on and would surely be victorious in the end.

Chapter 568

Days turned into weeks and those into months. The fighting continued with the battles turning from large ones into more minor skirmishes. The western regions that the demi-human invaders previously attacked had been fully cleared out and all the stragglers apprehended. With the help of the treasure from the Long Clan, it was possible to track some of the stronger members with ease.

The demi-humans were used to being the hunters but not the hunted and lacked the skills for hiding. With time even the weaker members were apprehended. Some of them were of course killed while others were imprisoned. The cultivators were quite interested in the body-refining skills that the demi-humans were in possession of. While the Sect leader wasn’t so keen on having his people turn into monster-like beings it didn’t hurt to learn from that strength and adapt the refining skills to their own.

Thus the western front of the entire empire returned to normal and was now going from a rebuilding stage. Cities were being repopulated and the small and middle-sized sects that fled and were still alive returned. They were able to reclaim their old lands depending on how well they treated their populace. Sects that were similar to the old Dark Palm sect were removed from the chessboard.

This new land would be populated by the more righteous ones that needed to follow along with the new giant that was the United Element Sect. While the commoners and weaker cultivators were quite fond of the new leaders the rest weren’t as ecstatic. Old clans and people that ruled these lands would remain to hold a grudge and look for a chance to reclaim their past glory.

To the east on the other side, the war continued to flood the lands with blood. The Emerald Phoenix Emperor had made their appearance and taken over a central city in that area. Everyone wanted to express their indignation towards the passive Azure Emperor and Heavenly Crane Sect that these lands mostly belonged to. The Golden Dragon showed everyone that it was possible to fight back which caused a silent uproar. The people didn’t voice their complaints out of fright but everyone’s belief in the emperor was at an all-time low.

Rumors of strange golden knights with queer techniques started circulating. Due to their appearance, they were groped up with the Golden Dragon of the West. They did clash with the Emerald Phoenix Empire and even drove back some of the forward forces in the southeast. Later on, they had been officially announced to be allies of the United Element Sect. With their help, some of the bloodshed was stopped and the battles in the lower eastern regions stagnated.

Then there was the north sea which was in constant turmoil. Word of strange sea creatures going up against the new United Element Army was the hottest topic in the empire. Some people see this as a chance to gain some scraps. The monsters that were being murdered weren’t strong but for lesser sects and clans it was a treasure. Pills and tinctures made from their bodies could help foundation establishment cultivators take that one step further.

…

“That’s what our spies have figured out.”

“Is that all? What are we paying them for? These are just the same as rumors, nothing substantial.”

A man was shouting in a disgruntled voice at a group of old men. Everyone had gathered in a large room that looked like an old auditorium. The man was wearing a long white robe with a black crane symbol over a red circle. Around him were various men and women of advanced ages nodding their heads while looking at the thin elder in the middle.

In front, there was a red light that took the form of a certain young-looking man. Due to the red shading the white hair that he was known for looked more pink than usual. Everyone here knew who he was as his deeds were known throughout the empire.

“Grand Elder, due to the state of affairs we aren’t able to send out the best scouting units, this is as much as they could find and the Long Clan has remained silent.”

“Those damn bastards, they will sooner let us burn than help out against the upstarts…”

The old man generated a burst of energy that sent a burst of wind through the whole auditorium. Some of the elders that were here were close to passing out but voicing their discomfort was not allowed.

This was a meeting between high-ranking Heavenly Crane Sect members. They had lost a big chunk of their eastern territories that were under the Emerald Phoenix Empire ownership now. Previously the Empire was mostly divided between them which had the east and the Soaring Dragon Sect which owned the west. The Azure Emperor had a small chunk of land right in the center that was exceptionally potent.

Their connection to the Long Clan was through the central spirit vein. Both they and the Soaring Dragon Sect received access to it but the distribution wasn’t equal. The Azure Emperor received half of its concentration while the other two sects only had a quarter. After the other sect fell they were planning on a fifty-fifty split but then another problem arose.

This Emerald Phoenix Empire was making their life difficult. Their forces steamrolled through the lower eastern regions and quickly reached the middle ones that could only bunker up in their main cities behind their grand formations. They were quickly losing ground and people were forced to retreat to their main cities. Now they were constantly on the edge of disaster while fighting against the Saint Emperors.

These were the nascent soul counterparts but just slightly stronger. For the time being, they managed to protect their bottom line but the enemy forces continued to gain ground. Perhaps if the golden soldiers that appeared in the southeast regions didn’t appear they would have had to even retreat further.

“Grand Elder please ease your anger…”

“... My apologies, I have let my emotions get the better of me. Our great sect has stood through the ages and we must not allow it to fall. The enemies are strong but they are not invincible… let me hear your opinions, Elders.”

The old man gave out a sigh while looking at the holographic image of Zhang Dong. No one really knew what they should make of this man. Were the demi-humans and the merpeople he and his sect was going against on par with the Emerald Phoenix Empire? There was information about that sect defeating the demi-human Emperor but no one could really confirm his true strength.

For all they knew, Zhang Dong could have been a late-stage nascent stage cultivator. Only when Wang Long was destroyed did their interest increase. While they couldn’t measure the power of the demi-humans the demonic cultivators were another thing entirely. The man leading them was able to destroy their rival but this could also be a red herring. What if the demons had depleted their power with constant infighting and Wang Long was too injured to do anything?

“I say we wait, even if those Emerald bastards reach our gates they will never be able to break through our grand formation.”

“I concur, as long as our main sect survives and we don't lose access to the central spirit vein, we can rebuild!”

“That’s only if we can last through the siege! What about Grand Elder Zimo? He couldn’t even face one of their generals in single combat!”

“He must have been ill-prepared, if we just…”

“You just want to sit on your hands for years and let them build up an army? Are you crazy, we must counter-attack if not with our own forces then with the help of others!”

“We can’t bring outsiders into our territory! Do you really want to seek help form the Azure Emperor?”

“No the Azure Dragon won’t help us… that one will always remain neutral as history told us, the one that we need help from is his brother.”

The heated exchange between the elders stopped when the Azure Dragon and Golden Dragon were mentioned. This whole meeting was mostly due to how the western side had been able to contain the spread of war and they couldn’t. There were two options, one was to stem the tide and remain in their central city.

It was a fortress not much weaker than that of the Azure Capital. However, after the fall of their equals that were the Soaring Dragon Sect, they started getting cold feet. Their minds were filled with thoughts of failure and death. The only thing making them ignore that incident was that it happened from the inside. As long as they didn’t have someone from the inside deactivating their grand formation they felt secure.

“You all know what it will mean if we ask for help from the Golden Dragon and his forces, right?”

The grand elder raised his hand, and the moment he did all the other old people in the room quieted down. While it wasn’t treason to ask for help, getting it from someone able to contend for the Azure throne could spark a civil war. If Zhang Dong put his sights on the throne and helped them out then he could ask for their aid.

“We don’t know which of the brothers is stronger… this Zhang Dong could be an old monster or a frog in a well, if we get involved in their squabble we might sentence our sect to ruin…”

The grand elder asked while a old woman from the crowd stepped up to reply.

“Do we have a choice though? The Emperor will not help us, he would sooner retreat to his flying palace and wait just like his ancestor did. You know the forgotten records, as long as the Long Clan can run away they will…”

“Aye… if what the old records say is true, then we won’t be able to contend with this threat by ourselves… We shall give this thought and vote on this matter in a day, please consider all the outcomes my brothers and sisters as this decision will decide our faith. I will go inform the Patriarch while you all contemplate the issue.”

The old man retreated from the meeting room while some of the elders remained seated and started meditating over the problem. On one hand, they could try to remain vigilant in their beliefs, their sect was strong and they had a deep pool of secret old monsters still capable of fighting.

Their grand formation couldn’t be broken easily but the forces of the Emerald Phoenix Empire were vast and united. It was as if going against a combined big three sects with a strong Emperor leading them. Their side was unwilling to help, and their Emperor was more concerned with their own safety. Could the Empire require a switch, could switching to a Golden Emperor be the only way of survival…

Chapter 569

“It’s been going well, a bit too well…”

Zhang Dong was looking at the big monitor screen in his office. There he could see the map of the entire empire and how his forces were able to push back the fish people. While he wanted to attribute this to his people performing well and improving this wasn’t the entire truth.

“Why do they keep throwing these generals at us constantly? Do they think that sooner or later our forces will tire and falter?”

After Huo Qiang defeated the first general of the Cerulean Empire he didn’t let up. They continued throwing the exact same army at them with a pallet-swapped general. Even though they had some grand titles like the four Cerulean Generals they looked exactly the same with a few changes in their armor and hairstyle.

“Their names almost sound the same, the first one was Tritton, then came Triggon and the third one was Tragron. The difference in power wasn’t even that great …”

Tragron the third general was a bit more troublesome which required the involvement of Zhi but he didn’t amount to much either. The armies he was leading continued to feed his forces with all the leftover materials and the number of spirit points he was receiving was tremendous. With all those points he could ramp up his manufacturing plant, even if the opponent got stronger he could offset them by simply giving his forces more weapons or better versions of them.

This was exactly the strategy that let his forces be victorious over the fourth and last general of the bunch. With the combined might of Huo Qiang, Zhang Zhi, and a few nascent soul masters that were utilizing a grand attacking formation the man was taken down. With the addition of spirit points, his prestige ‘units’ were able to level up further. This they needed for the fifth appearance of a new general, this one with another name but the same appearance.

It was clear that the cloning technology of the Cerulean Empire was paramount. They just restored their entire army and tried attacking them with the first general again. His power was even identical but now after progressing this much Zhi was able to kill him even without the help of the additional skills given through the faction system.

“Could this actually be a grinding spot for system users? Normally the leader would be the one to appear after the generals get smoked. Instead, they restarted the scenario from the first part…”

This strategy only made sense in this kind of world. Considering that system holders were from the modern world and probably had a gaming background, they would certainly use this exploit to gain more power. It was possible that the being behind this wanted to give the more brain-dead system holder a chance of victory. With this amount of enemies to slay even the most untalented one would be able to get some power.

“Is this just a precaution or a necessity though?”

There could also be another possibility of this grinding break. There could actually be a potential threat out there that required this many spirit points. As it stood now he was looking at two or three people that could potentially threaten him. One was the current Cerulean Empress that hasn’t shown herself.

Then there was the Emerald Phoenix Emperor that was turning the eastern regions upside down. That guy in particular was somewhat worse than the demi-human emperor. He came from an orthodox cultivation world and performed warfare as a cultivator would. This meant that they would uproot everything, no one was safe, not even mortals or lesser cultivators.

In this world filled with strange scenarios, it wasn’t that odd to find some secret immortal heritage. Even one person that was left alive could become an earth-shattering grandmaster that could potentially come seeking vengeance. To prevent this from ever happening all enemies had to be erased from the face of the world. Anyone with a semblance of talent that had been too long in the opposing faction was a potential threat.

The only way they would be willing to let someone like that live was by binding their souls to their side. At least the demi-humans didn’t care about such things, they hunted for fun and weren’t afraid to let some people go. They even craved the challenge of fighting someone that empowered themselves through the pursuit of vengeance.

“My forces are spread thin already but if I leave them be…”

Zhang Dong remained on the western side for a few reasons. One was just a lack of power and forces to defend his people. The second one was fear of losing his loved ones. Both of these problems were now somewhat resolved with how Zhi and Qiang were progressing. Even his wife started taking part in the grandest which gave him an ample supply of spirit points.

While they were getting stronger he was left with not much to do. He had tried meditating on his Dao but his seed wasn’t really reacting and the progress was stalled. By his calculations, it would require many years of pondering and training to level up his Daos. The path was long and boring but it was still on the safer side.

In reality, he didn’t really need to push as hard as in the past. The eastern regions might fall but the Azure Emperor was still in the middle to act as a buffer between him and the Emerald Phoenix Empire. The more sensible thing to do would be to wait, the Long Clan could at least halt one of the invaders while he contended with the other one.

“But if the Heavenly Crane Sect falls and they reach the Long Clan, my dear brother might ask for help…”

That was one of the problems that he didn’t want to get involved with just yet. If he was called over he would need to contend with that Overseer. For the time being, he wanted to remain as far away from that woman as humanly possible. If she caught on that his system was different then his life and his family’s life could be over.

“Nevertheless… this is kind of boring…”
Zhang Dong stood up and after taking a few steps he was teleported out of this room to his own house. There he saw a marvelous garden filled with trees, flowers, and even spiritual herbs. His wife had designed it as a spot to relax and have tea parties with others.

At the moment his children were outperforming their own daily routine. Zhang Xiu his daughter was being trained by his disciple Zhang Xue while her brother was performing the same with Zhang Jun. It was a bit strange to have his disciples train his kids but they knew all the basics and foundation of his own technique. They would be capable enough and a bit stricter than he could be with them.

“Jun has gotten quite into it now, he spends most of the day training and Xue has gotten more serious too since he started showing promise…”

It seemed that his kids were in a competition now. The younger brother wanted to show that he was worthy of the title of Patriarch’s son. This of course made the older sibling try harder, she did not want her younger brother to catch up, even less after seeing that he was actually talented.

To Zhang Dong, it seemed that both of them were competing for his affection which could produce a problem down the line. He at least hoped that the two wouldn’t undermine each other's progress. It was a scenario old as time, children of a clan head would try to one-up each other just to impress their father and gain more cultivation resources. It was quite a widespread phenomenon around young masters.

“It shouldn’t really be a problem though, it might have been if I had like three or more sons.”

In the cultivation world resources were everything. Even top experts couldn’t equally spread them between their children. It was normal to give more to the ones that showed more promise and were more serious about their training. Thus some naturally progressed faster than others and were rewarded for it and the gap kept increasing.

This approach didn’t really sit too well with Zhang Dong. Even when a child showed promise in the early stages of their life it didn’t mean that when they got older it would continue. The same came for the ones that were slower. Many times the ones that needed to work harder in the early days built up a strong work foundation. When they hit a wall they were more likely to work through it but the ones that had an easy life wouldn’t be capable of passing any type of roadblock as they didn’t gain the required skills.

“Think I’ve read this one in my past life, a talented child is a special needs child, if you’re not careful they can be left behind in the later stages of their life.”

Keeping that in mind he didn’t want to show favoritism between his two kids. Even if Jun had more lenient talent than his sister he wasn’t allowed to praise him too much. Both his kids needed to progress at their own pace and he needed to watch his words. Anything that he said could be blown out of proportion by the young minds and affect them for the rest of their life.

“Being an adult sure is hard… even now I don’t know how others do it…”
While going through this peaceful garden he focused on his kids that were quickly progressing. By the rate they were improving, reaching core formation in their early teens wasn’t a pipe dream. This rate of progress was incomprehensible to people that needed hundreds of years for the same result. This however wasn’t only their fault as the world stippled everyone's progress.

“I bet reaching core formation in your thirties would be the norm when brought up near a spirit vein but then the problems start. With the world blocking the hidden realms and no clear path of progress out there…”

There was no clear path laid out toward the immortal stage. All records pointed to a handful of people being allowed to reach it. They had all been system holders however, without it there was no way the people could reach it as a hidden force was preventing them from opening their Dao.

‘I really hope that getting to that immortal stage is the right path, if that being is much stronger then…’

“Hm?”

While contemplating his choices again he noticed that there was some movement in the sect. A group of cultivators was approaching from afar and they were wearing robes that he had seen before.

“Heavenly Crane Sect? What do they want?”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 570

“Halt, identify yourselves!”

“You dare block our path? Who do you think that you are?”

“Elder, please calm down, we didn’t make the proper arrangements with the sect…”

“Stop, do not cross the gate if you do, you will be apprehended!”

‘What are those people doing…’

Zhang Dong had just been wondering what he should do about his slow progress. His cultivator army didn’t really need his help and he was left to cultivate alone. With time spirit points would come to him and if an Emperor level enemy appeared he could always use his system to teleport to either Zhi or Qiang. Thus when he saw an interesting group of cultivators approach his city it piqued his interest.

They came in a rather small group of ten members, quite a small delegation for the name they were carrying. The Heavenly Crane Sect was the faction they belonged to and they carried themselves as people that belonged to one of the big three. The leader was a nascent soul elder at the late stage, this was quite the achievement. A person like this would have been able to be the Patriarch of a middle-sized sect if they wanted. Instead they were arguing with some foundation establishment guards at the entrance to the city.

If this was any other city then these people would probably be wined and dined. Instead however, they were getting pushback by people that were ordered to treat everyone equally. There weren’t any forces in the empire left that his United Element Sect needed to bow their heads to.

The guards were just doing their job and it was normal for them to be confused. It was strange for someone from a large sect like that to just arrive at their doorstep without any plans. Normally someone would send some kind of letter or messenger to announce themselves. It was strange for them not to set up a meeting with some high-ranking elder in the main sect before coming here. They would be then guided through a VIP gate but instead, they were trying to make it through the one used by regular people.

“They won’t get mad and attack the guards right?”

Zhang Dong didn’t really fear for the safety of his people. Even though the opponent was a late nascent soul stage master, he was still on sect grounds. The protective array would keep him from being able to penetrate inside. Even now it was keeping him from approaching the main gate without being given the right to enter by the guards. The shouting match started after the elder was bounced back by the invisible shield that wouldn’t let outsiders in.

‘He won’t be able to blast his way in but my people can attack him from safety… but It probably wouldn’t be too great if a person from that sect died…’

There had to be a reason for this unannounced meeting. In fact, he didn’t believe that anyone from his sect had ever interacted with the Heavenly Crane Sect themselves. Perhaps they didn’t send any letters or notices because they didn’t know how. Thanks to the faction system his people started to communicate differently than the rest of the empire. Relay stations that worked like radio stations and satellites were implemented along the entire western side. People were switching to instant messaging over comunication jades which could have led to the problem as well.

“Hm… will they handle this well… I don’t really want to start my relations with that sect by having their elders get hurt…”

This was a strange sight to behold but there had to be a reason that they were here. Could the east have already been overrun by the Emerald Phoenix Empire and they were seeking refuge here? This was probably not true as he could just consult his world map to see that the enemy troops had not reached the central Empire or the core regions of the Heavenly Crane Sect.

“They could also just be people that believe that their side will lose, could they be attempting to stay here and wait the war out?”

His side had proven itself to be strong and after driving back the demi-human scourge refugees kept flooding. Some people that could see the bigger picture would abandon even the central and core eastern regions. If they believed that it was just a matter of time before their lands would be overrun then this was a good choice. While the Long Clan was probably their first option they wouldn’t help anyone with this war until the enemy was on their doorstep.

“It wouldn’t be good if I get involved, should I send someone out before those people get trashed?”

Zhang Kuo was out helping Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang with the war effort up north. Zhang Ya, his second long-time retainer remained in the city and this was the perfect chance to use her radiant smile and people skills. He knew that cultivators that were part of the big three had a big ego but this was the first real interaction between the two camps, it was better to show some leniency.

“Zhang Ya, there are some guests from the Heavenly Crane Sect at the northern gate, look into it before things get out of hand.”

The woman received a voice message through the faction system and was quick to get to work. She arrived within a minute at the scene with an assortment of beauties behind her. Her position in the sect as the Patriarch's secretary made everyone spread to the sides and also caused confusion within the Heavenly Crane Sect.

“Let me introduce myself, I am Zhang Ya of the United Element Sect. Could you explain why delegates from the Heavenly Crane Sect have come to our doorsteps?”

Zhang Dong watched with interest as Ya worked. She gave a lot of face to the other side and it would be interesting to see if the other side was cordial as well. Previously the elder at the front was shouting at the guards that continued to diffuse the situation. Probably if he didn’t send the woman over a fight could have broken out. However, damaging his sect and threatening his citizens wasn’t allowed even for people of high status.

“Finally someone with some sense! Young girl, open up the gates and let me speak with your elders. The words that I bring aren’t meant for people of your status.”

Zhang Ya was just a core formation cultivator which normally would make her unworthy of exchanging words with a nascent soul master. That would be the case if she wasn’t part of his inner circle, even a nascent soul master couldn’t offend her as the Patriarch’s presence followed her every step. She knew that outsiders wouldn’t know this and was intelligent enough to not spoil the first encounter with a sect that on paper was on equal footing as theirs.

“Friends from the Heavenly Crane Sect, is it? Which elder do you have in mind?”

“Which one? The one with the most status of course?”

“Most status? Do you wish to meet with the sect Patriarch in person?”

“I see that you understand, now make way for this Sun Shi, I’m sure your Patriarch wouldn’t want you to wait for this important meeting either.”

“An important meeting that had not been scheduled? Who do you think our Patriarch is!?”

Zhang Dong raised his eyebrow as Zhang Ya exploded with anger. All the sect members that were here started glaring at the small group of cultivators and even some of the defensive weapons were pointed at the group now. While the cultivators defending this location weren’t strong by themselves the weapons that they were using would be troublesome for even a nascent soul master.

“You dare to threaten us, we are of the Heavenly Crane Sect!”

“What of it, we are of the United Element Sect! We are the law here and you best yield if you do not wish to offend!”

‘Well, this turned around quickly… why do those old farts always think that they are above others…’

He wanted to flick the old man’s forehead for acting as if he owned the place. It was clear that this elder was still living in the past and thought that this place was unworthy of his presence. After all the guns and attacking formations gathered around their group in a matter of seconds he was quickly realizing that he made a mistake. Being a high level cultivator he obviously knew that the level of defense here was immense.

“Please uncle Shi, calm yourself. Friends of the United Element Sect appease your anger, we did not come here to fight, we came for debate with your leaders.”

Luckily before he needed to intervene a small girl that looked to be in her early teens jumped out in front of the angry old man. By the way, she referred to the old man. It was clear that she was part of his family and also the only one daring enough to cut him off.

‘I guess the young girl has more sense than the old man but Ya went a bit overboard too.’

He expected Zhang Ya to be able to handle the situation without a fight breaking out. Instead, she almost allowed the delegation to be attacked by their spirit bullet cannons. Perhaps she wanted to scare them into submission instead but he wouldn’t really know until the deed was done.

‘I guess I’ll need to think about procedures in situations like this, maybe send in a nascent soul elder with a silvery tongue.’

The conversation continued with the little lady speaking out and apologizing. Her uncle didn’t look amused but he just turned his head away as the two females talked.

“So you wish to offer a bargain to our leader and this you hoped to achieve without a proper audience?”

“We apologize immensely but there was no other way to do this…”

The girl kept bowing before Zhang Ya and her words started to intrigue him. What could these people want from him and his army? Could there perhaps be trouble brewing from within the Heavenly Crane Sect? If their forces faltered and the eastern regions fell then even he would need to get involved. With how the situation north was progressing he couldn’t really spare any troops.

‘Hm, will I have to get involved myself? That would save me from this boredom before that Empress made her move…’

Before the conversation between the two parties could continue a booming voice spread from all directions.

“Let them in, I’ll speak with them shortly.”

It was a very simple message but no one refused to comply. It was very surprising to the group of cultivators that came from outside to have the path opened within a few seconds of the voice speaking out.

‘Hope this is a worthwhile endeavor but at least they can inform me about what is happening in the east in detail…’

Thus he vanished towards the usual meeting room where he expected the delegation to be sent promptly.

Chapter 571

“It’s been a while, should I wear the golden royal robe or the white ceremonial one… maybe going with the usual will make me seem more relatable, they might get scared otherwise… but the old farts will complain if I don’t look properly again…”

Zhang Dong was looking at the large assortment of robes that his wife forced him to have. Each time he had to go to some kind of meeting and she was around he was forced to wear a new one, the old ones were then disposed of and remade into something else. To this day he didn’t get the fascination with clothing that people had, if it was up to him he would wear the same pair of pants for the rest of his life. In this world where materials could last for millennia, it wasn’t a pipe dream.

The people from the Heavenly Crane Sect were now inside the city. They were being transported by a small flying ship towards the main sect where they would be checked for any serious weaponry. Disarming people from other powers that didn’t make an appointment should be obvious but he could see that late stage nascent soul master kicking up a fuss.

“There are only a few early stage masters in the sect, the only one that could match him is Zhi, Liena or Qiang… I might have to get some elders up to the middle stage at least.”

While he wasn’t planning on making the new nascent soul elders into his prestige units, he could still boost their cultivation with the help of the faction system. It wouldn’t be as efficient and they wouldn’t gain any special skills through it but they would get stronger. With the amount of points he was getting from wiping out the fish people this would actually be one of the next steps.

“However, I should level up those three first and also decide on the two remaining spots, should I give it to gramps? or maybe Qiang’s father but that guy didn’t really earn something like this…”

Qiang’s father had on several occasions tried to go against him. Whenever Zhang Dong was gone and the power shifted to the Huo side of the sect they attempted to force their way. It wouldn’t be strange if he insisted that his wife got married to his son if he never returned. He did trust Qiang but his father was another thing.

When it came to Zhang Jin then his age was slightly a problem. His capabilities as a commanding officer were over his fighting strength. He was already an early stage master and could be further enhanced through normal means. Giving him a special battle skill through the prestige unit system might not have been the greatest idea. Even now he wasn’t really interested in training but having fun at his new position.

He wasn’t as hungry as the younger generation as he had somewhat given up on his progress ever since being stuck at the core formation stage for a hundred years. Only when Zhang Dong appeared did he start progressing further but this required a big investment of spirit points.

“The system isn’t a miracle solution and it's harder to make people with shaky foundations stronger, it would be much better to invest in someone with a better future.”

Zhang Jin’s potential had been spent, the only reason Zhang Dong invested in his grandfather was that he was someone he could trust. But there were two other people that he trusted just as much, his two disciples that in the long run would even require a lesser investment of spirit points. Their foundation was strong and their will to train even stronger, it would be much better to finance the two than tired old elders that had no will to endanger their lives anymore.

“The two aren’t really ready to ascend into the nascent soul stage yet at most I can help them get half a step into that realm…”

Both of his students were following his old Dao of heavenly lightning but they did not fully grasp it yet, forcefully pushing them into the next realm without them understanding it would slow down their growth in the future. They needed to have the knowledge of getting through some bottlenecks because if not, they might falter later in life.

“If I push it too soon, they might remain at the early nascent soul stage for the rest of their lives.”

He was pushing for progress quite fast as the looming threat of the overseer was there. What he wanted was for his loved ones to be able to protect themselves after he was gone. If he ascended to the immortal stage then his presence would be gone. All the records pointed to all immortals being rejected by this world and pushed out.

A thing like a will of the world apparently existed and it forced some laws onto this realm. One of them was that no immortal was to reside in this lower ‘mortal realm’. Anyone that made it past the nascent soul stage would be going against the will of the world and their only hope of survival was to leave it. If they didn’t they would be assaulted by tribulation lightning until they were dead.

Some records say that certain immortals were able to postpone their departure by a slither before either succumbing to the lightning or venturing into the heavens. Perhaps thanks to his Dao of Heavenly lightning he would be able to postpone it longer than others but perhaps not. For this reason, he needed to leave a seed behind, one that would lead his people in his stead.

Zhang Xue and Zhang Liu, both of his disciples whom he treated like younger siblings might have to do this. His children were next in line in terms of succession of power but they needed trusted retainers that would keep them safe. If either of his disciples became the new Patriarch or if it was his children didn’t really matter to him. As long as both of them continued to work with each other when he was gone then it would be fine.

“I don’t think I need to worry about that, Xue treats Xiu and Jun as if they were her own children. Jun is a bit stricter but he just expects my kids to follow in my footsteps.”

Xue acted like a younger mother while Jun was taking on the mantle of a stricker father. Even during the training sessions, he was a bit stricter than his sister. However, whenever the training was over he would give Jun some good pointers. This worked out well as he didn’t need to play the villain to strengthen his own children when their uncle was enough.

“Well then, it's time to listen to what these people have to say.”

Sun Shi was the elder's name and he came together with a small group of core formation experts. One of them looked to be one of his family members and the only person that dared to raise their voice whenever he was speaking.

“Why is it always an old fart and a granddaughter combo…”

It started in the past but for some reason, a powerful elder always had a beautiful granddaughter around them. It was as if those granddaughters were there to diffuse the situation. It slightly made sense as the powerful elders could not really lower their heads and be cordial even if they wanted. They needed to seem strong and ready to eradicate all opposition.

“Those granddaughters are good at diffusing the situation, could it be another setting in this world…”

He shrugged while pointing towards one of the golden robes. In retrospect, it was better to look like a proper godly being surrounded by gold than a bum. The people meeting him will be more likely to tell him everything if they see him as a force to be reckoned with. Thus it was time to present himself as one of the most powerful experts on the face of this cultivation world.

“Though I’ll never understand why they were these rectangular small hats… wouldn’t a proper crown be better? These beads always get in the way if I walk too fast… Oh well…”

Soon he vanished from his private dressing room wearing one of the golden robes. The sleeves were long and flowy and he was sure to radiate his usual golden aura. There would be no malice in it but the man he was going to meet would certainly realize how powerful this Patriarch is.

…

“Grandfather, what do you think of this place… the city was…”

“Yes, it was peculiar… the standard of living of those regular citizens is quite high, I didn’t expect to see something like this in the lower regions. Then there is the Qi quality… they must be hiding a spirit vein. It's not as strong as the central one but also not far behind.”

The people from the Heavenly Crane Sect had been all allowed to enter the main sect grounds and flew all the way up to the palace in the sky. They had heard about a strange gold fortress that this sect was in possession of but this one wasn't. Even then the grandness of the structure wasn’t behind anything that their sect was used to. This Sect was new but it certainly wasn’t behind them and they had to admit that the United Element Sect had the right to be part of the big three.

“..however, while the structures and lands are exquisite I’m not sure I can say the same about their cultivators, they seem to be lacking compared to ours.”
“That is true, perhaps their experts are all out in the north?”

“That might be possible but they should have more to spare…”

While the city was large and prosperous there was a lack of powerful cultivators. The ones that appeared before them were early stage, nascent soul masters. It looked like the weapon level of this sect outpaced the power of their experts. Cultivation realms were still the most prominent measure of power and prestige so it didn’t sit well that they were being kept waiting by people of lower strength.

“Maybe the red faction was right and they aren’t capable of helping us?”

Asked the granddaughter while looking around the lush meeting room. It was a bit different than the ones they were used to as they were all sitting by a table on quite comfy chairs. Before them was a huge door that for now remained closed but would probably be used by this sect’s Patriarch.

“I hope not but if that is true then perhaps I have made the wrong decision…”

Sun Shi frowned, he was hoping to gain some help from this new upstart but if this was the level of their power then the journey had been wasted. However, as he was slowly giving up hope a powerful aura surrounded the entire room. It was as if an ancestor had awakened who could be this powerful, could it really be the United Sect Leader… and could he have heard their conversation and been maddened…

Chapter 572

The small group of cultivators was stunned as the expert made his way through the large entrance. No one could take their eyes off the man that was slowly venturing through the room threshold. He radiated a brilliance that they weren’t expecting, much more than any other elder or grandmaster they had come across. It was at the level of an old ancestor that was at the cusp of breaking through into the immortal realm.

‘Huh, some of them actually went slack-jawed, did I overdo it with the shiny aura?’

Zhang Dong asked himself while slowly walking to the main chair in the royal meeting room. He was against it but Zhang Jin insisted on giving these places a royal prefix after his true roots were discovered. He was part of the empire's royal family but if he followed the succession laws then he would have no right to the throne.

The next in line would be the current Emperor’s children and only after them, it was his turn. Though in a world ruled by might, if the strongest cultivator that was the Azure Emperor vanished then he could probably circumvent the laws if he so desired. Of course, the Long Clan would not allow that without a bloody battle.

Then even if he didn’t get involved, probably some of the elders residing there would try to get the crown for themselves. This was what usually happened when the head of a sect or clan died and there was no proper successor present. Even the kids of the current Emperor would need to be backed by the other elders, the three grand elders in particular.

If for some reason two of them didn’t agree with the succession then a civil war could break out. Everything depended on the goals of the individuals, some elders craved positions of power while others just wanted to be part of the most powerful sect. The more subfactions in a faction existed the weaker it became, this was the same for his United Element Sect which when he was gone went through some turmoil . Luckily his presence was so large that they managed to hold out for five years for his return.

‘This couldn’t be about some succession war right? Could they want to ally themselves with me to overthrow the Azure Emperor?’

This was a wild idea but it wasn’t as outlandish as it might seem. The Heavenly Crane Sect was in a bad position, from the outside it looked like it was the weakest of the big three of the empire. After the collapse of the Soaring Dragon Sect, it was supposed to be the second in command but the Emerald Phoenix Emperor destroyed that notion. They had been constantly losing their land and getting backed into a corner.

On the other side of the Empire, this wasn’t the case for the upstart Sect that Zhang Dong established. They had pushed back all of their enemies and even cleared out the island populated by the demonic cultivators. News of a spirit vein being there had reached the inner circles of the other sects. They were clearly on the upswing while the Heavenly Crane Sect was on a quick decline.

‘Can’t discount that, perhaps that will be one of their talking points…’

While he wasn’t sure about teaming up with this sect to take care of his brother he couldn’t discount the idea. After the Emerald Phoenix Empire and the Cerulean Empire were gone they would go back to the usual power struggle between sects and clans. He did not wish to go to war with his brother but this didn’t mean that he wouldn’t be asked to make concessions.

Having such a large army that was growing each day wouldn’t fly well with the other large factions. It wouldn’t be strange for a new conflict to arise and it finishing with another confrontation. When this happened it would probably be better to have a deal made with the only people capable, which were the Heavenly Crane Sect cultivators.

‘But going by what they were constantly whispering about, they are here for help against those Emerald cultivators…’

Zhang Dong made sure to place them in this room where he could listen in on the conversation without the other party knowing. Thanks to his system he could see everything written down before him. It was always good to know what you are debating about and these people were here to ask for a favor. This service that they wanted to ask of him wasn’t something that he needed to follow through. There were no previous arrangements or deals made between these two sects so he wasn’t sure why they were here with this small group.

‘Do they expect me to jump in just because of their old name or something? Their sect name carries millennia of prestige but they should know that such things don’t matter when talking to someone on the same level… do they perhaps think less of my sect?’

Finally, it was time to stop with the speculations and hear them out. Thus after sitting down and lessening his cultivation he spoke out. The others were still a bit stunned by his appearance and were probably fearful of beginning the conversation first. This shifted the situation in his favor and put his side as the one in control, at least for now.

“Greeting friends from the Heavenly Crane Sect, If you send some word my people would have given you a better reception but I am glad that it was resolved without it affecting anyone's dignity.”

“Ah yes… haha… This Sun Shi greets Long Dong the Golden Dragon of the west.”

Try he did but it seemed that he wouldn’t be able to escape from that title. His older brother and his whole clan were still the more famous ones. Even the people in his sect weren’t sure what to call him as having the title of Golden Dragon was in their mind an honor. Most of them liked the idea of their leader being part of the royal family as it gave validity to their sect.

They did not see anything wrong with it, the only ones against it were mostly from the Zhang side of the clan that wanted their leader to retain his old clan name. When historians uncovered the records they wanted the name Zhang Dong and not Long Dong to be remembered as it immortalized their clan.

“So you do know that title but you will have to explain to me why you have appeared before me, as you might have heard the war rages in the north, I don’t have much time to spare for trivial conversations so I would have you give me the reason for your coming.”

“Uh…”

The elder that previously was looking at animosity at his gate guards was acting like a meek kitten. He probably didn’t expect Zhang Dong to be so much stronger than himself. The power difference was above what this man probably was used to as regular nascent soul cultivators at the great circle level weren’t this imposing. This display of might was of course one of the oldest tactics in this world.

The other side would think twice before withholding information or acting rashly in front of someone that could tear them apart with one finger. However, he couldn’t keep it up for too long as most of the people before him were only core formation experts. The moment he increased the intensity they would probably pass out almost instantly. Thus for the time being he leaned back in his seat while smiling and letting the man speak.

“Of course, I must seek the Golden Dragon’s forgiveness for this unannounced visit. We are truly grateful that you have accepted our coming at such short notice, your magnanimity knows no bounds the legends of your generosity…”

‘Man this guy knows how to crawl up someone’s ass, look at him go.’

It was a bit funny to see a late stage nascent soul elder throw around this number of praises. The people around him were even surprised as they probably only saw someone of this status only act as a grumpy senior. Now on the other hand he needed to prostrate himself before someone stronger and remember all the way he kissed ass before he became a nascent soul grandmaster.

“That’s enough, Sun Shi was it? Just get to the point before you make the people that came here with you blush.”

The old man looked around and could see that everyone including his granddaughter had their heads down. They knew that the old man was trying to get on the good side of this Patriarch but seeing him lower himself to this extent was a bit traumatizing. Seeing a pillar of support for their sect acting like a fangirl wasn’t something that they expected to see when they came here.

“Very well… we have come to ask you the Golden Dragon… for aid.”

“You want my help? Is the situation in the east this bad? What about my brother, shouldn’t you ask him first?”

“”The Azure Emperor is…”

The old man wasn’t sure what to say which was only natural. He had no idea of knowledge of the relationship between the two dragons. There were only unconfirmed rumors of them either being at each other's throats or acting like the closest brothers. If he insulted Zhang Dong’s brother in any way that could be it, the talks could be ended abruptly and they could even lose their life.

Normally the Heavenly Crane Sect wouldn’t need to worry about such things but at the moment they were apparently backed against a corner. It wouldn’t be strange if their competition saw this injured giant as prey. It was quite a risky tactic to even send people into the bowels of the golden beast. No one really knew Long Dong’s true character, just that his armies were conquering all the lands. To some, he would seem like a warmonger that could turn his sights on anyone after the invaders were gone.

“Did he decline the offer or did you not even bother because you knew the answer he would give you?”

The old man didn’t answer while Zhang Dong started rubbing his chin and speaking his thoughts out loud.

“That does sound like my brother, he probably won’t make a move until the enemies are right at his doorstep.”

To ease the tension he waved his hand around nonchalantly in dismissal of the Azure Emperor. He wanted to give the old man the idea that he didn’t think that much of the Emperor and was not afraid to speak ill of him.

“I’m sure the great Azure Emperor has his own things to worry about…”

“Better things than the survival of his empire? Well, in his case he probably sees the Long Clan as the only worthwhile part of the empire that is worth saving.”

It seemed that he hit the bullseye as the old man only replied with silence. It wasn’t strange for the clan or sect leaders to only look out for their own faction members. However this was a whole empire and not just the long clan, in the people's eyes the Emperor had a duty of coming to their aid which he wasn’t.

“Well, I’ll stop prattling on about my dear brother, how about you tell me what you really want but first tell me of how things look in the east…”

“I… Of course, great Golden Dragon…”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 573

“Hoh? So it’s this bad already? Shouldn’t you have some defenses built up in some of those cities, wouldn’t that one mountain range have been a good place for a fortress… or that place filled with stormy winds…”

“That was an oversight by our elders, we never expected something like this to have happened… but it’s all that Long Clan’s fault, they clearly knew about this disaster coming, why they never went past the central region, why they decided to focus all of their forces in one area! It was all to sacrifice us as pawns!”

“Now, now, Elder Sun Shi, calm yourself, it's not like I’m blaming you or anything…”

He was putting the blame on them but not for the lack of information. They had enough years to push some of their resources to different regions and create defensive measures that would last them more than a week or two. As it was now, the Emerald Phoenix Empire just steamrolled through their lands as if they were nothing.

This of course was due to the culture of this place. The large sects would see the smaller ones as tax zones and nothing more. They wouldn’t invest any of their own resources in the middle-sized sects, instead they would weaken them. This was expected but if the Long Clan informed everyone this could have been prevented. They clearly knew about the bridges and where they existed.

‘I can’t tell them but this is probably because of that Overseer Empress… she must have made it so that the Long Clan never cooperates with the others. It would have been an easy task to use the millennia they had to prepare.’

His sect was able to create barricades at the locations of the two bridges from the demi-human side. After their emperor had died there were some small skirmishes but nothing that could get past the stronghold. Now they would probably remain there without anything being able to slip past them. This could have easily been fashioned with the help of the Long Clan resources. They didn’t even need to hurry as this happened every hundred thousand years or so.

‘They were the only ones that survived the previous attack and probably also the ones that withheld the information. They want everyone else to be a shield and use their flying city to escape if things get too spicy…’

At first, he didn’t think much of it, he attributed it to the setting of the world and how the cultivators were. Most of them just stuck to their own faction and didn’t care about the other but now he wasn’t that sure anymore. The people around him began changing and there became a lot more magnanimous. But that wasn’t even the biggest reason, it didn’t actually go in line with how these cultivator nuts operated.

First of all, if the Long Clan knew of the four invading forces that came from all sides, wouldn’t they have at least tried to prepare? They had almost a hundred thousand years to make some changes, and create special sects to act as bodyguards or vanguards. Normally they would have been scared into acting, the only reason they wouldn’t care would be that they were convinced that they weren’t in any danger at all.

‘Can you be that sure of your victory though? Wouldn’t it be better to tell everyone and let them prepare something? or did they think that the other sects would just continue to bother them about resources and aid?’

Zhang Dong didn’t really get it, he would have at least tried to reinforce the areas where the bridges were. It was clearly possible to halt the advances of those empires which he proved by taking out the forward forces by himself. If it was possible for him to achieve this by himself then the Azure Emperor should have been able too.

Even the other large sects would only require a few more nascent soul elders and some other troops for the same effect. It was possible to hold the invaders at the borders if all the three grand sects worked together with each other and prepared for it.

‘Chicken and the egg scenario… were they affected by the overseer to act this way or is this just how they are, selfish and fearful…’

“I must apologize for my behavior, I also insulted the Golden Dragon’s brother in his presence.”

While he was thinking about what to do the old man along with his entourage started bowing all over the place. It might have seemed that he was being remorseful about his words but in reality, he was prodding for information. Through the conversation, the other side clearly realized that Zhang Dong didn’t fear the Azure Emperor and didn’t care if someone talked badly of him.

“It’s fine, he’s not here but you better stop while you're ahead, I do know what you are doing and trying to pit me against my brother won’t work.”

“I didn’t… I mean I wouldn’t…”

Zhang Dong’s aura rose in the room and started causing the core formation experts to faint while their mouths filled with foam. It was clear to him that the other side wanted to push him against the Azure Emperor that looked like the villain here. He was withholding his help from everyone and the Heavenly Crane Sect elder wanted a target that they could team up against.

The intention was clear, they wanted his help against the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. The man here probably thought that Zhang Dong wanted to prove himself. If he was able to defeat the Emerald Phoenix Emperor when his brother couldn’t then the validity of his power could not be disputed. As it stood at this time people still weren’t sure where to place him on the power scale. It was possible that the demi-human strength had been over-exaggerated and the United Element Sect was just lucky.

If he defeated the Emerald Phoenix Emperor whom the Heavenly Crane Sect was suffering greatly against, then it would be another thing. This sect had lasted through tens of thousands of years and had a long history of victories. It would cement his place as a potential new Emperor and also in-depth this sect to him which normally wouldn’t be a bad idea.

“I do not wish to swipe the throne away from my brother, this would only weaken this Empire and the blood of my sect members is not something I want to have on my hands, at least not for something this meaningless.”

“M-meaningless?”

Sun Shi was stunned at the reply as for a person like him there was no greater honor than being the Emperor of these lands. It was not an empty title as the Azure Emperor title was always in the hands of the strongest cultivator. This had been true for millennia and Zhang Dong actually had the right to challenge the man for that title. With the help of the Heavenly Crane Sect, it would be possible to force a confrontation, perhaps even a one-on-one battle.

“But I digress, in short, you wish me to lend you a few of my people to clear out some of the critical locations and push back the invaders, right?”

“Y-yes, that’s right.”

Sun Shi gave out a sigh of relief as Zhang Dong’s aura returned to normal. Everyone else that was in the room had passed out so only the two elders were left. While they were talking the silent guards that weren’t part of the conversation moved in to carry the people out and to let the two seniors discuss things between them.

“Don’t worry, they will be taken care of. Now for your request… Do you actually think that I would accept something like this? That I wouldn’t realize that you are going behind the back of your leader to do this?”

“Aye… the Golden Dragon is truly wise, you have figured out everything, this old man might not be suited for politics…”

Sun Shi gave out a sigh while dropping his head. Zhang Dong had figured out long ago that something was fishy here. No one from that sect sent any words and instead, this one elder appeared.

“Now tell me the truth.”

“As you wish… The truth is, we really need help but the council of elders wasn’t able to decide yet.”

“So, you were of the mind of asking me for help and decided to go behind your elder council’s back?”

The man just nodded while looking dejected.

“I truly am regretful, please Golden Dragon show mercy, this was a lapse in my judgment, please don’t punish the juniors.”

“Punish?”

“This old man will pay with his life for this misdeed!”

“Now hold up…”

Zhang Dong’s eyes almost popped out of his head as he saw the old man trying to sink his whole palm into his own dantian. The man was trying to cripple himself and regress into a mortal out of fear. In Sun Shi’s eyes, he came under false pretenses and tried to swindle a powerful entity into a battle with enemies that he didn’t know. Besides the talk about becoming the new Emperor, he was also offering some treasures and spoils of battle.

“There is no need for that, I’m not going to kill you or your juniors so calm down.”

He wanted to give out a sigh after seeing the man going for self-mutilation. It was something that he had forgotten existed after spending his days together with his people. They knew that he wouldn’t really punish anyone. However, to other people outside the sect, he could be considered a person that they couldn’t antagonize. It wouldn’t be hard for him to kill all of them and not even report it to the Heavenly Crane Sect, at this point they wouldn’t really be able to complain as the man visited them of his own volition.

“You won’t? But I tried to …”

“Well, you’re probably not used to handling things like this. I also have this stuff taken care of by some of my people, I know the feeling.”

Sun Shi was stunned to see Zhang Dong just shaking his head and shrugging as if it wasn’t a big deal. Any other big wig cultivator would have told the old man to slap himself at least fifty times before allowing them to speak.

“To be honest I was interested in what was happening in the eastern front, if you continue to inform me about what happens there I might even help you out…”

“You would?”

“Yes, but you’ll have to follow some of my directions first so let me explain…”

Zhang Dong smiled while taking out a special item from his spatial ring. It looked like a regular paperweight but in actuality, it was a savepoint he could teleport to. While he wouldn’t be willing to take the trip himself this man could take this to a place he could pop out from and investigate that war-torn region.

‘This way Liena won’t even know that I left…’

With the teleport in place, he could safely travel to where the action was without worrying anyone from his inner circle and mainly his wife. He would of course tell people like Zhang Jin so that in case of distress the golden dong palace could be activated to come to his rescue.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 574

‘It never ceases to amaze me how large this world is, it’s like I’ve arrived at an entirely new planet or something…”

Zhang Dong spread his senses into all directions and noticed various things that he had never seen before. The beasts were different, the plant life varied and evolved in a strange way compared to what he was used to. Even the clothes that people were wearing were unique to this part of the Empire that he now arrived in.

“Honorable Golden Dragon… are you sure about this?”

“Yeah, there is no problem but you’ll need to drop those honorifics, just call me Ching Li or something, I’m just a bodyguard for your granddaughter.”

“Ah yea, of course…”

The group of cultivators led by Sun Shi performed the task that they were given to their utmost ability. They were far too afraid that Zhang Dong would kill them if they went behind his back and informed their more prominent elders about this issue. While Sun Shi was a late stage nascent soul elder and part of the elder council, he was not part of the top brass that was made up of people a minor realm higher.

What had happened after their introduction to this man was a quick journey back home. They were given the right to use the teleportation gate of the United Elemental Sect and arrived really close to the central areas owned by the Long Clan. It was astonishing that this new power could have expanded this fast and could even afford to create such large gates everywhere.

They were quite surprised to see that these gates were brand new and quickly being established everywhere on the western side of the empire. Sun Shi was able to ascertain names on the teleporter list corresponding to some large cities previously owned by middle-sized sects. Now, these factions existed in a diminished fashion while this United Elemental Sect was quickly taking over everything. It was as if they were softly taking over all the areas but allowing the other older sects to prosper.

The one they visited wasn’t doing that badly. They could see modern-looking buildings similar to the ones they saw in the main sect being established. It looked like each large city would be given someone to govern it. From Sun Shi’s point, this was a good tactic to force the other sects to develop the city in the way that Zhang Dong wanted but would also irritate the other middle-sized sects that ruled these lands before.

However, with how much stronger the United Element Sect was than the others, they couldn’t really complain. They were not more like vassal states than independent factions as they were able to govern themselves only in certain ways. It seemed that the United Element Sect would jump in if a dispute occurred but the other factions could reason with each other before that happened. Only when the dispute was overblown and bloodshed was the only outcome did the other sect get involved.

This would indeed lower the death toll in each city as sects usually battled each other for resources or honor. The only downside would be that Zhang Dong’s sect would be put in a tough spot and depending on the person governing the city different outcomes would be probable. Sun Shi expected these governors to be bribed left and right and a possibly bad attribute to be given to Zhang Dong’s sect. Was this something the Patriarch was aware of and didn’t care or was there something else he was planning?

Nevertheless, after getting to the first city they made their way through the central southern region where it was safer. The golden knights that appeared out of nowhere were around that location and were able to push back the eastern invaders. Getting through this part took some days but after around a week they finally ventured into Heavenly Crane Sect territory. At one of their minor cities, they then activated the treasure given to them by the Golden Dragon.

That’s also when the main plan was revealed to them which they weren’t sure what to make of. Zhang Dong insisted that he wanted to moonlight as Sun Ling’s bodyguard. This was the name of the elder’s granddaughter that was a core formation expert. When he appeared out of the blue he was already wearing the correct robes, which were exactly the same as the other core formation guards that were taken on the journey.

“Don’t worry, just go about your things and I’ll just take a stroll through your lands, it’s better this way, what do you think would happen if people found out that the Emperor’s brother appeared in your lands?”

“Well… that would certainly complicate things…”

Sun Shi somewhat knew what this was about. Zhang Dong here seemed to not be willing to help them just yet, or at least that's how it looked. There could be a few reasons here, one of them was that he wanted to examine the situation before committing his forces. Then another reason could be that he was afraid of how his brother the Azure Emperor could view this.

It would at least look like he had made some kind of deal with the Heavenly Crane Sect which could push the Long Clan into believing that he was hostile. Perhaps this was the true reason and he needed to weigh his options first before a pact could be made. He could just want to examine if their sect was powerful enough to even be of use. This thought was quite maddening as the Heavenly Crane Sect stood at the apex of the Empire for many millennia but now it might not even be worth helping.

If times weren’t dire then Sun Shi would have never agreed to something as outlandish as this. Just the thought of some random person snooping around in his sect and lands was hard to stomach. It was however clear that this person was truly mighty and such power didn’t come without wisdom. He must have been planning something and had good reasons for it. Now if this would benefit his side was still up to debate but it was better than his entire sect to be eradicated. This in his mind was the trajectory they were heading toward and this man here was someone that could help them.

“Well then, let us head out young mistress~”
“I uh… you don’t have to…”

Sun Ling looked toward her grandfather in confusion but quickly nodded. She was not in the slightest able to deny Zhang Dong’s request. If someone as mighty as her grandfather was afraid of this man, then what was she as a tiny little core formation junior do? She and all the other sect members they came with passed out almost instantly at the sight of that aura and then awoke in a separate room after all the deliberating was over.

“Good, just try to act natural I’ll be shadowing you as a bodyguard should and don’t be afraid to give me some orders if someone gets suspicious.”

“Orders to the Golden Dragon? I would never…”

The young girl started sweating as she knew what it was about. If she behaved awkwardly around the mighty Emperor’s brother, then the trick would be easily discovered by everyone. If this happened her head and even her grandfather’s head could roll. She did not know much about this person but he had at least dispatched Wang Long, who had been a thorn in everyone's side for quite some time.

‘They really look uncomfortable, am I demanding too much from them?... Nah, they’ll be fine, even if I’m found out it will be fine.’

In Zhang Dong’s mind, it wasn’t a big deal, even if his acting was seen through it didn’t really matter. He just wanted to see how everything looked in the eastern lands. If his silly bodyguard disguise was seen through he could just assume the role of the Golden Dragon. For now, at least he would be able to avoid any large meetings with old elders and everyone kicking up a fuss about his appearance.

‘It was a lot easier when no one knew who I was, I didn’t need to hide my face either…’

He did not manage to enjoy a life of adventuring too much. Everything happened to fast and he quickly became the Clan leader within a matter of months of him appearing in this world. From that point on he was responsible for a lot of things and had to even get a special skill from the old system store to now get so stressed about it.

“Well then, I’ll let you take it from here, how about we visit your sect first, I’m interested in how they are conducting themselves in such times. After that, perhaps you can take me to a more volatile location where some of the battles are happening.”

“As you wish!”

While Sun Shi wasn’t that happy about the first part, the moment Zhang Dong mentioned that he would aid them on the battlefield a glint appeared in his eye. This was all that he was to these people, a way out of being conquered by their enemies. While Zhang Dong had the power he also needed to be wary of the Heavenly Crane Sect. Perhaps this elder was docile but others could see him as an enemy.

Thus while sticking to the back he followed after the group of cultivators. At that moment he knew that they were from a splinter group that was convinced that they would lose this war. Apparently, another delegation was sent to the Azure Emperor’s side but they never returned. The plaque that represented their elder’s life was supposedly still unbroken which meant that they weren’t killed at least.

“They probably never let them into the main city, I bet they are still somewhere at the border trying to get in. Maybe with enough bribes, they could make the elders budge? But probably not…”

These thoughts he didn’t voice as they didn’t bear any meaning on his situation here. What he needed to focus on was gaining information about his enemies and if it was possible to resolve everything without any more bloodshed. While it was true that he wanted to get the Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s Dao and take it as his own, if there was a possibility of damping this onslaught then he could wait.

His biggest enemy was the overseer and not these people. Absorbing Dao from the emperors was the fastest way to get to his destination but it wasn’t the only one. He had calculated that it would be feasible for him to ascend even without all the battles. It would only take a lot of time, perhaps even his entire lifespan.

‘Well then, let us get to it!’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 575

“Sun Ling, I’ll have to go report to the other elders, please stay out of trouble…”

Sun Shi’s eyes darted to the side for a fraction of a second to the person leaning up against a nearby building. He was dressed as one of the bodyguards that had come on the journey to the United Element Sect. At this moment he looked like he was in deep thought while looking around the premises. What he was thinking was unknown to anyone but this was a potential powder keg that could go off at any moment.

‘This is all for the future generations and the sect, I really hope that I’m doing the right thing…’

The old man thought to himself while having a hard time leaving this man with his granddaughter. There was no telling what this person would do when inside the sect. He could even decide to attack them when arriving inside, though the old man didn’t believe that even the Azure Dragon would be capable of taking out their entire sect by themselves.

Everyone was constricted by the nascent soul level to an extent. Wang Long was a cautionary tale now but his case was a bit different. He had been part of the Soaring Dragon Sect and had access to their protective formation. That demonic cultivator had a lot of time to prepare and strike at the right time. Zhang Dong here on the other hand came alone and would not have access to their formations and would be closely monitored by his people. If he did something suspicious he could just spring the alarm.

“I will, grandfather, don’t worry about me.”

The pretty girl didn’t move her head towards the man standing in the back but Sun Shi was sure that she understood the hidden order. The plan was to guide the man through all the best tourist attractions and places that wouldn’t be prone to incidents happening. With a heavy heart the old man finally departed and the young jade beauty finally turned towards the group of sect brothers and one guest.

“Let us depart then, I’m sure everyone is tired and hungry, how about we go to the Flowing Gazebo for a bit?”

“That’s a great idea young miss, don’t you all thinking?”

“Y-yes sect brother, we should depart with haste…”

The whole group was having a hard time hiding their awkwardness around the hidden expert. Everyone here was even more fearful than before as the only person even capable of protecting them was now gone. People would probably be informed about the Golden Dragon but that didn’t mean that didn’t help with the part that he could flatten them with his small toe.

“Ah yes, the young miss is truly mindful, if she thinks that we should visit this Flowing Gazebo then we should.”

Everyone listened to the man’s words to seek for any hidden meaning behind them. Was he annoyed by the fact that they were going to a restaurant or was he interested? There didn’t seem to be any animosity within the words or any prickling aura that was raining down on them. It seemed that they were safe for now but if perchance the food was not to his taste they might have to even slay the cook. Thus with a robotic way of walking, they departed with the man remaining at the back.

‘They are really stiff… I wouldn’t be surprised if one of them got a heart attack if I glared at them…’

Zhang Dong thought back to the short trip to this city. He was able to see the lands of the Heavenly Crane Sect. They were similar to the western regions but in a slightly better shape. Where he came from the Soaring Dragon Sect was the supreme faction and didn’t care much for the other groups. The only things they cared about were the tolls and taxes that they needed to pay them.

This place didn’t seem much different but they did look somewhat better. This was at least from the state of the buildings and land, when it concerned the people it was different. They were all talking about the ferocious cultivators that invaded their lands which made it hard to measure their liking for this Heavenly Crane Sect. They were certainly distraught and second-guessing their masters, some of them were even in the process of fleeing to the central parts of the Empire.

The sect city was quite the sight to behold. First of all, they needed to take a ship through a huge river. There the closer they got to the city the more cherry blossom petals could be spotted in the water. Koi fish were everywhere and they were munching on those red petals that contained a trace of spiritual energy. He could already see that this would be considered a costly elixir in the old lower regions.

This gate was wooden and only opened up after Sun Shi was identified. Large statues of some old masters were in place of the columns to the gates attached. On the inside, he was greeted by a large open space filled with various bird species, cranes included. They were swimming in the water but also just hanging out everywhere. Only after slowly traveling further did they arrive at a largely populated area filled with various buildings.

What was different about this place was the lack of tall structures. The buildings were densely packed together and didn’t really go past the third floor. This of course caused the city to be quite wide as it was populated by millions upon millions of people. Cherry trees with red petals were everywhere as well as different versions with white ones.

‘Was it the cherry blossom swordsmanship they called it?’

While going towards the restaurant he recalled what his retainers brought him about the sect. They were a swordsmanship sect and they were famous for the flashiness of their moves. Apparently with every swing of their sword they would produce cherry blossoms. These petals were anything but gentle though and they would shred through the bodies of their enemies.

‘I wonder if this sword style could help me with my own Dao or if it's just all for show, flashy moves can be confusing at first but after seeing through the illusion the flaws become apparent.’

Techniques that were eye-catching usually have the downside of being filled with useless movements. At first, they would confuse the enemy but after seeing it once and figuring out the trick they were easy to counter. This was not something that he was willing to invest his time into but it also didn’t mean that he didn’t want to see these people in action.

‘Probably better if I don’t challenge anyone to a duel though, better to just see how they fight on the eastern front.’

At the moment he didn’t want to spook his new potential allies. If he challenged their best swordmaster to a one-on-one fight out of the blue he would probably be denied. They could assume that he wished to lower their battle power by killing their grandmaster. Some might even think that it was some kind of tactic thought up by the Azure Emperor to weaken them even further.

‘Can’t give them stupid ideas, these guys always read into things too much and get the wrong idea.’

The trope of cultivators getting the wrong idea was quite prominent here. They could misconstrue him wiggling his eyebrow and think that he wanted someone dead. To not let this happen he needed to keep himself in check and implement his poker face. This place that they were taking him to required another boat ride through one of the smaller rivers that spread out through the city.

‘So this is it?... Looks like a giant gazebo…’

The restaurant in question was on a little island with a huge gazebo over it. The small boat that looked similar to a gondola could move through the water canals that connected to the center of the island where people could exit.

‘I guess the flowing part referred to all these waterways.’

It was quite a sight to see rich merchants and young cultivators being chauffeured around to this place. It was an open-air establishment with the gazebo roof meant to keep the rain out. At a glance, he also noticed that there were several formations everywhere. They were there to control the temperature and also bounce the wind away. Instead, a gentle warm breeze was hitting his cheek with the stray cherry blossom petal here and there.

‘I wonder if they didn’t block the wind if these would fly into people's mouths…’

For a moment he wanted to disable the formation to see the petals flying all over the place and into the bowls filled with noodles. On second thought however, with all these wealthy people around it would probably generate a lot of trouble for the business owner. Some young master types were here and he knew how they reacted to bad service.

‘The regular people were a bit alarmed but these guys don’t seem to be taking the threat seriously.’

The whole place was divided into booths and the ones in the center were the most exquisite. There he could see some flamboyant young masters with multiple women around them, drinking tea and playing the zither. Some were even in a poem battle where the girls cheered, it was quite an interesting sight to behold. They didn’t seem to be perturbed by the nature of the war but perhaps their parents were taking it more seriously.

‘I don’t see any older people here, some guards but no one that looks like a proper elder.’

“How about we get some spirit cherry sake, that will warm everyone up!”

“Great idea young miss!”

After arriving here everyone crowded around the young miss. He was just supposed to be a bodyguard so he remained standing while she should have to sit down. This of course ended up in an awkward display as the young woman wasn’t able to while an expert like Zhang Dong stared at her. It took her a few moments to realize that people were looking at her to finally give in and now they just waited for their order.

‘It does seem peaceful here and I haven’t even had the time to travel through this wide and open world.’

The world they were living in was truly tremendous. Ever since coming here he was locked to a section of it and unable to relax. He had traversed the lands on various occasions but it was always done in a rush. What he wanted to do instead was a slow journey together with his wife and kids that would allow them to take in the beautiful sights this place had to offer. However, this dream would have to wait as for the time being some trouble approached.

“Ah, if it isn’t Fairy Ling, what brings you to this place and why are you sitting so far from this young lord.”

The trouble came in the form of a smiling young man. Behind him stood various people, some were guards while others were part of the main sect.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 576

‘Why does it always end up like this…’

“You shitty moon lily bastards are always like this!”

“What are you talking about, it’s your smelly sun lily that is always looking for trouble!”

“We haven’t even started trouble but it seems that you bastards need to be reminded again of your place!”

Zhang Dong was taking in the sights while looking over the restaurant. He wasn’t even able to sample the eastern empire cuisine before people started arguing with each other. It all started with the usual appearance of a young master. From that point, it spiraled out of control and now the group he was with had started fighting.

It was funny how they forgot that he was with them and started mouthing off with the other group. The robes they wore were similar with one thing, in particular, being different. The ones the people he was with had a silver lily pattern close to the heart while the other had a golden one. This was supposedly some kind of distinction between the factions and perhaps it went further than that.

What happened was that the boisterous young master started making moves on Sun Ling. However her bodyguards didn’t take this lightly, some of them were quite young and probably fostered feelings for this beautiful young missus. She had the usual looks that these cultivator types liked to go for. Pale jade skin and jet black hair, coupled with quite the large rear and also front end made the young men do silly things.

Soon enough they were arguing with the young master's entourage which was composed of cultivators from the sect. As he understood it, they were lone warriors brought up by the sect and then taken in by each faction. Even though they had some personal power as core formation masters they were considered lesser without a proper nascent soul elder backing them. Only by aligning themselves to a side faction of a sect did they stand a chance of progressing in this dog-eat-dog world.

‘Well… not like it’s not fun to watch… but this is troublesome, I don’t think my side can actually win if a brawl breaks out…’

Zhang Dong was able to remain calm and assess the situation. Thanks to his spirit sense and also the system that presented him with everyone’s power level, he was sure that they would lose. Sun Ling was just an early-stage core formation cultivator and her guards were composed of late stage experts and a few in the great circle stage.

Some of the stronger combatants had left the group to carry out some orders given by Sun Shi which diminished their numbers. On the other hand, the group that he was looking at was purely composed of great circle core formation experts with the young master being in the middle stage of it.

‘But someone will surely come out and stop them before that happens, right?’

Thanks to being a nascent soul master he could feel the presence of a few grandmasters watching the show. However, even after some of the people from both sides started getting pushy nothing happened. Finally, he realized that whenever a strong faction is involved not even a nascent soul master dared to interfere. They would probably at most keep them from killing each other but this didn’t mean death wasn’t possible.

‘Even a nascent soul master has their limits and I wouldn’t expect them to care about the guards…’

This was a reality in this world, only a few people were considered special. In this case, it was the young lady named Sun Ling and the young lordling that was smirking her way. As long as each of them remained relatively safe the battle might not end. Even if one of the guards gets crippled or died it could continue past it.

‘Will I have to jump in?’

Now that people were getting handsy he was in a pickle. He was supposed to be part of Sun Ling’s group and some people on the other side started looking at him funny. At the moment he was using his disguising skill and looked like a man in his late forties. His face was the most average-looking one that he could come up with and he was mimicking the late core formation stage.

This of course painted him as an easy target for the other side. The older a person looked the more it gave away about their talent. For someone being close to the appearance of a fifty-year-old and being at this stage, it didn’t bode well. It indicated that he was close to reaching his limit and probably reaching the nascent soul level would have been hard. He just wanted to be more realistic with his appearance but it also painted a target on his face.

“Hey you there, you’ve been awfully quiet for this whole time, so a coward like you made it into the moon lily? No wonder no one takes you seriously!”

‘Oh boy, here we go…’

One of the people from the Sun Lily faction looked in his direction. Zhang Dong was trying to not get involved and remained in the back but for this reason, he was singled out. The other guards were feeling each other out but he just remained in place with his hands crossed over one another. It was as if he wasn’t willing to participate which was true but for different reasons.

“The Moon Lily faction allows such unloyal people to become retainers? Hey come over here, this lord will give you a piece of his mind!”

The man approached Zhang Dong which caused the people that he came here to freeze in place. Finally, they realized that they had begun doing such embarrassing things before a hidden expert. All of them had gone through this shouting match many times before so they didn’t make much of it. Now on the other hand one of the Sun Lily guards was walking towards him with a grin on his face.

“No, that person…, you must not…”

“Fairy Ling, I don’t think you should interest yourself with lowly cowards like that, if you join me and the Sun Lily faction I’ll be sure to replace such lowly retainers.”

Sun Ling's eyes almost popped out of her sockets as she turned to see one of the Sun Lily faction men walking towards Zhang Dong. From her perspective the hidden expert wouldn’t really distinguish between the two factions, they were both part of the Heavenly Crane Sect.

If they were rude to him then it could be all over, with one burst of his Qi all of the people that were gathered here could be eradicated from the spot. In her eyes, he was a ticking time bomb that could explode at any moment she was supposed to keep busy until her grandfather’s return.

“What are you too scared to reply? Are you even listening? What’s wrong with you bastard?”

Sun Ling began foaming at the mouth as she saw the random Sun Lily faction guard grab the collar of the hidden expert. The man then started shamelessly shouting profanities as if he was hired by the invaders to stir up trouble. To her dismay, the people she was with were all blocked from helping by the young master and his men.

“Look at me when I’m talking to y…..ughhhhhhhhh”

Suddenly a loud smack echoed through the entire restaurant. People were already looking at the entire commotion so it was easy for them to notice the man flying through the air. It was truly a bizarre sight to behold, they had never seen someone twirling through the air like a propeller blade. The man’s body made a nice arch as he flew for more than a hundred meters and dive bombed into one of the water canals. This caused the water to splash some of the new arrivals as well as some of the restaurant staff.

‘Shit, I made a scene…’

Zhang Dong remained poker-faced throughout the whole incident. At first, he intended to just wait and perhaps push the man away gently. If he mimicked the realm of a great circle core formation expert perhaps the man would have backed away. Before he could do this however the man’s ugly face was before him. He could work with the yanking of his robe but when he got a whiff of the guy’s breath he lost it.

Luckily he had enough restraint in him to not do any long-lasting damage to the man. The smack to the face would leave a red handprint but the man’s neck would still be on his head. If he actually performed a smack with his whole strength behind it then the guard’s head would have exploded instantly.

“Oh my, he went really far… he must have been injured or something, he shouldn’t have been shouting in my ear if he was this tired don’t you think?”

“T-that’s right…”

Sun Ling clearly didn’t know what to say but she along with the guards used this chance to move toward Zhang Dong’s location. That is that they tried but before they could huddle around him and protect others from another smack they heard a booming sound.

“How dare you hit my younger brother, who do you think that you are?”

A strong aura hit the whole place and out of nowhere another person appeared. He looked to be a bit older than the man that Zhang Dong smacked away but somewhat similar looking. By the words that he said he seemed to be the elder brother of this person and he had been sitting in the back watching the entire thing happen.

‘Somewhere around a half-step nascent soul master? Did he fail at ascending?’

Normally being at a half-step realm level wasn’t possible, this mostly was reached by having better-graded cultivation techniques and being a prodigy. The other way of attaining this power was by failing through the transition. They didn’t fully achieve a breakthrough but also didn’t fully fail, it was a realm between realms. The uniqueness of this state was that a person could not progress any further unless they found some kind of miracle medicine their cultivation journey was over.

‘Is it this trope? Did I really walk into something as cliche as this?’

His poker face was almost torn down as he wanted to reveal his true power level. If the scenario continued then after he smacked this person away another hidden expert would show himself. There were some nascent soul masters watching from afar so this was a possibility…

‘Is this some kind of law of this world… whenever I try to disguise myself things tend to go wrong…’

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh which was of course mistaken for an insult by the man there. It seemed that he needed to either continue taking out the small fries or stand his ground but perhaps there was also another way to diffuse this situation.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 577

“Who is that? Was there a person like that in the Moon Lily faction?”

“If there was, we would have heard about them, he doesn’t look that old… where was this genius hiding?”

“Could it be a hidden disciple of the Moon Lily Elder?”

People started whispering among each other after seeing an unknown man slapping away a half nascent soul master like it was nothing. They tussled for a moment but the person from the Sun Lily faction was promptly disposed of. It looked like a little tap but he was sent flying in the same direction the other guard was and joined him for a swim.

‘Shit, it became harder to control my strength after the recent advancements, I just wanted to push that guy away…’

Zhang Dong was wallowing in self-pity after showing off his might. His intent was to remain hidden away and watch people without them becoming guarded against him. If they knew that he was the Golden Dragon or some hidden master they would quickly change the way they treated him. Already at this moment the people from the Sun Lily side were backing away and lowering their heads. They all knew that this amount of power wasn’t normal and that only a nascent soul master would be able to contend with it.

“Hey Sun Ling, do something about this, we have to go… figure out an excuse and lets go!”

He sent a hidden message to the granddaughter that was supposed to lead him through the city. The young lady was just standing there with her mouth open and was quick to jump back after hearing his voice. It was a bit funny to see the girl panicking and not knowing what to do but finally she raised her voice.

“I just remembered something, we were supposed to meet up with my friend at the Tea Palace, we should depart promptly…”

“T-that’s right, it’s my fault for not reminding the young miss about it!”

“It’s fine, that happens, we should go…”

The guards that were with them got the intent rather quickly and everyone started to back away. Zhang Dong was quick to turn around and follow after the departing group he was with. Luckily the people from the Sun Lily faction were smart enough to not call out to them. They did lose a bit of face but they clearly didn’t want to lose even more.

…

“Please appease your anger senior, if it’s enough you can have this Sun Ling’s head…”

“What the hell are you talking about? Just stand there for a moment… here this should be enough…”

The group had retreated to a more secluded area of the city and into an empty alleyway. The guards along with the young miss were quite fidgety. It looked like they would be receiving a thrashing from Zhang Dong for failing their mission. Instead however he just used his disguising technique to change his appearance yet again.

His previous persona’s deed was already spreading through the entire sect and thus to remain unnoticed he needed a new face. They might look for the hidden master among the Moon Lily faction but they would not find him.

“This should do but remember, if they ask about that little incident just say that I left or something.”

“O-of course, Senior.”

“Stop calling me senior, now wasn’t there a tea house that we were supposed to visit?”

Sun Ling covered her mouth as it was ingrained into every fiber of her being to properly refer to seniors. Zhang Dong went against the norm, no one here understood what he was actually doing as any other elder would have just demanded a tour through the city from someone at their level. It was actually deplorable to have core formation juniors lead a nascent soul grandmaster like him through the city.

Unfortunately for them, it seemed that they were under the boot of an eccentric and would need to adhere to the plan he prepared. Thus they departed towards the next destination, the place was a famous tea house where various experts liked to relax and discuss the Dao.

‘Is this supposed to be a tea house? Looks more like an area for a picnic.”

They passed through a gate that had the writing ‘Tea Palace’ on it. However, instead of a large castle-like structure, they ended up at something that looked more like a park. It was an open field covered in high-quality spirit grass. Trees were spaced out at equal intervals which led him to believe that they were planted this way on purpose. Up in the air he coils see ladies in flowy robes swishing on swords, in their hands they had trays filled with tea.

“Let us relax under the cherry tree.”

Sun Ling called out without looking behind her where Zhang Dong was standing. All of the people around him were quite stiff but they needed to remember to act the part. He was still only a lowly guard so Sun Ling couldn’t interact with him normally. His job was just to stand there and answer her orders. Thus for the time being he leaned up against the large cherry tree and started looking around.

‘It does look peaceful here, maybe I should make one of these in my city… but it doesn’t look like kids are allowed, they would certainly make this place a lot louder.’

What he saw was mostly elderly people sipping on tea and meditating. It was a peaceful place with a nice atmosphere and everyone was talking in a hushed tone. That is almost everyone, there was a certain group of people that was just sitting there and practically shouting.

‘Are they putting alcohol into the tea or something?’

Most people didn’t have the keen eye that Zhang Dong did but he certainly saw one of the people adding something to the teacup. Afterward, he served over to one of the women from their group that instantly became flushed in the face. It was another group of young cultivators.

‘It’s not the Sun Lily Faction this time around… it looks very similar but the lily is green?’

When looking at the others gathered here these people were taking up a lot more space. Everyone else had made way and cleared out. It was possible that these people were trouble or at least their leader looked like another young master type. This one had a more gentle look and demeanor. His gentle smile was deceiving as Zhang Dong could see his eyes darting towards the spiked drink.

‘He might have been the one that ordered the other person to spike the drink… the girl that is with him is probably a target, there are more with them too…’

Now, this was another predicament, there were about ten men within that group and three girls that looked to be in their twenties. On the outside, it looked like they were having fun and were laughing but he was willing to believe that they didn’t consent to the thing getting put into their drink. While he wasn’t that close to the scene of the crime he could somewhat discern with this spirit sense what they were working with.

‘Looks like it’s an aphrodisiac mixed with some other recreational drugs…’

His brain was already filled with all possible herb combinations that there were in this world. Just by the faint smell and spirit qi fluctuations, he was somewhat able to tell what would be the result of drinking the tea. The woman was already showing early signs, she was becoming less guarded and laughing. Probably after twenty minutes or so she would be ready for whatever they were planning here.

‘So this is the young generation of the Heavenly Crane Sect?’

First was the young master that was trying to pick a fight with them after seeing their Moon Lily insignia. Now it was another one attempting to drug an unsuspecting junior. It was clear that the leader of the group was interested in the lady but probably didn’t have the patience to pursue her in a regular fashion. It was quite strange to see, the man clearly had it all, looks, status, and a nice smile. Still with all of that he decided to hasten the process through underhanded means and probably had already walked over others to get to this spot.

‘Another psychopath that thinks that they are above others…’

“Sun Ling, who is that person?”

“That person?”

Zhang Dong motioned with his nose toward the group that was sitting in the middle of this tea park. They were quite easy to spot as they were sitting at exactly the center stage of this place that was up on a little hill.

“That’s… the Sage Lily Faction and that person is the grandson of their leader, Elder Jia Yong, his name is Jia Yang, is there a problem senior?”

‘There is something, do you know any of those girls that are with them?’

“Not in particular, they seem to be part of their faction.”

It would have been easy for him to just go over there and yank the girl away but then he would be giving himself away as always. Sun Ling was the better option but if it was possible for her to intervene was up for debate.

‘The young lordling there seemed to have mixed something into the tea, would it be possible for you to do something about it without rousing suspicion?”

“Senior Jia Yang did?”

“So he is a senior to you? That complicates things.”

This was troubling, if Sun Ling was lower on the totem pole than this young man then it would be hard for her to do anything about the situation. Even if she had his word it would be unbecoming of her to just go there and accuse Jia Yang of drugging the junior. The people around them would probably sweep it under the rug and no one would say a thing due to the difference in status.

‘Think I might have become a little disconnected with how things worked around this world.’

With how Zhang Dong was at the apex of his sect he forgot how the people below him usually operated. Status and power were still supreme and even when he informed Sun Ling about a potential rape scenario she couldn’t just act. Normally he would expect everyone to make a scene but instead, they buried their heads as if this was not something worth getting involved in.

‘Even if they help the girl, the young master will probably inform the elder backing him about this disgrace… they could lose a lot of status or even their lives depending on the mood of that elder.’

He pondered, there were many ways of taking care of this situation but what would be the best? Just giving the young man a slap on the wrist for something as dastardly as this just felt wrong but time was of the essence as the group was probably going to leave soon...

Chapter 578

“They are on the move, lets go and try not to make it too obvious.”

“As you wish, Senior…but what are you going to do, you’re not planning to …”

Sun Ling replied in a meek voice as her group was forced to follow after the Sage Lily faction and their greatest young master. The young lordling had put something into the tea of her sect sister and was now leading her outside of the Tea Palace.

Zhang Dong had seen through this quick movement and contemplated how to handle the situation. To avoid another predicament as at the restaurant under the gazebo he decided to not intervene yet. Instead of taking out Jia Yang here where everyone could see them, it would be better to do it at a location with fewer people.

“Don’t worry I’m not going to kill him, I’m not crazy. I’ll just put him to sleep for a day or two, nothing too serious but…”

He wasn’t really sure what to do about this case. The man seemed to be a sexual deviant that was fine with abusing his position and even using drugs to hasten the process. This was strange indeed, Jia Yang had to be the impatient one as from Zhang Dong’s perspective there shouldn’t be a reason that he wouldn’t be able to get a woman for himself.

Perhaps there was more to the situation, the world had a concept of marriage but between cultivators, they were referred to as Daoist Partners. It was only socially acceptable to have one such partner and stay loyal to them throughout their life. Usually, a cultivator would never get another one even after death but then there were people like Huo Qiang and his grandfather that were able to take in multiple wives.

It all depended on their way of living but from what he knew about the Heavenly Crane Sect, they were the type to go for one long-lasting partner. This could be the reason why he was going with the drugging route. Perhaps after the deed was over the lady in question wouldn’t even remember that it happened. This would give Jia Yang an incentive to act this way, instead of committing to one partner that he would need to present to the whole sect he could hide his deviancy.

‘Can’t he just go to the red light district or something? There should be enough professionals there that would be willing to hide things like these…’

He didn’t understand why the person was acting this way. Prostitution was legal in this world and with the amount of wealth this sect had Jia Yang should have been able to hire the best ladies. It was perhaps some kind of power move to perform the act with a fellow cultivator that was at a similar level. Women that trained in the arts did usually look better than the common folk but the reason didn’t matter and the man’s acts needed to stop.

“Move closer to me and you won’t be discovered, just try not to bump into people.”

His body vanished from the spot which caught the small group of Moon Lily’s off guard. After a moment he was back but for some reason, Sun Ling and the others felt like their bodies weren’t there. It was a special technique to hide one's presence. When done by an expert like Zhang Dong even a nascent soul master at the late stage wouldn’t be able to tell that someone was there unless they got really close.

Thus they followed after the small group of young cultivators that weren’t actually that young, to begin with. All of them looked to be in their early twenties but even Jia Yang was already over fifty. The faster one became a core formation expert the more the aging process was halted. How young a person looked was also an indication of how good of a future prospect they were.

Someone that was half a century and looked like this had a bright future ahead of them. However getting over towards the nascent soul level wasn’t that easy, anyone making their way there and not looking like a sixty-year-old grandpa was a genius. Zhang Dong was considered one and his brother the Azure Dragon was another one.

The latter was many times older but the two didn’t look that much different and no one could really pinpoint their real ages. Most people wouldn’t believe that the famous Golden Dragon was even younger than Jia Yang here. If this was common knowledge then he would probably be considered the most promising prospect in the world.

“Sun Ling, what is this place?”

“It’s an area used by core disciples and it’s run by disciples as well.”

“I see, it makes sense.”

After following the group of miscreants they arrived at another part of the city. It looked like a large town in itself and was characterized by the people that lived there. The ages did vary but there didn’t seem to be that many old people with gray hair here. Most of the elderly were store owners and merchants while the vast majority of the population were the disciples.

It made sense that Jia Yang would take his victim to a place where he had a lot of pull in. Even the elders that resided here were probably mostly only affiliated with powerful families. They would not be able to do much against a large faction leader's grandson even if they wanted to.

‘That’s quite the grand cultivation abode this little shit has…’

They continued to a large villa with everything that a cultivator could want included. It had a backyard training area, and a garden filled with spirit herbs and fruits. There was even a separate cultivation cave protected by a powerful protective array that would block out any sounds. The young man was certainly living a life of leisure with everything being handled to him on a silver platter.

‘Could my kids end up like this if I spoil them too much?’

As a parent of a five-year-old boy that was the son of the most powerful cultivator in the sect, it was troubling. He could very well see Zhang Jun becoming a spoiled brat if he wasn’t careful. When he became a teenager his hormones would shoot through the roof but it would be up to him as a father to reel him in. It wouldn’t be acceptable if he became a young master with no morals like this.

“You guys wait here, I’ll be right back.”

“S-senior if I may…”

“Go ahead.”

“Thank you, w-what do you intend to do with Jia Yang… if the elder finds out…”

“You don’t need to worry about that, we won’t die but…”

“But…”

“Well… let’s say that he won’t be able to use his little brother for a while…”

“Oh…”

With that response, Zhang Dong vanished while leaving the group he came with outside the premises of Jia Yang home. The looks on their faces were truly interesting, it was as if they were constipated throughout the entire trip. It wouldn’t be strange if they didn’t try to contact Sun Shi to get back here before something disastrous happened. They were probably thinking that he would actually kill the young man but he had other plans.

…

“Here, why don’t you just relax here… but I don’t think you can hear me anymore, this miracle drug was really worth the price.”

Jia Yang had a massive grin on his face that was uncharacteristic of his stoic demeanor. He had managed to fool many people by playing the perfect senior. Even the elders above him had no idea of what he was doing here but even if they found out he didn’t believe that anything would come of it. His position as a future elder was already cemented and the way had been paved by his grandfather. Sooner this woman would be accused of lying than he would

“You better be thankful, this young lord spent a lot to make this happen.”

The young master licked his lips while staring at the mostly passed-out woman. He had thrown her onto his bed and it was ready to start the fun. Her whole face was red and her body was sweaty from the drug's side effects. She was a core formation expert and not easy to get into such a state. She would be out for half a day which gave him ample time to play around.

“Hehe, don’t run away now, I’ll be right back.”

He laughed while strutting out of the bedchamber to check once more if everything was in order. Even though the deed was done the man didn’t want to get caught in the act or have anyone interrupting them. Thus only after making sure that everything was in order did he return to the room.

There she was, his long-desired prize and something he was looking towards for all these months. He had worked tirelessly to get the woman’s defenses down and finally was able to deliver the drug into the tea. No one would suspect someone of a pristine image like him to be able to do something like this and he used this fact to his advantage.

“How did she manage to get the bedsheets onto herself?”

To his surprise when he returned the woman was curled up under some satin clothes and probably also hugging some pillows as her stature was a bit larger than he remembered. With a smirk on his face, he grabbed those fabrics to yank them down.

“This lord desires to see his bride! … Huh?”

“Is there a problem, lover boy?”

“W…who are you, how d-dare you!’

Jia Yang's eyes bulged out of the eye sockets as after yanking the bedsheets away there was another person waiting for him. They looked truly hideous, warts were all over their body and their face was truly horrendous. This wasn’t the worst part as clearly this person was a man and his stature was quite hefty.

“What, I’m not to the young lord’s fancy? Well, this doesn’t matter, come here, dear!”

“Wait what?”

The young master tried resisting but he quickly realized that his cultivation was sealed. All of his limbs felt like they were made of noodles as he couldn’t muster any strength to resist the man before him. This was clearly not something that he wanted, the man's stinky breath hit his face but he couldn’t resist. Soon he realized what was happening but it was too late, the act that he was trying to perform on the passed-out lady was about to happen to him instead.

“Nnnnnnoooooooooooooooo….”

…

“Hm… I guess reading those ugly bastard books paid off in the end… He won’t be able to function as a normal man for a while after this…”

Zhang Dong was looking at Jia Yang who passed out on the ground. His mouth was filled with foam and he was in the process of having the worst life-like dream ever. It was all an illusion that had been infused into his brain by Zhang Dong’s technique. He would go through quite a mind-shattering experience and would not even know that it was all a dream. The passed-out girl that was brought here was unharmed and untouched, her dream was probably much better than what Jia Yang was experiencing now.

“Time to go, I’ve already made them wait long enough.”

Soon Zhang Dong departed the premises with the girl, she would be handed over to Sun Ling and gotten some help. Jia Yang on the other hand would never be the same man he once was…

Chapter 579

‘That was somewhat refreshing for some reason…’

Zhang Dong thought back to the young master he had disabled and sneaked away. Just giving him a nightmare wasn’t enough though. Inserting cultivation demons into a person of a lower realm was possible. This illusion that he fed to Jia Yang would fester and eat away at the man’s mental state.

It was a little thing he learned from the demonic faction, he would never be able to achieve the nascent soul level like this and regress. In a world ruled by power and prestige, he would be quickly overtaken by others that desired his possession and his grandfather wouldn’t be able to do anything about it.

‘Still leave a bit of a bad aftertaste in my mouth, he should be thrown to jail but this should be the closest thing here.’

In reality, Zhang Dong would have rather dealt with something like this according to his old-world morals. Here on the other hand he couldn’t if he wanted to maintain good relations with the Heavenly Crane Sect. If he crippled him in an open fashion then the faction this cultivator was a part of would hold malice against him. In a time when both sides were needed to take care of a threat, this was not an option.

‘Never thought I would be making deals like this, I guess that’s war for you, never know what you might have to do to survive…’

For the time being, he could only bury this case in the back of his mind. Perhaps when all of this was over he could go after all the war criminals he encountered. Winning the exchange between empires was for now more important than the dealings of juniors. As someone at the top, his time would be better spent creating a system to not allow things like this to happen anymore. Handling everything on a case-by-case basis by himself was not feasible, he needed to create a task force and get many other people involved instead.

“Sun Ling, do you know where this person lives we need to drop her of in a safe location.”

“Yes, Senior, it's not that far from here.”

“Well then, I’ll be right behind you, and don’t worry, no one will be able to see you.”

Sun Ling clasped her hands while guiding Zhang Dong toward this woman’s own crafting abode. He kept them hidden away from any nosy Sage Lily faction members to not implicate them. After Jia Yang awoke, he would probably search for the woman that escaped, if Sun Ling was seen dropping her over at her house then it would be obvious that she was a part of the attack on the young master.

Not much happened on the way to the lady's home that she shared with a few other junior sisters. She was in a lesser zone than to which the young master belonged. This made her a perfect target as she didn’t have any proper backing than her own master that was of course below in status than Jia Yang’s grandfather.

While perhaps this visit wasn’t that productive it was eye-opening. Ever since he established his own sect he didn’t really look into that many things. He relied on the system to point out a person’s alignment to him. While no evil people were taken in there were some that were morally gray.

‘What is even good anymore, a lot of things can be skewed to fit anyone's worldview and justify even murder…’

Perhaps things weren’t as bad at his own sect but he couldn’t discount that young masters like this one could be appearing. The new generation of cultivators might have been analyzed by the system but he didn’t do the same with the older members. They were the overbearing grandfathers at the top that would strike fear into everyone.

He could also not account for new people being born with an evil alignment or it switching through their life for one reason or another. There were many things that affected this base state and it could even be switched instantly after a traumatic experience.

‘But now is not the time for this, let's continue this…’

The trip through the city continued with him getting more and more disappointed with each new reveal. He stopped interfering with the people as nothing as bad happened but the small things kept piling up. This place had a clear divide between casts and it existed everywhere. The ones born to the wrong parents had to bow their heads and it was almost impossible to change their fate.

When listening to the rumors of what was happening at the eastern fronts he realized that most of the people fighting there were expendable. All the powerful sect masters were from the various Lily factions and didn’t need to do anything. Even the nascent soul masters there were just groomed for such an occasion.

‘So that’s why a large chunk of them just want to wait here. At least it was smart for them to create backup experts for such an occasion, all the main families will be fine but the branching ones will mostly fall after this war. I bet they think that they can just rebuild as long as the tree survives, not much different than what the Azure Emperor is doing…’

After some time had passed Zhang Dong and his entourage were sitting outside another tea house. All the second-hand information that he wanted to gather was there and now he needed to make a decision. While the strongest cultivators with the best techniques were sitting on their hands, their vassal clans were dying out on the field. Probably until all of them were spent they wouldn’t act.

‘They might not even act at all, this protective formation is bad, even the demi-human emperor wouldn’t be able to easily get in here…’

He only fought against one of the emperor-level threats so he didn’t have all the data. The one that ruled over the oceans didn’t show herself yet but her troops were around the same level as the demi-humans. When taking that into consideration this place seemed like it could last out for a while before being conquered. It depended on how much spirit energy and masters they had to infuse their defenses in.

‘This place is mostly self-sufficient but sooner or later they would run out of resources.’

From his calculations and current information, he believed that they would last at least ten years, perhaps more if they had some hidden resources. This also depended on how hard the opposition wanted to go. Usually what happened was a slow siege and battle of attrition, cultivator types lived for long, thus they didn’t risk rushing into things. Perhaps if the Emperor moved by himself they wouldn’t even last a few months.

“Junior greets senior.”

‘I guess I’ll have to make a decision soon, time for the next part.’

Finally, after a few hours in the city, Sun Shi arrived once more. Together with him were various other old men that were wearing the Moon Lily faction emblems on their robes. These were far more intricate than the one's Zhang Dong and the guards were wearing.

The Lily Factions were the ones in power and they split off into quite a lot. The Sun, Moon, and Sage were only three out of ten camps. Each one had a head elder leading them to have ten feuding factions only looking out for themselves. There were exactly ten of them which made it problematic whenever any decisions needed to be made.

Each Lily could cast a vote and most of the time it was five against five with nothing being decided. There was one above them, his name was Tao Guan and he was the current sect leader. Even though he was at the top spot he couldn’t discount any of the other factions and from what he heard was also unwilling to veto a vote when it was five against five.

“Are you the Moon Lily Grand Elder?”

“That is true, Golden Dragon, I am called Sun Shen.”

He already knew that they were somehow related but Sun Shi and Sun Ling were part of the Moon Lily Clan. This whole thing was very similar to the situation back at his own sect, there they had three main factions with the Zhang, Huo, and Feng Clans that were part of the founding clans. The biggest difference was that Zhang Dong as the Patriarch carried a lot more weight there and his orders could not be denied by any of the factions.

Here, on the other hand, their leader needed to consult everyone before making any kind of decision. If he tried imposing a rule that a lot of people were against, something like an internal war could break out. It wasn’t anything new, many times did clans or sects produce people that craved to be the leader.

It was the same here, he was sure that some people in the background were already trying to come out on top of this war. Sending their competition to the front lines would be the most sensible move but could also backfire if the people sent there actually came out victorious and ended up increasing their fame.

“Your granddaughter had explained a few things to me but she couldn’t delve too much into it, so can you answer this, what do you wish me to do?”

“Of course but this isn’t the place to discuss such issues, why don’t you join me in my private abode? The other elders would be honored to meet the honorable Golden Dragon, the hero of the western front.”

“Ah, I see that I have gained some interesting titles but sure, let us depart but first let me change into something more fitting.”

After a few pleasantries he discarded his guard persona, there was no use hiding it anymore as the Moon Lily Grand Elder was there. The man looked like a gentle person and gave off pleasant vibes but he also drew in all the eyes. The smaller tea house they were sitting outside of was filled with lesser sect members. All of them lowered their heads and dared not to look at this group.

It was quite a strenuous task as strange radiant energy took over the whole place. Some of them backed off and even raised their heads to see Zhang Dong shedding his disguise. Where previously an average-looking guard was now stood a rather handsome man with long white hair. People could feel instantly that it was a powerful master and quickly bowed before him in a show of respect.

Chapter 580

‘So, this is the Moon Lily faction… I didn’t expect to be actually covered in moon lilies though…’

Zhang Dong was done with going through the main city that belonged to the Heavenly Crane Sect. After being picked up by Sun Shi who was the initial elder that started this whole journey, he met up with Sun Shen. This person was at the level of great circle of nascent soul that was above the norm. When comparing him against the tribe chiefs from the demi-humans he didn’t fall that much behind.

A theoretical battle would go in the demi-human’s favor even more if he faced someone like the vampire lord that could regenerate himself at a fast pace. However, with some help from other nascent soul masters, he could see this man being victorious. Without seeing what kind of techniques he was capable off it was hard to make a complete assessment. This at least meant that this sect had enough force to not get steamrolled by these invaders, that is if they actually committed to some type of strategy.

The more they waited the more ground the other camps took and their influence grew smaller. Zhang Dong was still convinced that if the Azure Emperor along with this Sect actually acted then the Emerald Phoenix Empire wouldn’t have been able to progress this far. He was able to hold off the demi-human offensive so it should have been possible for people that weren’t that far off from his level. The only problem as always was cooperation, cultivators didn’t like to work with one another and only acted if the reward justified it.

Perhaps if both sides were offered some kind of treasure or long-lost cultivation technique then they would consider making a move. The old men at the top wouldn’t be easily convinced as they had mostly emptied all the resources that would allow them to progress. Only legendary objects would move their hearts and trust was nonexistent. It wouldn’t be strange if after taking care of the Emerald Phoenix Emperor one of the sides attempted to overthrow the other if they were weakened enough.

This everlasting fear of being betrayed was the biggest reason that all sects preferred not getting involved in any kind of outside battles. There was always something that they could lose or it could have been trickery involved of some kind. This was also one of the reasons so many misunderstandings happened as they always expected some kind of ruse.

‘They do have a nice fragrance and spiritual energy, I could probably make some good pills from them… I wonder if the other factions have more of the same.’

While thinking about his options here Zhang Dong slowly walked through the garden filled with spiritual lily flowers. This land was truly beautiful and he regretted that he wasn’t able to look at these lilies during the night when the moon was at its zenith. From the whispers that he heard around and interaction with the Sun Lily faction, he knew that both of them were at each other's throats.

These Moon Lilies were something one had to cultivate at night while the Sun Lilies were the exact reverse. They were like Yin and Yang and also carried the same energies with them. In this case, the Sun side was pushing towards the element of fire while the Moon to the ice element. The women on this side were exceptionally pale and filled with that icy demeanor that was so sought after by the cultivators in this world. So were the men though while the Sun side was more exterior with their emotions. It was as if a group of introverts and extroverts were going after each other.

“Elder Sun Shen, I think this is enough, could you tell me your intention?”

After arriving at the main sect area and this sub-zone that was the Moon Lily faction. Some sects had mountain peaks that divided their groups while others had massive buildings or even separate cities. This one on the other hand had whole valleys surrounded by medium-sized mountains from each side. Ten such valleys existed here and he was invited to one of them where he could have a conversation with their leader.

Of course, as per cultivator standards, he was taken on a tour through all the various vistas. They were clearly trying to show him the superiority of their faction by presenting various high-quality resources and manufacturing processes. He was even shown some of the pills that this sect was famous for but it was not something that he was interested in or envious of. Anything that was in this Empire was already at his fingertips. With enough time he would have probably been able to create a massive army that would have easily defeated both three great sects even if they were at full power and existed again.

It was obvious that they wanted to entice him with something to have a bargaining chip. As it stood now they didn’t know what they could offer to the Golden Dragon for his services. It wasn’t possible for anyone to not want any kind of reward. Zhang Dong on the other hand didn’t really need anything besides the basic resources like spirit stones and herbs. With the base materials, he could use his crafting abode to produce pills and weapons at a factory scale.

There was not really much they could offer to him and if it was any other time then a deal would not have been made. However, what he needed was to siphon the Daos of the two Emperors for himself and gain more power to go against the Overseer. If he could use the Heavenly Crane Sect to get him into a one-on-one confrontation with the Emerald Phoenix Emperor then it would actually be enough.

If he could get them to act as a vanguard and just allow him to add the finishing touches, then it would be enough. The only problem was the mistrusting nature of cultivators. If he didn’t ask for anything then they would assume that there was something else he was after. Something that either was worth risking his life for or he was intending to betray them when they needed him the most.

There were many records of faction leaders not keeping promises and pulling their troops out of battle to allow their allies to be eradicated. Then invading their weakened lands and taking over. Sometimes the third party would just wait for two foes to go into battle and after both of them were at the end of their wits, they entered the playing field to flip the board.

“I’m sure the honorable Golden Dragon knows what we wish of him.”

“That is true, you want me to help you with your little problem in the east but what can you offer me in return?”
After going through the various smithies, libraries, and alchemist workshops he ended up in a secluded room with Sun Shen the leader of the Moon Lily faction. It seemed that the man was convinced that the problem was greater than the other thought. He was even willing to bring in an outsider that could potentially put them in bad grace with the current Emperor.

“We will swear an oath of comradeship to the United Element Sect that will not be broken for millennia.”

“Hoh, you wish to be our long-lived friends but such an oath won’t mean much after both of us are gone, you’ll have to give me something more tangible.”

“Does the Golden Dragon have something in mind?”

“I actually do, I’ve seen the resourcefulness of your sect and you do have something that I want.”

A bond of friendship between two sects would only last as long as their Patriarch’s stayed in power. Sun Shen here could only go through with something like that if their leader agreed to it so it wasn’t a done deal. Normally it would have been a great deal to any other sect or clan. If they gained recognition as an allied sect to the Heavenly Crane Sect then no one could come seeking trouble with them.

People coming from the Heavenly Crane Sect would be compelled to help anyone from the United Element Sect if there was any trouble. Zhang Dong’s sect didn’t really need any help in this regard as they had already proven themselves to be strong. What he needed was resources that he could use to enhance his own army.

“Oh, if it’s within my power then I’m sure we could come to an agreement.”

“As you know we are in dire times and as such resources are scarce. I wish you to supply me with the highest quality spirit metals that the eastern region is known for, of course without any taxation…”

“You wish to use our ore mines?”

“Yes.”

Zhang Dong nodded as the resources on his side were starting to be drained. What he needed was more materials to produce large flying ships like the Argonaut and other minerals. This was the best way of improving his forces without spending too many spirit points on rising people's cultivation. There was just not enough spirit steel to go around for manufacturing such large flying vessels and the eastern region was known for having abundant mines.

“My faction has access to a repository of ancient metals and some mines but…”

“Is there a problem?”

“... I won’t lie, but the mines belong to another faction that we aren’t at great terms with.”

“Let me guess, is it the Sun Lily faction?”

“I see the Golden Dragon is wise.”

The old man nodded as he misunderstood Zhang Dong’s shot in the dark for wisdom. Instead, to him, it only made sense that what he wanted was lying behind someone that he was up against. It was as if the world was conspiring against him to make things harder. This could have actually been very true in this case if the Overseer was keeping track of his movements.

“Do you perhaps have a way to move the Sun Lily faction to prepare the items that I want?”

“That is…possible, I would have to discuss it at the faction leader gathering.”

“Can you take care of that? I don’t think you or me have time to waste on too much bureaucracy.”

He wished to just head out into the field and drive the invaders back. Nevertheless, he had asked for payment and unless he wanted to be looked down on he needed to stick through it. There was always a way to change the minds of others and he was very convincing when it came to knocking some sense into people.

“This might actually be possible, we are holding a meeting tomorrow… but do you wish to join me for it?”

“Yes, would that be a problem?”

Zhang Dong asked while giving the old man the gentlest smile he could muster. The only way to move things along would be to kick up a fuss where the most prominent sect elders were taking part in.

Chapter 581

‘I’ve come all the way here but I’m not sure if what these people are planning will work, or at least not if I don’t give them a nudge in the right way.’

After having a conversation with Sun Shen, the Moon Lily faction leader, he had a general idea of what was happening. In short, the Sun Lily faction along with three others wanted to wait it out while the Moon Lily wanted to ask for help from outside. For now, it was four against four with two factions withholding their vote.

‘I guess his plan is to present me to the other factions that are withholding their vote, it could work in theory but this leaves a lot up to me. Not like everyone has bought into the whole Golden Dragon persona, some still think that my sect had just been lucky or that we had help from the Azure Emperor.’

His side actually needed to get both of those factions that didn’t vote on their side or at least keep one from voting. If both continued to withhold the vote or if they each gave theirs to another side then nothing would be done. From what Sun Shen had told him the only person that could push a decision with equal votes was the Patriarch.

‘Apparently, this guy's position isn’t cemented so he usually doesn't favor any side out of fear of a backlash.’

Usually, the most prominent elder from one of the ten factions would be chosen as their leader. There was a strong right and left side leaning with these factions with only two being mostly neutral. This time around the Patriarch was chosen from one of these more neutral factions that had a more shaky footing. They were down on the totem pole and knew that sooner or later the leader would be replaced by a new one.

‘It’s a bit strange to be in a sect with a somewhat democratic approach to everything but even in this case, the one with the stronger first is right. Even the leader that is supposed to be the strongest can’t go against the mob. If he starts provoking those cultivator nuts with decisions that go against them, something drastic could happen.’

Zhang Dong believed that factions like the Sun Lily could do something to reel their leader in. They would probably not go against him directly as that would put their whole power structure at risk. Instead, they would probably go after the faction the man came from or for people that he was close with. They could do this by making their lives harder or outright assassinations at night.

Even if the Patriarch knew who did it they wouldn’t be able to move without proper evidence. Otherwise, the whole sect could collapse into a civil war, it was a balancing act between everyone to keep them from going ballistic. No one's bottom line could be affected out of fear of everything collapsing.

‘This might have been what became of my sect if I didn’t come back. It’s disheartening but sometimes a leader that can overpower the opposition is needed.’

His might couldn’t be challenged and everyone inside of his sect knew this. No one had been stupid enough to attempt a coup yet, the only ones that were from the Huo Clan were close but abandoned their desires after he arrived. This was thanks to Huo Qiang who didn’t pose a threat to Zhang Dong in the first place. He didn’t have any wish to become Patriarch and didn’t push for a switch in power. It was his father that was luckily below his son in strength that attempted this and thus was never successful.

‘They really like their tranquil places don’t they?’

The trip to the discussion was quite interesting. First of all he was given a large crane to sit on, it was quite majestic and an interesting way to travel considering he had already been used to flying or doing it on a sword. The ten valleys where the factions had their headquarters all pointed to a center plane, there he could now see a large palace surrounded by a marsh.

In this marsh, he could see many various birds walking around. There were cranes but also pink flamingos strutting around and hunting for some food. When he squinted he could feel that the water they were walking in was filled to the brim with spiritual energy and it was the same for the fish and frogs living in it. These various colorful birds radiated a queer power, they weren’t strong but packed with extraordinary qi.

‘Do they eat those birds or perhaps use their eggs for something in particular?’

He wasn’t sure but it wasn’t strange to use things like eggs to make pills or special dishes. Cooking was one of the great professions as well. A chef could produce something that was on the level of alchemical pills with the only drawback being that food spoiled a lot faster than pills did.

‘The pastry that they offered with the tea was quite rich in spiritual energy, it would have probably helped a lesser cultivator to jump a large realm or a few smaller ones…’

There were a few things that this sect exported, perhaps the baked goods were something they kept within the ten great factions. Nevertheless, he didn’t come here to make any deals for cookies or cakes. What was on the line was the early end of this war and him potentially getting the Dao of the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. While he didn’t actually think that would be happening any time soon if he could gain the trust of these people that option could open up in the near future.

‘It would be nice to end this war faster but confronting the last boss without my troops could be suicide.’

Zhang Dong had gotten a lot stronger than before but he couldn’t just one-shot an emperor-level threat. While he thought that at this point in time he could beat them in a fair one-on-one confrontation this didn’t mean that he would get one. This opponent was very similar to the cultivators that lived here and these experts were very guarded.

First, they would throw their underlings to test out the waters before engaging. If the Emerald Phoenix Emperor concluded that Zhang Dong was someone that he couldn’t handle directly, he just wouldn’t. Either they would retreat or use other means to get ahead, this by using a powerful treasure or tiring the foes out by having them fight multiple strong opponents at once.

This approach of course could be copied by Zhang Dong but he wasn’t willing to sacrifice the people from his sect as easily as the other Patriarchs did. However to everyone involved this wasn’t really a strength but a big weakness. A general couldn’t feel bad for their soldiers when out on the field of battle. They needed to take into account losing a few to save the many, sometimes sacrifices needed to be made.

Zhang Dong on the other hand put himself in danger multiple times. Over and over again he would put his nose into places that he shouldn’t. Considering that he was the leader of a massive sect now he should have enough people to do it for him. His biggest weak point was that compassion for the lives of others, even now he put himself in a spot that he could easily be trapped in.

Only with the system aiding him in an assured escape would he actually be able to escape from a place filled with nascent soul masters and powerful formations. There was always a possibility of enemies working against him. Perhaps when he arrived at the meeting place his brother would be there to capture him and along with the ten grand elders here, he would probably be able to.

‘Doesn’t seem like he is here though, lucky me…’

Of course, his fame that was rising was still new and he wasn’t taken quite as seriously as some might think. Thanks to this no one expected him to be brought to this assembly with the Heavenly Crane Sect on the line.

“Welcome sect brothers and sisters, we have gathered here today to contemplate the future of our Heavenly Crane Sect, last time we weren’t able to come to a consensus but now that some events have unfolded we must be prepared to make a final decision. Will we send our warriors to deal with this scourge or will we wait?”

Finally, all of them were there. The place might have been a palace on the outside but inside it was another lovely garden filled with tranquility. There was a shallow stream of water connecting to a middle pound at which the Patriarch was sitting. Behind him were two men wearing masks and radiating tremendous amounts of energy. To Zhang Dong’s knowledge, these two were called left and right guardians and could potentially be the way of moving these people.

‘So that’s the two… they are indeed at the cusp of the nascent soul level, well perhaps if I’m lucky I won’t need to do anything, let me wait for Sun Shen to make his speech.’

The ten grand elders and leaders of their factions were seated on the ground with everyone else behind them. Each faction besides the leaders could bring two other people. The Moon Lily side that he was with decided to bring him and Sun Shi along. This of course raised a few brows as no one knew who he was and why he wasn’t turning his head down when looking at their leader, Tao Guan.

He could feel some of the piercing gazes falling on his face. The two guardians that were next to Tao Guan were of course trying to get a feel of his power level. Their spiritual sense that was prodding at his cultivation was bounced away. As he was playing the Golden Dragon he needed to act for his position. In this large open space, only Tao Guan was at his level of status, if he turned his gaze away it would mean weakness. This was known by everyone and thus they were weary of a person that would dare to do this.

“Leader Shen, would you be so kind to introduce your friend, I’m sure every leader is eager to know.”

“I was about to, Leader Zhong. I just didn’t want to interrupt the Patriarch’s speech.”

The two old men looked at each other and sparks started flying. It was clear to Zhang Dong that the two men hated each other's guts whenever talking about the Sun Lily faction Sun Shen always did have a frown on his face. It was some kind of long-lasting grudge that most didn’t even remember why it started.

‘I guess this is it, better have that system window open just in case…’

Chapter 582

“I’m sure everyone here has heard about the hero of the west.”

“You mean Long Dong, the brother of the Azure Emperor? What does he have to do with any of this… It couldn’t be?”

“Yes, that’s right, may I present to you, Long Dong, the Golden Dragon of the west.”

‘Huh, I think my title is becoming longer…’

Zhang Dong didn’t flinch as he was being examined by everyone in this open-air meeting place. There was a gentle wind passing by that made the flowy robes that everyone else was wearing quite enchanting. He on the other hand remained in battle-ready robes that wouldn’t constrict his movements in any way.

“You are the honorable Golden Dragon?”

“Yes, that is true.”

“You must excuse us for such a welcome. If everyone knew about your arrival, then we would surely prepare a banquet…”

“Oh no that’s fine, things like that don’t really matter.”

Tao Guan the Heavenly Crane Sect Patriarch was giving him a bright smile that made him look like a gentle grandfather. In his mind however, there was probably chaos brewing and this Zhang Dong knew. This was quite the strange occurrence where a sect leader from a new up-and-coming powerhouse appeared before them without any preparation.

They were caught with their pants down and no one really knew how to react to all of this. Most of the elders were looking with spire and Sun Shen and Sun Shi that brought him over. Normally such a move would be discussed between all of the elders and the Moon Lily faction knew it. It was as if they were going behind everyone's backs and trying to force a decision to be made.

“With all due respect to the Golden Dragon but I don’t think he or even the Azure Emperor should be looking into our problems, Sun Shen what is the meaning of this?”

Leader Zhong from the Sun Lily faction burst out with anger while pointing his finger at the other old man. However, he didn’t take the bait and remained calm even when accused and scoffed at by some of the other faction leaders.

“I have only brought the Golden Dragon because he wished to present us with an offer that would be beneficial to us all.”

“You mean to your Moon Lily faction! Do you wish to become the next Patriarch!”

“ Leader Zhong, those are baseless accusations! Also, you don’t think that we don’t know of your own desire for that position!”
“That’s right, you think we don’t know what you are doing Zhong?”

“How dare you speak to the leader in such a way!”

This time Sun Shi was the one to start the shouting match. He was joined by the allies from other Lily factions while the opposition did the same. In a matter of seconds, the peaceful conversation turned into a shouting match between old men and women. Zhang Dong could only raise his brow at how badly this place was being run, the Patriarch truly didn’t seem to have much pull in this place. No one from his sect would dare to start something like this in his presence out of fear.

‘Having a good backing and personal power does really help but even when he is letting them speak those two seem angered…’

What he was more interested in was the two guardians that were behind the Patriarch. Sun Shen had informed him about the duo of experts; apparently, they had a peculiar story. First of all, they were twins just like the two others that came before them. They had a long-lasting history with the whole sect and were in a sense a weapon that only the Patriarch could use.

He didn’t get the full story but he could put it together by himself. Twins were always chosen for this position from the ten great factions. They would have to abandon their family and swear allegiance to the Patriarch instead. Those two would then be taught a peculiar martial art that could only be used by people of similar features.

With this technique, they could boost their power above a regular nascent soul master but on the flip side, they would be a bit weaker if they ever fought by themselves. It was some kind of dual cultivation method that blended the twins into a singular fighter. Zhang Dong could feel that their souls were quite attuned to each other, it wasn’t just their bodies. It was as if they had become one with each other, one being that could use two bodies.

‘If they can’t make a decision, then should I really go through with it or just wait…’

While the Lily factions continued to fight with each other he listened in and continued to feel them out. While he wanted to use this sect to help him take on the Phoenix Emerald Empire it wasn’t something that he couldn’t live without. Now that he made the trip here and set a teleportation spot it wouldn’t be hard to return. Just like with the demonic island he could just set up a teleportation gate for his people and move in without asking anyone. Bringing a forward force over with this replica medallion was also an option.

There was a lot of chaotic energy among these people. Each group was looking out for themselves and unwilling to give up on any of their current power. A large part of they still considered waiting for a good strategy but he knew that they would not be able to push back against the enemy. The only thing they would be able to do was to buy some time for Zhang Dong to get stronger.

Perhaps if he was a less compassionate person then this would have been a good plan. While he farmed the northern water empire the east side of the empire would probably last out for a few years. Even though the Emerald Phoenix Empire was strong they would probably lose a percentage of their forces and use up some treasures to get through the defensive array that was in this area.

He could even lay a trap and wait for his enemies to celebrate. When they were at their highest point and convinced of their power he could bring them down a peg. Within all those years he would have probably been able to bring forth more nascent soul masters and perhaps even defeat the other emperor. Then equipped with a new Dao he would have a better chance at victory than before.

‘That could be the best option but a lot of these people will die and lose their homes in the process, at this point they can still be saved…’

“Silence!”

Finally, after a long tiresome back and forth the two guardians stepped forward. Their aura burst through the entire area and smacked everyone in the face. Even the faction leaders had to turn their heads away for a moment as it was too much for them. Only two people were able not to look away, which were the sect Patriarch and Zhang Dong.

This was noticed by the people gathered here and put them in a bad position. First of all, it showed that the name Golden Dragon wasn’t boisterous. Second, they all knew that only masters of a certain level could just shrug off the twin's suppressive Qi. Thirdly, this put them in a bind as now they were rude in front of a powerful master that could very well be on the level of the Azure Emperor but without confirming this claim further they wouldn’t be convinced yet.

“Please forgive my people, they are under a lot of stress lately, you are probably aware of the situation at our borders.”

“Yes I am but I don’t think that you are taking it as seriously as you should.”

He could see Zhong gritting his teeth after looking up. There were probably various reasons that he would be against this type of meeting. One of the larger ones was probably because it made his sect look weak. Inviting an outsider like this without properly discussing everything was also something that went against sect rules. It was as if his faction wasn’t taken seriously in this decision that Sun Shen had made.

The others that were against engaging with the other empire were probably of the same mind. If it weren’t for Zhang Dong’s high cultivation level he would have probably been removed from this meeting place already. Only thanks to the way that he presented himself and his current fame could he stand tall and on the same level as the other Patriarch.

There was a limit to what he could do however if he was rude and pushed too much even these people here would attack him. They still didn’t know his full capabilities and only if he showed them what he was made of would they actually listen. Otherwise, he would need to return later with an army which they could not deny before forcing an agreement.

“I wish to not be rude to the Emperor's Brother but these are our sect's problems. The Azure Emperor has already refused his aid or did the honorable Golden Dragon arrive at the behest of the Emperor to offer aid?”

“No, my brother has nothing to do with it.”

Why the Patriarch didn’t use any rude words he did imply the standing of the Azure Emperor to be above Zhang Dong’s. It somewhat carried an implication that they wouldn’t move for someone like him that had not yet been tested by them. Rumors could only carry him this far without any proper information; they couldn’t take him as seriously as the Azure Dragon.

“But my brother isn’t all-knowing, he does not know the gravity of this situation and it seems that neither do you, the Emerald Phoenix Emperor is an expert not below me or my brother and you won’t be able to stop their forces, at least not by yourself…”

“Honorable Golden Dragon with all due respect, our sect has survived for thousands of years…”

“Will that mean anything when the Emerald Phoenix Empire arrives at your doorstep and crushes your people? Do you really think that these feeble defenses that you have will last you more than a few years? What after that, will you run with tails between your legs to my brother or me to save you?”

“Y…you…”

The Patriarch was stunned by the way Zhang Dong was speaking but he needed to get a point across. This was that the longer they kept to themselves and didn’t do anything the faster they would come to ruin. The only way out would be sending the bulk of their forces out to the warning zones because as it was now, their numbers and experts would be slowly diminished until the enemy arrived at their main sect grounds. Before that could happen and before more people died for nothing he needed to make this group of old farts move.

Chapter 584

“Patriarch? Won’t you reconsider? We can’t have an outsider like this come to our sect and challenge our elders, there are procedures that we need to follow.”

“Faction Leader Zhong, you are forgetting yourself.”

“I… I understand Patriarch.”

To everyone's surprise, Tao Guan took Zhang Dong up on the offer. Then out of nowhere he finally glared at Zhong that was throwing his weight around. The man had no right to call out the Patriarch on his decision; that was something he could decide on. The two guardians that were his protectors only answered to him and him alone. They would follow his orders just as they were taught to do.

Zhang Dong looked at these two men with identical stature and matching clothes. The only difference was that one was wearing a black robe while the other was donning a white one. They were no simple opponents and this he knew, they were endgame characters that would probably pose a threat to the generals of the opposing force. However, when pitting them against an Emperor level there was probably a gap that he wanted to show to these people.

It seemed that these people were having a misconception about the power levels existing in this world. The Great Circle level of the Nascent Soul realm was considered to be the pinnacle of power. Most people that achieved this goal were considered true grandmasters of similar power. With only the immortal stage existing above and no one being able to even grasp it to become a half-step expert, this was all they knew.

By this logic, even the Azure Emperor that was considered to be the world's strongest could be defeated by numbers. This sect had quite a number of nascent soul masters and was convinced that with enough of them any master could be taken down. It was just a matter of numbers as there was a limit to everyone's true power and potential.

He on the other hand knew that this wasn’t quite true. With the system and his world-traveling expedition, he had enhanced his soul. This was to the point of it being over the limit of what was possible in this world. Coupled with various other enhancements as his queer cultivation seed within, he was able to exert a power that was over the great circle of the nascent soul level.

The existence of stages between the immortal realm and the great circle was known to him. This growing seed inside of him was close to something like those but not quite. This created world rejected the conventional methods that allowed people to achieve one of those realms between the immortal one.

His own theory was that if a person was capable of grasping one Dao fully then they should be able to take the next step. In Zhang Dong’s mind, there were at least three steps the cultivator could take. The first one started from the Qi Condensation stage and ended at the Great Circle of the Nascent Soul realm. The second step started after that and ended right before the immortal stage which was then the third step and perhaps the final one.

It was impossible for the people to skip the middle step. The path was blocked by a mountain that no one besides a system holder could cross. Even those people like him needed to gather a massive amount of spirit points through the thousand or so years that they were allowed to live in this world. Then they would forcefully advance to a higher realm or at least that is what the speculation was.

No one really knew anymore what happened after a person reached the immortal stage. Even those with talent could barely grasp one greeted Dao in their entire life but even with multiple ones, it was still impossible to progress. He already knew it as he had a grasp on three greater Daos and his seed was still not opening up.

With each realm, some of the secrets of the world became more apparent. When achieving the nascent soul level a person became more aware of the spiritual energy around them. Probably the first step required a person to grasp one of the lesser Daos to advance. Then mastering a greater Dao to go further and finally perhaps multiple ones along with something else before achieving the Immortal stage. This he felt slightly after defeating Wang Long but the moment was too fleeting for him to fully grasp it.

Nevertheless, he considered himself on a level slightly above what a great circle nascent soul master should be. This was the same for the demi-human emperor that he face and also for Wang Long that was defeated. It wouldn’t be strange if the Fish Empress in the north or the Emerald Bird Emperor were above them.

This all depended on how this game-like world worked. Usually, there were two possibilities, one of them that whatever the order he beat the last bosses their power would not change. Then there was the second type that was more concerning where the emperors could become more powerful depending on how many of them were already dead. This would balance things out slightly for the enemy side slightly but he didn’t expect the emperors to get too out of hand.

Would this scaling process exist for the people that lived in this empire? Probably not. While the enemies grew in power the sects that he wanted to protect would remain stagnant. They already started at a lower point. Old records showed that if a system holder wasn't there to aid in the battles the lands would be overrun. Then the Long Clan would use their flying city to stem the tide and emerge after the enemies had retreated into their own lands.

“You are very confident in yourself Golden Dragon but you must understand our position, we can’t have the Emperor’s brother be injured in our sect thus…”

“Do you want a written contract? Don’t worry my brother won’t seek vengeance even if I fall here, your guardians can come at me what all they have.”

“If you are going to this extent then I will not stop you but let it be known that we from the Heavenly Crane Sect have warned you.”

Zhang Dong smirked a bit while producing a legally binding document along with a recording of this bout. Tao Guan didn’t seem to be convinced of his power but instead was worried that the Azure Emperor would seek trouble with them if something happened.
‘Not bad, he insulted me and my sect without even mentioning them.’

It didn’t seem that the Patriarch was concerned about the United Element Sect and any of their masters. No one was mentioned explicitly, it was as if they wouldn’t be able to seek revenge even if they wanted after he vanished. People did somewhat accept his strength but not much was known about people like Huo Qiang or Zhang Zhi that were only now showing their expertise. He could not really do much about it for now but perhaps after a joint mission with this Heavenly Crane Sect, even his people would finally be accepted as some of the all-time greats.

“A decision has been made then, let us depart to the holy testing ground!”

“The holy testing ground?”

“Yes, Leader Shen, will you please guide our honorable guest there.”

“As you wish, Patriarch.”

Zhang Dong repeated what the Patriarch said after the contract was signed. Tao Guan took the piece of jade with Zhang Dong’s spiritual signature as proof. Then instead of answering the question, he shoved that onto Sun Shen. He didn’t sound particularly mad about being called out but Zhang Dong felt that this man was working from some kind of angle. This angle was discussed previously between Sun Shen and him before this meeting.

“It seems that you were right, Leader Shen. I didn’t think that he would actually agree to something like this, this fast.”

“The Patriarch is a smart man, he knows that we need to move but is being held back by the traditions.”

“His arms are tied eh? Well I guess I’ll have to untangle those bonds”

“Honorable Golden Dragon, be careful the left and right guardians can’t be taken lightly not even the Patriarch could face them alone…”

“Don’t worry, I never take anyone lightly.”

Tao Guan, the current leader, could not force a move without straining his own position. This didn’t mean that he didn’t want to do something about it. The way he went about things didn’t really sit well with Zhang Dong though. Even if he was going to lose some of his power base in the sect or anger some elders, he should have prioritized his people and survival. The more they spend on bureaucracy the more lands were getting taken.

However, he understood that it was hard for anyone to forsake the old traditions. After a sect had existed for a while people would start to adhere to traditions. It was a safe road paved by their predecessors that had lasted them for millennia. It was a tried and true process that never failed them so there was no reason to not stick with it. Unless something really drastic happened there was no use in changing what was already working well.
‘I need to really show them the difference between the pinnacle experts…’

His main goal was to beat into these people that they should fear the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and his forces. This he could only do by totally eviscerating their top experts. He could not leave any doubt in their minds, the victory didn’t need to be swift but it had to leave a long-lasting stigma in their hearts.

“So, what is this secret trial ground?”

“It’s a secret spot that our elders use to settle disagreements, there you won’t have to worry about causing destruction to the surrounding.”

“Sounds good but I’ll hold you to that…”

“Hm?”

“Oh, nothing.”

Zhang Dong whispered while placing his hands behind his back and whistling. Soon enough all of the elders that were gathered here started flying away toward a certain location. This was a large mountain at the end of this valley that had been hidden from view by a grand illusory formation.

‘Not bad, even I had a hard time noticing it…’

It was quite well hidden and only when he got within a few hundred meters of the secret spot did he notice that something was there. This was truly an end-level zone that he would not have been able to discover on any other occasion. Inside was the battleground where he needed to deliver a swift beating to two people he didn’t know.

‘Well then, let’s see what these guardians are made off.’

Chapter 585

‘Looks like we are in some kind of giant soap bubble… neat.’

Zhang Dong was always surprised by the fantastic sights that this world was capable of providing him. At this very moment, he was floating around a large open area somewhat similar to another dimension. This one wasn’t as stable as the one used in the dimensional regalia or the replica he made. Instead of being contained its walls were somewhat transparent and looked similar to a soap bubble.

This produced clear edges of this zone that he was inside of now. From the outside, the space also looked more compact. When looking inside the elders from the Heavenly Crane Sect would see militarized versions of Zhang Dong and the two guardians that he was facing.

The landscape on the inside was quite natural and filled with green grass and trees. The whole area was around five kilometers in diameter with some hills here and there. It was enough for a nascent soul master to let loose, damaging the translucent walls of this place wouldn’t be easy even for him. At most he could puncture a small hole to get out or use his formation knowledge to find the exit.

‘The system’s teleportation function isn’t getting blocked at least so I don’t have to worry about them holding me captive here.’

What he was doing was quite risky. He placed himself in an unknown lesser dimensional treasure. Objects like this weren’t easily left and could act as a prison for a cultivator like him. Perhaps the Heavenly Crane Sect was even planning to do this if things got out of hand.

However, he managed to keep some decorum and was acting as an ally and not an enemy. If they chose to trap him here then perhaps the east side of the empire would already be lost. Without this sect's approval, it would be hard to maneuver in their lands. Potentially getting attacked by their masters when he was trying to subjugate the other forces was a possibility. In that case, the safer bet would be to wait for the Heavenly Crane Sect to weaken a bit before taking over their lands.

This would be then further complicated by the Long Clan which was right in the middle of it all. The whole thing might look like a hostile takeover even more and war might follow. As long as the Heavenly Crane Sect made an official statement asking for help though, then even the Azure Emperor couldn’t complain.

‘It doesn’t seem that this place has any suppressing formations at least, at most they would try to trap me inside…’

The notion that Sun Shen and Sun Shi had planned all of this out just to get him here crossed his mind. There could be many reasons why they would try to capture the rising star of the empire. Perhaps the Azure Emperor ordered it or they were hoping to stop his meteoric rise to power out of fear. This was a bit of a stretch though as the real problem was the Empire at their doorstep and not what was happening on the other side of the empire.
The people in this world mostly kept to their lands and ignored what was happening outside of them. This was also one of the biggest reasons that no one was actually interested in aiding the Heavenly Crane Sect out with their problems. It was their land and it was their responsibility to take care of it.

“You two don’t talk much but that’s fine, I’m a man of few words myself.”

Zhang Dong looked at the two men before him, they were standing there with their hands behind their backs just like him. It looked like there was a mirror between the two as their poses were identical to a strange extent. This was part of their routine and the power of the technique they were using. It was as if they were one being and their souls that showed signs of resonance confirmed this.

‘I wonder if it would be possible to go further with this technique and actually fuse both souls together…’

It was a scary thought to have two people combine their souls. Normally absorption of soul energy was possible while the rest dissipated. Then there was the more drastic method of devouring it whole without leaving anything behind. Such a thing would of course kill the person that the soul was devoured. Side-effects of such a technique were always there, memories mixed with each other and could break a cultivator’s mind if they weren’t prepared for it.

“Well then, let us get this over with.”

Finally, after looking over his opponent that was standing half a kilometer away from him, Zhang Dong called out to the people watching them. The one to answer was Tao Guan the sect Patriarch and after his proclamation, it was on.

“We will then commence the match between the Twin Guardians and Long Dong the Golden Dragon of the West. Let it commence!”

A loud gong echoed through this compact landscape but none of the three fighters moved. While the two guardians took up fighting stances their opponent Zhang Dong didn’t. He just stood there while looking at them with his piercing gaze. Weapons were of course allowed, each of the guardians had a long sword matching the color of their robes but their opponent decided to remain without it.

“What are they doing? Why aren’t the guardians attacking?”

Zhong asked with a rather angry tone. He had been against all of this from the start and perhaps thought that there was someone that was working in the background to make all of this happen. From his standpoint, there was also no possibility of the guardians losing if they took the fight seriously. The young upstart was strong but he clearly lacked the proper decorum and experience of a grandmaster. If they lost then it was probably due to some kind of deal being made between the Moon Lily Faction and the Patriarch.

“Do you really think that the Golden Dragon is an easy opponent, Leader Zhong?”
“What do you mean Leader Shen? Of course, he is strong but he can’t be stronger than the left and right guardians! This is a preposterous claim, are you insinuating that they aren’t moving because they can’t?”

“You might not believe me but that man can’t be looked at with our current understanding of the Dao…”

“Hmph…”

There was usually one reason for an expert of the nascent soul level to remain standing, this was due to their keen sense of danger. People like the Twin Guardians didn’t reach this level of power without a good reason. Usually, with age and experience, a sense of measuring an opponent's strength came with it.

It wasn’t that they weren’t willing to engage in combat, they just couldn’t find a weak spot that they could exploit. The path of cultivation was a path of self-betterment but it was a continuous journey with no one. Through it, there were always a few chinks in a practitioner’s armor that would arise.

These could then be exploited in combat but in this case, the two grandmasters couldn’t see anything they could exploit. It was as if they were looking at a giant iron wall that would not buckle under their punches even if they continued to hit it for years.

“If you won’t move then I will have to, from the outset I apologize for what I’m about to do but you must understand my position here…”

Zhang Dong finally decided to act, the twins reacted by placing their backs against each other. They were clearly guarding both of their blindspots which was the main strength of their techniques. With both fighters attuned to each other's moves, they could perform more daring attacks. They could fully commit to devastating sword strikes when knowing well that the other would defend them if their enemy managed to dodge it.

‘So, one of them will concentrate on blocking my attack while the other launches an instant counter. I could play around with that but this won’t get the message across without them realizing the difference in power…’

There were many ways of going with this fight but he wanted to send a message. He could beat them by safely using his ranged skills and using his superior Qi foundation. The space they were fighting was large but not that large either. Producing powerful wide-area attacks to whittle down their defenses wouldn’t be such a bad idea, considering he had a lot more in his tank then they both combined.

Instead however, he decided to get in close range and engage the two in a battle that they were famous for. Close-range combat using mostly fast-paced skills that didn’t require much spiritual energy but instead a lot of battle sense and skills. Thus with just one step, his body blurred as he found himself right at the right guardian’s side. This one was wearing a black robe and was quick to move into a defensive position to intercept the kick that Zhang Dong jabbed at his stomach.
The left guardian instantly reacted, at the exact moment that the foot would collide with the black sword, the white one would deliver a devastating blow to the opponent. The only way to counter this would have normally been to change the trajectory of the kick and try to evade it. Yet when Zhang Dong tried that, then the black blade would find its way into his side.

This was what the two masters worked as one expected but reality was different. The kick that they predicted increased in speed and collided with the black blade to send the right guardian tumbling into the horizon. The amount of sheer power and Dao behind that kick was just too devastating. Even the white blade that was supposed to take advantage of the perfect counter hit nothing more than air.

“You should work on that a bit more…”

The ten elders and the Patriarch that were watching this exchange almost fell out of their seats. They couldn’t see what moves Zhang Dong used, the speed was above what they could predict and the movement seemed mysterious.

“Want to try it one more time?”

Then they instantly frowned at what the man in the white robe was doing. Instead of continuing with the assault he just stopped. He didn’t use the chance he made to capitalize on the exchange but instead moved back to the spot he started in and waited for the right guardian to return.

“Now, I’ll do the exact same thing… see if you can react this time around.”

With a smile plastered all over his face, he flew forward once more. Staying true to his word the exact same kick was used and it flew at the exact same guardian as it did before…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 586

“Are the twin guardians doing this on purpose? How can this man be this powerful?”

“Leader Zhong, those are some serious allegations, do you have anything to back those claims up? Do the guardians look like they are losing on purpose? Are we looking at the same fight?”

“What are you prattling about Leader Shen?”

“Do you have eyes like the rest of us? Do you think any of the Leaders would do better than the guardians, even when we all attacked him together?”

“Preposterous, he can’t be that strong…”

“Are you sure, perhaps you should change your tune, what if the Golden Dragon seeks you out for an apology, you have been quite rude?

Zhong’s forehead began to sweat, something a nascent soul master should be above. Sun Shen, whom he was talking to, was smiling. Zhong wanted to deny the claim of Zhang Dong’s superiority but it was obvious that his skills were far above those of the twin guardians.

Even he who was a smidge above the other Leaders couldn’t see the man’s moves, it wouldn’t be strange if he couldn’t take more than a few moves before being defeated. Only with a combined effort of at least three leaders could he see them wining against such an opponent.

“Patriarch as you can see, this is the true power that we will be facing and what the Azure Emperor was holding back from us.”

“This is truly concerning…”

Tao Guan’s eyebrows wiggled as he tried to hide his displeasure. His true reason of allowing this fight to happen was out of curiosity. He wanted to measure the power of the man called the Golden Dragon who was rumored to be on equal footing to the Azure Emperor. The latter was considered to be the true endpoint and foe that was holding his sect back from taking over the whole empire.

Now, on the other hand, he wasn’t sure if that had even been something that they would have been capable of. This man was just playing around with their strongest tag team experts. Tao Guan knew the two well and in the past he even sparred with the two. They were his equals and if they wanted they could defeat him by sacrificing one in the process. When looking at this fight, he couldn’t see the two winnings even if they attempted that secret technique.

Their opponent was far too nimble and if rumors were true, he could also recover from critical wounds in a matter of seconds. To defeat someone like this they would probably need to entrap him in a powerful formation and reduce him to ashes. Perhaps if they overloaded the pseudo-dimension that they were fighting in and used all the power of the ten grand elders together it would be possible. However, if he ever managed to escape, their sect would be ruined.

“Is the Azure Emperor as strong as his younger brother or could he actually be the more powerful one of the two?”

“No one knows, the younger one only appeared recently. The old information we receive of him must have been false as well, it's impossible that some little sect as the Dark Palm Sect almost destroyed him.”

Since the Golden Dragon appeared in the empire everyone started gathering all the data of his exploits. His first appearance dated back to around six years ago in the then-small Zhang Clan. The rumors stated that he was dragged around by one of the middle-sized sects to do their bidding. It appeared as if they were actually almost able to kill him before a turnaround.

Now after seeing his true power it was obvious to them that this was some kind of elaborate theater show. It made them believe that this Long Dong was hiding his power and slowly presenting it to the world at critical junctures. Some attributed this to some kind of hobby that this Golden Dragon had. He probably withheld his full strength in hopes of getting challenged by weaker masters only to then seek conflict with them.

It looked like the other side was bullying him but in reality, he was a master that could wipe them out with a poke of his finger. This was more probable than the other hypothesis which stated that he gained some type of legacy of an immortal. Even those took some time to stomach and going from core formation to the pinnacle of nascent soul in just six years was unfathomable.

Either he was some kind of old perverse monster that took joy in getting into trouble or an expert of unmanageable potential. None of these two were good choices but the second one was a bit better as it would mean that the man could perhaps be controlled. If he was a young expert that earned power fast he would probably be lacking in many other places. It would be easier to control a young inexperienced practitioner than an old monster that was playing some strange game with others.

“Wait… could he be the one?”

“What do you mean, Leader Qiaolian?”

While the other leaders were brooding and looking at the two guardian’s being smacked around by the much younger Zhang Dong, one of their leaders tried to get their attention. She was on the older side and looked like a nice old lady with a staff. She was wearing a gray robe and in front of her was a floating crystal ball which made her look like some kind of fortune teller.

“Could he be the reborn immortal of legends?”

“Leader Qiaolian…”

The other leaders frowned when they heard what the old woman spoke. She belonged to one of the neutral factions that never took any sides. They were known for their future-telling techniques that sometimes bore fruit. They were oracles in a sense and had some chaotic beliefs, one of them was the belief in an immortal being that would be reborn every hundred thousand years during a chaotic period.

“It all makes sense, this is the period of turmoil that has been passed down in legends, he must be the one, that aura of magnificence radiates excellence… he must be the immortal that was promised.”

This group of fortune tellers was considered to be mostly filled with insane people. However, their power in the sect was large as thanks to their future sight techniques which they could use in their battles, they were strong foes. Thanks to their power they were able to hold on to one of the ten great seats.

“Leader Qiaolian why don’t you calm down, the Golden Dragon is certainly strong but he is not immortal…”

“That’s why you’ve always been a fool Zhong, you wouldn’t be able to tell an immortal from a cow!”

“Now listen here you old crow!”

“I won’t listen to a fool, at least Leader Shen had the insight to bring this man here, my faction will not remain silent anymore!”

“Do you mean?”

“Yes, we will support the Moon Lily faction if this individual is involved, we must support the immortal, this is why our faction was created!”

“Just because of some old prophecy, you would risk our sect's safety?”

“Old Prophecy? My people have been passing down the legend of the immortal through generations since a time when the empire didn’t even exist! It’s not just an old prophecy you old fool, it’s the truth of this world, the immortal has always appeared and we have always lent him our strength!”

“Y-you…”

Zhong was not happy to hear that one of the neutral factions had decided to switch sides. With the old woman supporting the Moon Lily Faction he needed at least one of the other three neutral ones to come to his side instead. If he wasn’t able to convince them otherwise then what Leader Shen was proposing would be voted in his favor.

“Both of you, calm down, this is not the place to discuss this issue.”

The patriarch raised his voice at the two leaders that were fighting with each other. It was quite a surprise to have the old woman speak this much. Usually, she was uninterested in the voting process. There was not even a record of this faction group ever picking a side and now suddenly they were interested in this white-haired man. The Patriarch needed to agree that there was something about this Long Dong.

His presence was either a blessing or a curse on this sect and it was up to him to decide. The only problem was that this could perhaps be the only time that he could get rid of him. By ordering the guardians to use their life they could probably stall for long enough to overload the pseudo-dimension. Either the man there would die or be trapped for all eternity between dimensions with no way of getting back here.

“I think they are almost finished… the left guardian isn’t moving, is he out cold?”

“Hmmm…”

The Patriarch looked into the transparent dimension. There he saw one of his best warriors down on the ground. It took a lot to knock a nascent soul master, something that wouldn’t usually be possible. It meant that Zhang Dong’s Qi had overwhelmed them to a point of no return. The other guardian didn’t look much better, his face which was kept behind a robe was exposed. His face looked like it had been beaten on for a few days, and his lips and eyes were swollen. The man could not even hide the shaking knees that were barely keeping him upright.

After letting out a sigh Tao Guan decided to leave it up to a vote. The power of this man was not something he could contend with and he might have lost his chance of doing anything by this point. His most trusted two experts would probably not be able to muster much energy to keep him busy long enough. It was better to not poke the beehive if he didn’t have to, working under this man wouldn’t be a shame and it really didn’t matter if Long Dong or Long Qing ruled over them. Perhaps the other leaders still had rebellion on their minds but he had somewhat given up on that notion.

“This is enough, honorable Golden Dragon, we have seen your capabilities and we accept you as a proper honorary guest of our sect.”

“Patriarch?”

The man made the announcement which would make Zhang Dong one of their closest allies. It was not a hollow title, it would force their own sect members to be lenient with the United Element Sect and punish them if problems arose.

“Is that so, well then…”

Zhang Dong started speaking but in a flash, his voice found itself in the room that the ten great leaders were occupying.

“How about we talk about this little war you are having trouble with…”

The Patriarch’s eyes bulged out in fright as he realized that he made the right decision and if he actually attempted something sketch he would have died in this very instance.

Chapter 587

“Are you feeling alright? You don’t need to kneel that far down…did she get lost here or something, Sun Shen?”

Zhang Dong whispered the last part into Sun Shen’s ear while looking down at a strange grandma who looked like a witch. After he left the special battle area she had face-planted down on the floor and was prostrating herself before him. His battle with the guardians was one-sided and all but he didn’t think they would react this extremely.

“No Honorable Golden Dragon, this is Leader Qiaolian she is part of our sect…”

“Is that so…”

When looking at the old woman that was performing a dogeza bow before him, he started feeling uncomfortable. It always felt strange for the elders in this world to do it, even though he was a lot more powerful than she was, there was still a big difference in age. The woman looked to be in the twilight years of the nascent soul level.

‘She must be over nine hundred years old…’

“Please stand up Leader Qiaolian, there is no need for this.”

He beckoned her to stand up and luckily the old woman followed his proposition. Before getting to this meeting he got a short briefing from Sun Shen. The names of all the various leaders were known to him and this woman was part of the Astral Lily faction that was known for their foresight techniques.

These would allow people to see a second or so into the future and allow them to react to some attacks. It was somewhat similar to reading the flow of battle but it had some downsides. At first, it might have seemed that knowing for sure what an opponent would do was a big advantage but at the higher levels of power this wasn’t true.

A second was a lot of time for a nascent soul master. If the person with the foresight ability used it and knew that a right punch was coming they could counter it. However, if the opponent was good at reading the flow of battle they could instantly alter the trajectory of the fist.

Using future sight to predict enemy attacks cost a lot of spiritual energy and were usually slower than outright reacting to movements. This didn’t mean that it could be always countered, if a person trained in both foresight and was good at predicting the flow of battle they would make a dangerous opponent for anyone.

“I am truly blessed to have lived long enough to be spoken to by the Immortal of legends!”

“Immortal of legends?”

“Ah yes… Leader Qiaolian is a staunch believer in an old legend that speaks of Immortal rebirth, you can ignore her if you wish.”

“How dare you speak in that way to the Immortal, bow down your heads you old fools!”

The old lady peeked her head up to look at Leader Shen and Leader Zhong. The others looked at her as if she was crazy and Zhang Dong was just trying not to instigate anything. At least the woman belonged to one of the neutral factions so she would probably vote in his favor.

“The Immortal? I think your elder has quite the admiration for me but I’m not quite an Immortal.”

He chuckled a bit to ease the tension between this group of cultivators. Everyone was somewhat looking stressed out after he just popped out of nowhere next to them. It was possible that they could have tried to do something underhanded so he set up a teleportation point on the outside and then used him after winning the bout against the twin guardians.

The two weren’t weak by any means but their power was just slightly above that of a demi-human tribe chief. They would probably be able to win against one but probably one of the combatants would be injured or even die. With this amount of power, they were certainly not capable of taking out an Emperor level threat.

It wasn’t strange that they were weary of his movements now. Just a few moments ago he toyed around with one of the two most powerful experts this sect could offer. While they probably had some secret treasures that could increase their power further, it didn’t mean that those would be enough. Also after witnessing his teleportation capabilities they probably assumed that they were never capable of confining him here in the first place.

This meant that he could have killed any one of their ten leaders and the Patriarch. After witnessing his close-quarters capabilities and how easily he defeated the twin guardians they were scared. They all managed to survive for a good reason, all of them were good at assessing danger and they knew that it would be unreasonable to aggravate Zhang Dong. Leader Zhong in particular was starting to quiet down and inching toward the people from his faction.

Perhaps in his eyes, three or four of their leaders would be enough to cut him down. The only problem was the bout that took place inside the pseudo-realm. There all of them could see one of the passed-out guardians while the other was popping recovery pills to help with the swollen face. No grand techniques were really used during that combat demonstration, it was just an all-around loss for their side.

“Nonsense, the honored Immortal just doesn’t recognize his legacy yet but if you wish, This servant would be glad to tell the legend.”

“The legend? Sure, I don’t mind listening to your story.”

The others did quiet down but the old woman continued to talk. He wasn’t sure where she was going with this but hearing out an old legend could be helpful. Perhaps it would give him an idea of some kind of hidden treasure trove that would aid him in this war. It could also point him to a weakness of the overseer that he still needed to face in the end even after all of this was over.

“Yes, the honored Golden Dragon is probably tired after his presentation, why don’t we resume our talks tomorrow?”

Sun Shen proposed this notion and the other elders were all for it. This would give them precious time to discuss this one-sided beatdown and even let the guardians recover from the injuries for the next meeting. The man known as the Golden Dragon was not someone that they could disrespect and this also put their relationship with the Azure Emperor into perspective.

If Zhang Dong was this strong then perhaps his older brother was even stronger considering he was still the one on the top of the Empire. What would happen to them if these two decided to team up against them in the future? Now was the chance to foster a good relationship with this new powerhouse of a cultivator. Sun Shen seemed to have realized this sooner than the others and this would give the Moon Lily faction a lot more breathing room as they were already in Zhang Dong’s good graces.

“Yes, I’m sure you have things to discuss but let us not forget about the real enemies that are plaguing your borders. I will aid you if you so wish, so please decide on what you are going to do before it’s too late.”

“We will consider your wise words.”

The Patriarch nodded while all of them flew away. His side consisted of the three leaders from the Moon Lily faction side that were eager to get to know him and the old lady that was just prostrating herself before him. Even though she was of advanced age her mouth continued to move as she spits out long-forgotten fables. This somewhat caused the other two elders to be dejected as they couldn’t introduce themselves to him just yet.

“Let me describe the legend of the Immortal being that walks this earth every hundred thousands of years, it’s a tale passed down from faction leader to faction leader for generations…”

He perked up as she gave him a number that he was familiar with. If this legend told of an immortal that appeared every hundred thousand years then it could be only one thing it was referring to, a system holder. By the things that he saw at the secret ground his predecessor made, he too came at a hundred thousand-year interval.

This old woman painted the legend a bit differently but it was clear that this was what she was talking about. Apparently every so often an immortal would appear, they would show genius-like progress and quickly reach the pinnacle of power. A century of turmoil would follow as they appeared but would be continued by an era of prosperity and peace.

This was probably all hogwash as depending on the character of the system holder they could very well destroy everything around them, just like wang long. The time frames added up though, hundred years of wars with the other empires and then peace after it was all over. With the system aiding these ‘immortals’ it was easy to win even against all odds. The legend then ended with the immortal achieving godhood and ascending to a higher realm.

“So, are you saying that I’m the same Immortal that always appears? Why would an Immortal being need to be reborn every hundred thousand years?”

“Our people have no right to make any assumptions, the deep insights of the immortal are his to contemplate!”

“I see… I guess there are ways of explaining it…”

The other elders looked at Zhang Dong with interest as he didn’t discard the preposterous legend outright. However, this didn’t mean that they actually believed that he was some old monster and an immortal to boot. Explaining the system to them would be meaningless but there were a few alternative techniques that could explain it all.

“Perhaps it's a way of prolonging life by rebirth, even though we call it the immortal realm we don’t really know if a person that reaches that stage can actually live forever!”

“That does make sense.”

Sun Shen nodded as they finally arrived at his personal valley side resort. There he could rest for the day and then go see if they would allow him to take part in their war. Even when they wouldn’t it didn’t mean that he couldn’t delve into their lands by himself. The show of strength wasn’t just to convince them of the dire situation they were in, it was also meant as a warning. Now that they knew that he was more powerful than their best masters, they would be unable to deny his entrance into the East.

‘Still… it will be better if I can join up with their troops instead of wandering these lands alone, I’ll just get lost and sidetracked as always.’

Another awkward day of old people trying to crawl up his ass awaited him. He could tell that Sun Shen had prepared a feast and many other cultivators were already flying here to greet him. This was part of living at the top but he never could get used to the awkward exchanges.

Chapter 588

“Stop pushing you bastards, just because you’re from the Azure Lily faction doesn’t mean that you are related to the honored golden dragon!”

“You have always been jealous of our ties to the Azure Emperor, it’s pathetic!”

“You mean that one disgraced elder that got beat up twenty thousand years ago and came running back here with his tail between his legs? Now that there is a powerful member of that family there you think that you are related! I’m probably a closer relative to the Golden Dragon than you!”

“Why, just because you have white hair?”

“Yes, snow-white hair like that must mean that he is related to our Frost Lily faction! Perhaps one of our ancestors was his master!”

“Ancestor my ass, baseless claims as always!”

“Why you, I dare you to say that to me again!”

‘They are really going at it…’

Zhang Dong was sitting in an empty room while drinking some spirit alcohol that he was offered. While he wasn’t that much of a drinker he needed some liquid courage to survive the ordeal that was waiting for him in the next room. After showing his power the Heavenly Crane Sect went ballistic and now everyone was trying to seek favor with him.

“Honored Golden Dragon…”

“Another one?”

“Yes…”

“Okay, just bring it in…”

While a shouting match between the faction members continued outside there were some people allowed to enter this room. One of them showed up with a nice-looking spear in their hands that they then placed on the pile in the corner. Seeking favor with an expert like him had some bonuses to it, one of which was the large pile of costly items in the corner. It was slowly turning into a massive heap of treasure that would be enough for some to perform acts of murder.

“Well… at least I can use those for the coming battles…”

Luckily these gifts weren’t tied to any sort of official deal. While normally a person would return the favor in some kind of way, Zhang Dong felt that aiding this sect in the coming battles was thanks enough. They were in reality just trying to bribe him and expecting something in return or at least that he would not bring down his rage on them if they didn’t.

There were various pills of the heaven grade along with weapons of the same. They varied in quality that he was already able to achieve on his own accord.

“These weapons could be used by some of the elders but they aren’t all that great either… should I just melt them down for resources and make something better?”

Thanks to his system he had a whole factory waiting for him to just dump materials in. One of the reasons for coming here was to get to the various mines that the Heavenly Crane Sect was known for. Those were needed to help him outfit his people with better weapons and power armor replicas.

He had designed new models that could be used by anyone and were attuned to many Daos. They would not be as good as the battle armor that he made for himself or his wife but the power increase was there. If he wanted to produce those types he would need to examine each person individually. Even with the system giving him all the stats, it wasn’t easy to produce those suits with better resources.

It was far easier to prepare several prototypes for the main types of practitioners. He mainly wanted to focus on the main elemental Daos like Earth, Fire, Wind, and Water. Then his sect was also good with the holy element. With those five prototype armors, he could outfit his army by type and organize them into groups. Some elements worked well with each other, like the wind could augment fire and let it spread more thoroughly through the air.

Earth and water produced mud which combined the weight of earth and the moldability of water together. Then the people that were versed in the holy arts would probably be used as a combat medic. With their powerful healing arts that could mend wounds almost instantly his army would be unstoppable. Even now as he looked over these treasures this type of formation was being used by his army in the north.

“Honorable Golden Dragon…”

“You may enter.”

Sun Shi along with Sun Shen walked into the room. Before speaking out they looked at the mountain of unorganized treasures. It was clear that they wanted to say something about them but couldn’t complain before an expert of his caliber. Instead, they brought out another topic that concerned the people outside.

“Firstly, I must apologize for my sect brothers and sisters, they are being rather rude when so close.”

“It’s fine.”

“You have my thanks for your understanding.”

Sun Shen clasped his hands while trying not to show his displeasure. Even now he could hear the elders outside from various other factions shouting at each other. Many of them were old masters that rarely showed their faces to the public. Now they were surrounding his home and it was up to him to make it bearable. As the host, he needed to prepare rooms for such highly regarded figures but the sheer number of them was making it difficult.

This place they were in wasn’t really made to host so many nascent soul masters. Naturally, when he tried to offer smaller rooms to some they started to bicker with the ones that received better accommodations. In reality, the room assignment was mostly depending on who arrived first but this didn’t keep them from bickering. It was a hit to their face if they were given worse accommodations than someone they felt superior to.

“It must be hard on you, having to deal with people like those.”

“It’s nothing to be worried about, if you wish I’ll tell them to leave for now.”

Sun Shen replied but the old man wasn’t good at hiding his dissatisfaction with the situation. Zhang Dong knew that even the Moon Lily faction leader would not be able to push away so many nascent soul masters. They were dead set on gaining favor with the honored Golden Dragon and would probably not leave before at least seeing him once.

“Fine… how about I go meet with them?”

“You would, honorable Golden Dragon?”

“Sure, I just have the thing that might quiet them down for good.”

“Such a thing exists?”

“Just watch, I know how to deal with people like them…”

Zhang Dong smiled in a somewhat devilish way which made the two masters recoil in confusion. They couldn’t really stop him from moving out after he stood up but they also wouldn’t refuse aid if he was offering it. The fact that he was willing to converse with the mob of masters was already enough. Also at this point, they didn’t believe that he carried any animosity toward their sect members. There were accidents from which he could seek reparations but he never acted out on those occasions.

“First let me just grab those.”

After a wave of his hand, the pile of treasures vanished from the corner of the room. They made their way into his spatial ring and later would be given away for processing. He on the other hand walked out through the door that led him to a nice cozy looking garden. There were several pagodas and ponds here, quite a nice place to relax. That is if it wasn’t filled with old people fighting everywhere.

“It’s the honorable Long Dong!”

“He is more radiant than the rumors said!”

The fighting between the cultivator masters ended the moment they felt his aura. Even though he was hiding most of it, a smidge was enough for a nascent soul master to get a read on it. Everyone here was at least a late stage nascent soul master and even a couple were above it. Some of the faction leaders from the other camp had come here as well. They were certainly unwilling to let the Moon Lily Faction get everything.

“I am glad to see that so many of you have come to receive me.”

Zhang Dong was fast to garner everyone's attention while speaking out loudly. His voice had a nice ring to it and thanks to his senior aura skill that he entered this world, everyone was in a state of awe.

“You honor us with your words!”

One of them replied while stepping forward. The man had quite a full set of snow-white hair that was similar to his but before he could continue another old gentleman appeared from the side.

“No, you honor this Azure Lily faction with your words and presence, why don’t we discu…”

“Hey, what do you think you’re doing, I was first!”

“Hah.”

The two old men didn’t seem to have the best relationship with each other. It must have been really bad if they forgot that they were in the presence of the Golden Dragon. They almost forgot that he was there and only remembered after more people started clamoring for his attention.

“Please calm down everyone, I’m fully aware of your plight and I have just the thing to repay you with, just give me a second…”

Everyone was confused about what Zhang Dong meant but it was clear that he was scanning through his own spatial ring. Soon an item appeared in his hand, it looked to be a book of rather good quality. However, it looked to be newly made which disappointed most of them. Usually, techniques that were highly regarded were kept on old parchments and never copied down to new ones.

“This is a little something I’ve been working on, I think it should be enough as a thank you for all your hospitality.”

“Golden Dragon, this is?”

“Oh right, let me show you…I think it should be barely able to take it…”

“What do you mean?”

With a little jump, he found himself up in the air. There everyone started looking at him with question marks above their heads that is before a massive spike of spiritual energy appeared around his palm. This palm started radiating with a strange power, it was truly immense and something they could not quite understand.

“Is that a pinnacle-grade heavenly palm art?”

“It must be… such power!”

The palm quickly flew forward and collided with the nearby protective barrier in the sky. This forcefield was not weak but it buckled under the hit and even cracks started to form before the energy dissipated.

“This is called the Mystical Elemental Palm of Heavens and it's as you see, the highest grade!”

“Could that book be…”

“Yes, this contains this technique, I’m sure you’ll make good use of it… then, I’ll leave you to it, my friends.”

With those words, he took the pose of a baseball pitcher and quickly threw the book into the distance which caused everyone to panic.

“H-how could he throw a magnificent technique like that…”

“W-what?”

“What are you waiting for? The one that gets the book, gets to keep it of course, well if you don’t want it…”

The cultivators looked at each other and frantically took off in the direction he threw the secret technique. Thanks to his plan the whole place had become abandoned but to his surprise so did the homeowner.

“I didn’t expect both Sun Shen and Shi to go after it too…”

After laughing to himself he returned to his room where he decided to contact his family and generals. It seemed that the war effort would be moving along soon as this sect had no reason to deny him anymore.

Chapter 589

“So we are in agreement then?”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

“This is surprising, didn’t expect so many of you to agree with Leader Shen’s faction, did something happen in this one day?”

“No, we just saw the errors of our ways…”

Leader Zhong replied while thinking back to the various riches the Golden Dragon had in his possession. The pinnacle-grade heavenly palm art wasn’t the only technique he pulled out from his spatial ring. There was also a foot art, a fist art, and even a movement technique all above what they were used to. Everyone soon realized that if they hugged Zhang Dong’s thigh tightly enough they could profit greatly.

“This might have been the first time this sect council has been established that all factions agreed to something, unanimously. What did the Golden Dragon give you in return, is there something you wish to disclose?”

“Please Patriarch, what do you take us for? We wish nothing more than to let our sect prosper, a gift from someone reputable as the Golden Dragon would not move us in the slightest!”

“Leader Zhong speaks the truth.”

“I see that Leader Shen is a great man of true integrity, I’m glad that we were able to put our differences behind us.”

“I agree, Leader Zhong!”

The Patriarch narrowed his eyes at the two faction leaders that a day ago were at each other's throats. The Moon Lily Faction and the Sun Lily Faction stood divided for millennia now. Either they were offered something worth more than their pride or they were under the effect of some demonic technique.

He couldn’t feel any demonic energy around them and the protective formations didn’t pick up anything. Thus he concluded that they were offered something they couldn’t refuse and had the gall to not fill him in on the rewards the emperor’s brother was offering.

“... If there isn’t anyone against it, then we will accept Leader Shen’s proposition and allow the Golden Dragon access to our lands.”

The Patriarch proclaimed and everyone else nodded. With this Zhang Dong would be able to use all of their teleportation gates and be welcomed in all of their cities without any trouble. No elder or formation would stand in his way and offering him help would be required from everyone affiliated with them.

“While we agreed to this, we also need to understand that we do not know what the Golden Dragon wishes to accomplish, for all we know he could have discovered some immortal treasure in the deeper regions.”

“Could that be true?”

“It does make a bit of sense… why would he be so generous otherwise…”

“Now now, this is just a theory of mine without a basis, why are you losing faith in him this quickly? Why did you agree so easily to Leader Shen’s proposal??

The Patriarch narrowed his eyes once more but the other faction leaders just evaded his gaze. At this point, he was already convinced that in a day they had been bribed in some kind of way. The reward must have been nice if they were keeping him in the dark.

“Fine be silent, what I wanted to bring up was a guide for Long Dong.”

“A guide, Patriarch?”

“Yes, we can’t have a prominent figure like that wandering around our lands unsupervised. Someone will need to take a risk and go on this journey with him. We need to be aware of his movements, we can’t know what his true plan is… so which faction wishes to offer up their masters to go on this journey with him.”

“...”

“The Moon Lily has supported the honorable Golden Dragon from the beginning, it would be best if we continued with this support.”

“Hah, you just snatched him before any other from us could! I think the Sun Lily Faction should take over now, our masters are far more diligent than yours.”

“That is slander and you know it!”

“Both of you stop arguing, the sect doesn’t revolve around the Moon and Sun Lily factions, our Azure Lily faction has close ties to the emperor’s family and Long Dong is part of it so it’s best if we take care of this.”

“No, we will do it!”

“No!”

The Patriarch looked in astonishment as the people started bickering again. While this was not anything new there was a danger of fists flying between some of the leaders. He had no idea what Zhang Dong could have promised them but they were really trying to seek favor with the illusive master. This scene was even more troublesome as the two strong guardians that were his bodyguards were still injured. Even though they were here with him they would not really be able to fight with their usual strength.
…

‘They are really going at it…’

Zhang Dong was not with the faction leaders at this meeting. Instead, he was eavesdropping out of sight with the help of his system. It wasn’t hard to leave a little something on Sun Shen who was there and listen in. After yesterday's break, he disclosed the fact that he had many wondrous techniques that he could offer to these old men.

Cultivators were really hungry for more wisdom so dangling something that could make them slightly stronger or that could prolong their life would make them go berserk. They were now all seeking favor with him in hopes of getting their hands on some of that knowledge. He had it all, pill-making formulas, blacksmithing secrets, and formation arrays that they were all dreaming of. Each faction was guaranteed to find something they could use.

‘If what Sun Shi was telling was the truth then they could be arguing for days before coming to a decision…’

This was not an easy dilemma for the nascent soul masters. Everyone wanted to make a good impression and sending a guide was a good opportunity to do so. In reality, he would be fine with throwing a custom book at each of the leaders if it advanced everything faster. After all this was over he didn’t expect anyone to be able to go after him.

Since the seed appeared inside of his body he had become a lot stronger and even with these secret techniques his opponent wouldn’t be able to match him. There was also a difference in studying those arts at such an advanced age. His people had a better foundation to take in superior skills. They would have more time to study them and also more refined Qi to use them.

‘Can’t go overboard though, it will take some years until the nascent soul masters reach the later stages, that is if I don’t enhance them with my system.’

He didn’t want to keep using it but the system still remained the best tool for winning all of this. His whole sect was already reliant on it and whenever he vanished they were quickly driven onto the defensive. If he didn’t need to take care of this war as quickly as possible he would have loved to allow his people to do things at their own pace.

‘Sometimes taking time to think things over is a blessing. Can’t do much about it now, without the system they wouldn’t be able to contend with the sea creatures and I couldn’t be here either… I also didn’t expect that thing to be here, now what should I do with it?’

Zhang Dong waited for the elders to reach an agreement while also looking at an item that fell into his hands. The item he was holding was a silver bracelet, the design wasn’t anything special but it gave away some of its true nature. What he was holding was a very powerful defensive artifact, something that Argus and Lucius were looking for.

“What was it, the Aegis Shield or something?”

This bracelet was given to him by the old lady that thought that he was an immortal reborn. It was apparently something that her faction protected through generations and gave to their Matriarchs. At first, he wasn’t sure what he should make of it but after analyzing it slightly he remembered a similar weapon, the holy sword that the golden knights were looking for. Just like the sword, it reacted to his divine energy but like the other item, he couldn’t activate it.

If he injected a copious amount of holy energy into this thing he would be able to generate a radiant shield. It was fully golden and made from energy, the bracelet would change colors from silver to bright yellow when he activated it. However, within a few seconds, he would have drained half of his Qi reserves. It was not something he could actually use in battle as he could produce a better shield with his own abilities.

‘This just makes me think that that holy empire in the south is meant for another system holder instead of me, Bob can’t even do anything with this thing unless I feed in an astronomical amount of spirit points.’

While the item couldn’t be used there was still hope if he decided to use up spirit points. For the time being he didn’t have enough, even with the farm against the fish people continuing he would not be able to. It was to the point that he felt that his fortress could be upgraded a level further before he could even be able to work with any of these holy relics.

‘But considering that it can be accessed by the system there is a way, maybe it's similar to the fortress that was just given to me just thanks to having the system…’

This item could have just been late stage loot that was left for a given system holder. It might have been the same as the flying fortress that was left by the late Golden Dragon, a hidden quest reward for him transmigrating into this world.

‘No use spending so many points on it, I have other things I can spend them on. I’m sure Lucius and Argus will be ecstatic to get this but…’

While he didn’t need this item for anything it didn’t mean that he couldn’t use it for something. The Golden Knights were quite strong and perhaps even had an emperor-level combatant somewhere or some kind of magical ability that could bring something at that level out. Their power would be much appreciated when going up against the Emerald Phoenix Emperor.

‘They did help me with the demi-human emperor for the sword… now I’m sure they'll do the same for the shield…’

A smile crept on his face as things were going his way. After the Heavenly Crane Sect decided who to send him with he would depart to the east. Argus needed to be informed about the shield artifact and a deal needed to be made. It was almost time to tackle another Empire.

Chapter 590

“Uh… are you my guides?”

“Yes, great and honorable Golden Dragon!”

“But why are there so many of you…”

Zhang Dong turned to Sun Shi, the man that came to his sect and started this little adventure. Next to him was his granddaughter with only two guards this time around. Besides these four people, there were ten other small groups with around four to five people in them. Each nascent soul master seemed to have four or three core formation attendants but this wasn’t all.

“To make the journey preferable the council had decided to use our finest luxury flying ship. It will of course be escorted by our finest warriors and you Golden Dragon will be tended to by our finest servants.”

“And you are?”

A new face appeared next to Shun Shi. The moment Zhang Dong witnessed his robe he knew what the problem was. This late stage nascent soul elder was from the Sun Lily faction and it was obvious that the two men had a history with each other. He noticed the faint eyebrow twitch and raise in blood pressure Sun Shi which indicated anger.

This turned out into quite the expedition with each faction lending them one nascent soul elder of varying power. Some of the less prominent factions only gave out an early stage master but they tried to counter this deficiency by putting in better-serving staff. There were quite a few of them and would somewhat complicate things.

While it would probably open a lot of doors to him he wasn’t going out for a picnic. The power this group of nascent soul masters offered wasn’t small but he wasn’t sure if he could trust them to protect his back. Would they continue fighting in a dire situation or just flee to save their lives? He had already grown accustomed to fighting alone and taking out the leaders and now that Wang Long was dead there was no one that could block his teleportation escape.

It would be much easier for him to go around the eastern regions alone to scout things out first and then come back with reinforcements. With this many people around it, his progress would be slowed down by the slowest ship they had. His personal speed surpassed anything that could be built and not like he had that much time to spare.

“My name is Kang Yunru, Honorable Golden Dragon, I come from the Sun Lily faction and I’ll be honored to guide you through these lands.”

“Hm… sometimes more isn’t better, I think we’ll have to make some changes.”

“Golden Dragon, what do you mean?”

Kang Yunru asked and Sun Shi perked up along with all the other various elders that were gathered here. Zhang Dong needed to put his foot down as they weren’t out here for a picnic. If too many came with him he would feel responsible for them and it would slow down his progress. Instead of a bulky gathering that was a whole battalion, he wanted to go light and scout things out.

For that reason, he needed to get rid of most of these people. This was slightly problematic as he knew that they would start arguing if he picked out one group instead of the others. At the moment he wanted to just grab Sun Shi who he already knew slightly and go. The man called Kang Yunru would probably start pouting and complaining though. Thus when thinking about it he decided to go for a mix.

“There are far too many of you, one speedy flying vessel is all we need. For this reason, I have decided, Sun Shi from the Moon Lily faction will come with me.”

Sun Shi started grinning instantly and glanced at Kang Yunru as if his side was victorious. Of course, the other old fart wouldn’t just take this lying down. He was quick to step forward with his voice raised.

“But Honorable Golden Dragon what about…”

“Hold on there, I wasn’t finished. To be fair, the Sun Lily faction can tag along too but the rest will remain here. If you can’t agree with my decision then I will just go alone instead.”

He needed to put his foot down. These people were like hungry locusts, they clearly only intended to come with him in hopes of him giving them new high level techniques or perhaps some pointers. It wouldn’t be strange that if he corrected someone's form that another would quickly ask for some help. This whole expedition allowed him to remember how shameless some of these old cultivators really were.

“If the honorable Golden Dragon has decided then it will be so…”

Kang Yunru that was about to go into a rant covered his mouth while faking a coughing sound. It was clear that he didn’t have anything against this situation if his faction was allowed to come. The others looked disappointed but they didn’t complain as much and this was also what he expected.

Both the most prominent factions the Moon and Sun Lily were like representatives of each side, as long as both of them were allowed to go the other lesser factions wouldn’t complain. It was these two large sides that stirred the pot in the first place so if they agreed with Zhang Dong’s decision the other eight couldn’t complain.

“Lend me your fastest ship, best if it won’t announce to the whole world that we are coming from the Heavenly Crane sect… got something less flashy than those?”

In the air, ten flying ships from each faction had been gathered. From their designs, they screamed that they belonged to this large sect. They all had some crane-related symbols on them that gave everything away, one, in particular, was just shaped like a white crane including big wings on the side. To sneak up on the enemies something more neutral was required.

“Less flashy?”

“Yes, if it was silent and had some camouflaging formations to hide our approach. It should also be very fast but doesn’t need to be large as we won't be traveling in numbers.”

“Such a ship exists but…”

“But what? If it exists then go get it, we are wasting important time, what if your sect brothers are dying to the Emerald Phoenix Empire at this very moment?”

“I.. very well…”

Sun Shi looked at Kang Yunru who somehow deducted which ship they would be going for. The whole place went silent as the nascent soul elders felt uncomfortable about what they would be doing. Zhang Dong, on the other hand, didn’t care, he just wanted to get out of here if they didn’t give him a ship then they could all just stay here.

“Let’s go, unless you wish me to leave alone.”

“No honorable Golden Dragon, please just follow us I’m sure the owner of the ship you wish to take will give it up willingly.”

“Give it up?... Well whatever, let us just get on with this.”

…

“That both of you would lose, I can hardly still believe it.”

“Forgive us, Patriarch.”

“It’s fine, no one could hope to defeat that monster. It is better if we work with him than against him, if we are lucky then we won’t even need to lift a finger.”

Tao Guan and the two guardians were talking to each other over some tea. After the loss they had taken their bodies were still not fully healed. Even with the various healing pills and elixirs, they had access to, getting rid of internal Qi damage wasn’t that easy. Each punch and hit that their bodies took was like another day's worth of rest.

“The Patriarch is right, we just need to distance ourselves from both of them and only act after a victor presents himself.”

“Wise words left guardian.”

Tao Guan nodded as the three were talking about the Azure Emperor and Zhang Dong. They believed that sooner or later the two brothers would come to blows. After this transpired they would either use that moment to attack or follow the victor. The decision was not made yet but it would require some more deliberation with the other ten leaders.

“You two should rest up.”

“Thank you Patriarch but I’ll come with you while the right guardian rests, he had suffered more than me.”

“If you must.”

The two were still his bodyguards that were supposed to shadow his every movement. The sect didn’t want their Patriarch to ever suffer a defeat as he was a symbol for the whole sect. This was the first time in many years that one of the protectors had become injured this much. Luckily while inside of this sect there wasn’t that much to worry about, the two slowly moved over to another location where something awaited them.

“This always seems to calm me down.”

Tao Guan gave out a sigh while looking at something that he had received from the previous Patriarch. A medium-sized crystal treasure that was floating on top of a magnificent pond. At first, it looked like it was a regular boat but after peeking another time a person could see that it was gently floating above water that could not touch the surface. The water was instead repelled from the crystalized surface of this flying vessel.

This had turned into Tao Guan’s hobby. He would come to this serene pond where a treasured flying ship was docked. He would either ride it slowly while fishing or just clean it a few times to relax. It was his last hobby and something that he learned to treasure through the years. While everything seemed to have continued to change this ship that he was proud of always remained the same.

“Hm? Who is trying to gain entrance through the formation… is that the Golden Dragon? What does he want and why are there two elders from the factions with him…”

He didn’t like the look of this, ever since this troublesome man entered his sect things started moving in a direction that he couldn’t foresee. While he was not the greatest Patriarch out there, he still considered himself one of the better ones. His motto was to go with the flow while slowly analyzing things around him. There was no reason to rush into things before he had the whole picture. This approach had gotten them through hundreds of years but now things were moving too fast for him to wrap his head around it and this man was part of the problem.

“Honorable Golden Dragon, was there some kind of problem?”

“So that’s the ship… it does look like it fits the description, good we will take it and depart immediately!”

“You wish to take my ship? What is this about…”

He glanced at the two elders that were behind Zhang Dong but they instantly turned their heads away as if they didn’t have anything to do with it. The troublemaker of a Golden Dragon in response landed on the boat that he was about to give a nice scrub down with a sponge.

“A fine boat you have, I’m sure with its help I’ll be able to get my mission over fast, thank you for your help, Patriarch Guan.”

Zhang Dong clasped his hands while smiling, someone else wasn’t smiling though and it was the owner of this boat.

“B-but my boat…”

Chapter 591

“This is a nice ship, it’s nice that the Patriarch let me borrow it, although he didn’t look so good… are you sure he wasn’t sick or something?”

“No honorable Golden Dragon, he was just slightly tired. He'll be fine in a few days…”

“If you say so.”

Zhang Dong nodded while turning away from Sun Shi and looking out into the distance. He and a couple of other cultivators were zooming through the clouds in a crystal ship. Thanks to the strange material it was made from, it was able to hide them from any peering eyes. It could block out their Qi and even bend light in such a way that it would be almost fully invisible. When going through the air no one would be really able to see them until it was too late.

“While we are here, how about you tell me about the place we are going to and what you know of the Emerald Phoenix Empire.”

“As you wish.”

“My Sun Lily Faction scouts are more informed, why don’t I take this over while Elder Shi rests for now?”

“What nonsense… our scouts are not inferior to yours!”

“Uh, how about you both tell me what you know instead?”

The two elders glared at each other while following Zhang Dong into the captain's cabin. There they could see the scenery passing by at an alarming rate through a small window. There was no shaking or turbulence which made it a smooth ride and allowed for ample conversations.

“We will be arriving at the City of Panhua in a day, close to it is our closest outpost that some of our sect elders are guarding.”

“City of Panhua?”

“Yes, have you heard of it?”

“No… I just expected a different-sounding name… could it be because its closer to the Eastern Empire? Ah, sorry I’m just thinking out loud.”

Zhang Dong was confused at the start that the city that they were going to didn’t have the usual sounding name. It was more in line with the cities in the Emerald Phoenix Empire than what he was used to here. Kang Yunru nodded and continued with the briefing but there wasn’t really that much information to go around.

First of all, at least half of the eastern regions had already fallen into the hands of the Emerald Phoenix Empire. This constituted all of the lower regions and part of the middle ones. Kang Yunru didn’t mention it but from Zhang Dong’s perspective, this was still an amount that the Heavenly Crane Sect could stomach. They didn’t really care or need anything from the lower regions as the sects in the middle region were the ones sending them taxes in various forms. Unless they lost the bulk of the middle districts they wouldn’t really care or feel a loss.

“So they have been stopped at this outpost close to the City of Panhua?”

“Not exactly.”

Sun Shi chimed in while Kang Yunru became silent during his explanation.

“In all honestly they should have been able to continue forward and take the outpost and the city over, for some reason they stopped with their forceful push and retreated into the territories that they had already conquered.”

“They did? Hmm… they might not have had enough resources for a prolonged siege perhaps? But they could have been other reasons, like searching for something in the lands that they already occupied or waiting for reinforcements…”

Zhang Dong spoke out to the two elders that probably knew more about tactics than he did. They just nodded without speaking, it seemed that they were mostly of the same mind.

“Some of our elders are of the mind that they didn’t have the manpower for a further push, Leader Shen wished to launch a counter-offensive due to this reason but the Leaders couldn’t reach an agreement.”

“Leader Zhong didn’t see a purpose in attacking now, we didn’t have enough information about the situation.”

“Hmph.”

The two elders continued to scoff at each other. One side wanted to quickly push back at a seemingly weakened enemy while the other didn’t see a problem in waiting. Both of them could have been equally wrong or right. From Zhang Dong’s perspective, taking back some lands would have probably been the better idea, that is if they actually had the army for it.

As it stood now he didn’t believe that the Heavenly Crane Sect would win a large-scale counter-offensive without going all out from the start. This they would of course not do as it went against most of their core beliefs and their way of life that allowed them to exist to this day.

‘They probably could have pushed in further if they wanted, they must have been another reason for it.’

He had already asked around the Heavenly Crane Sect about all the information that they had. The Emerald Phoenix Emperor had apparently not appeared yet, at least he did not make a move. The people from that empire were different from the demi-humans, they weren’t here to play around. To them, this was probably more akin to a huge secret ground zone that was opened every hundred thousand years.

Considering that they were almost identical to the cultivating nuts in this empire this was probably the case. They had certainly been preparing for hundreds of years for this event, perhaps even thousands. In their mind probably a way to immortality existed here and even the Emperor wanted it. It wouldn’t be strange if all their strongest sects ventured here to compete for that elusive power-up.

The only problem was the bridge connecting to this world. It wouldn’t be strange if the strongest sect or in this case the royal family tried to block access to these lands. While they probably wanted some help in taking over the lands this meant more competition for them. It wouldn’t be strange that they would start infighting when discovering that treasure they were hoping for.

‘Well… not like it exists, it’s probably some lie thought out by the Overseer or the one above them. I bet they sprinkled some rumors about the location of this immortal treasure. In time they will get to the Azure Emperor's palace if they aren’t stopped…’

This was only his speculation, to confirm this he needed to capture someone that was in a higher position than a junior sect member. It wouldn’t be strange to anyone below the nascent soul level to be uninformed about the true purpose of this war. They had to listen to their elders that could snuff them out with a poke of their finger.

“We will see when we get there, do you perhaps have any idea of the numbers of Saint Emperor-level cultivators that they have?”

“Saint Emperor? So the honorable Golden Dragon does know about their strange cultivation realism.”

“I’ve heard a bit, they an early level Saint Emperor should be above a regular nascent soul master.”

“That is right, some of our elders had fallen when combating those ferocious masters.”

“Hah, I bet they just got lazy and forgot how to fight after all these years of latency.”

Kang Yunru grumbled while commenting about the deaths of his sect brothers. It seemed that mostly elders of the early and middle nascent soul realms were stationed there. They were also all old and too busy sitting in their cultivation chambers to do anything in real combat. It wasn’t strange for masters to become complacent at an advanced age, their only thought was to prolong their life and nothing else. When coming in contact with hungry battle-ready masters they were sure to fail.

“They might have to fight again soon, it would be better that we get there sooner rather than later.”

“Do you think that they will attack once more after retreating?”
“It’s possible that they just decided to rendezvous with some reinforcement, it would be better to stay vigilant, they could appear at any moment but I could also be wrong.”

The two elders nodded and after some chatting, the two left the cabin and returned to their own. This ship wasn’t that large but there was room to spare for the entire crew. With the two nascent soul masters came around five core formation experts and a few lesser servants to tend to their needs.

Thus while traveling through the lands he took a look over his system screen. There he investigated the state of his own sect. There wasn’t much to see there besides the ever-increasing number of spirit points. Ever since he took over the west side of the empire it was designated as his territory from which he was allowed to get his spirit points from.

These he received from having a good approval rating from the people living there. Perhaps it wasn’t the best of times for the people living there but it was for his spirit point farm. The citizens there just wanted to get back to their homes so their approval was particularly high whenever they were just able to return. As long as the war lasted and they felt that they needed the protection of the United Element Sect, it would probably not change.

It felt bad to use this war to get more powerful but not like he wouldn’t take care of those people after it was all over. The only problem would remain in the form of the old Emperor which he didn’t really want to face. However with the overseer huddled up there, the confrontation could have been predetermined already.

Thus time continued to pass as he examined the map and the mass of red fog in the eastern corner. Just as he expected, the biggest concentration of Qi was right outside of the cross empire bridge. Which wasn’t anything alarming but the concentration there was quite staggering. His assumption that his new enemies were treating this as a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to reach immortality was probably true.

“One side wanted to hunt people for fun, one to gain immortality, one to find a long lost treasure to help them survive… that just leaves the ones in the north that I don’t really know the motives for… but they probably just want something like world domination…”

Soon he shot off the mapping device to just glance outside the window. Without ever being in these lands he couldn’t just teleport to the city he desired. Instead, he needed to establish a safe point where he could summon his people if he needed them. That wasn’t really the plan as his forces were busy in the north, instead he needed to somehow utilize the Heavenly Crane Sect and their vassal sects to fight for him instead.

“Well, it doesn’t seem like I will need to wait for long, a red blob is getting close to that outpost… I just hope that we can reach it in time…”

Chapter 592

“Is this really it? Is this all that a branch sect amounts to?”

“M-my apologies senior but we must retreat, our warriors aren’t strong enough to hold the formation, they are going to break through soon, we need to evacuate!”

“You want to evacuate? Me an elder from the main sect!?”

“I…”

An angry-looking old man dressed in a white robe with the Heavenly Crane Sect insignia was shouting at another elder. Before them stood a large wall that they were protecting, large amounts of cultivators were flying on their swords and frantically trying to reinforce the protective formation with their Qi.

“It has only been a day! How can you dimwits not be able to empower this formation our ancestors left behind even for one day! We must not retreat, we will defend for as long as we have to and the main sect sends us reinforcements!”

The man’s nascent soul aura flew through the area stopping any replies of protests from the other people here, in his eyes, it would be dishonorable to retreat. The people under him wanted to cry out in indignation and run away. They knew that this man was strong enough to flee after the barrier was gone but they on the other hand had no such power. There were various elders just as strong as this man there and they would make quick work of their defensive structures and weapons, the battle was already lost.

“B-but, they won’t make it in time, we lack a teleportation gate at this outpost, and the closest city is two days away, we won’t last.”

“You still dare speak up? Be quiet!”

One of the older core formation experts cried out through his bloodied teeth as he was being suppressed by the much stronger elder. No one could go against him, if they dared to retreat they would be killed by his sword but if they stayed here the monsters on the other side would break through and do the same.

There was still hope though, if they were really able to hold out then perhaps a few elders that remained at the main city would arrive. They didn’t believe that the main sect would do anything about this as they had let many other outposts like this fall. Even if they fled now they would be branded as deserters and their close relatives would suffer the same fate. This was the price for yearning for immortality, only the resourceful would remain at the end and everyone here knew it.

“They are truly weak, we should have not waited this long and just continued to their capital.”

On the other side of the barrier, a different scene was playing out. Members of the Emerald Phoenix Empire were having quite a jolly good time. Grins were plastered over all their faces as they were ready to massacre their opponents the moment the barrier was blasted open by their large-scale ships. These along with their own battle formations were pouring their own version of spiritual energy onto the shields and quickly getting through.

“You are right Senior, if that order wasn’t given we would have been able to gather more merits than the other battalions.”

“That is true, I don’t expect these lesser warriors to have anything of worth but perhaps we’ll get lucky.”

“You are right senior, the further we get to the middle of this backwater Empire the higher the concentration of this magnificent energy.”

“Yes it is truly a blessed land, I feel that I’m already close to breaking through after spending just a month's time here.”

A Saint Emperor-level cultivator and his Supreme Saint follower were laughing while watching the siege taking place. To them, this was a land of secrets that opened up every hundred thousand years. Only the best elders and most diligent prospects could enter it and the rewards were truly magnificent. First of all the Qi here gave everyone a big boost, the concentration was at least twice as high as in their Emerald Phoenix Empire.

However, while this Qi was bountiful the residents of this region weren’t able to use it. They had captured various elders and some were on the level of Supreme Saints but paled in comparison to their grandmasters. They were using a faulty cultivation method that didn’t allow them to prosper in this place. The people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire, on the other hand, could prosper here, it was to the point of some of them instantly breaking through after entering this spirit-energy-rich environment.

In comparison, the pills, elixirs, and weapons that these lesser cultivators could offer them weren’t all that great. There was nothing besides the raw resources in their lands that were worth claiming and the spirit stone mines were one of the better catches. With the ever-increasing quality when pushing forward they were convinced to find something great in these vast lands that were even larger than their own Empire.

“That’s it, I can’t wait any longer, all Generals and Commanders follow me, we will push through this flimsy formation in one go and then slaughter the enemy!”

“As you command, Senior General!”

All of them were waiting for this order, even though they would need to use up a lot of their power it would come back to them almost instantly. This was the true might of their forces, even though they were outnumbered by the native people here they could fight almost without resting. Even their biggest attacks that would normally put them out of commission for multiple days would only need an hour or two before they recovered.

With all this newly gained power they were drunk on it. Every part of their body was bursting with new spiritual energy and it made them feel invincible. What normally would have been a suicide attack would turn to assured victory as they were not afraid of tackling the enemies in a direct fight. Thus they all combined their power to form an enormous bird that looked like a phoenix.

It was made up of green flames and symbolized the whole Empire. The technique was a war formation developed by the emperor themselves and took this form for a reason. It was supposed to signal his coming and the green flames were intended to be burned into the people that didn’t perish in this noble creature's wake.

“We… we can’t hold it!”

The large monstrosity collided with the translucent barrier that began to buckle under pressure. Everyone on the side of the Heavenly Crane Sect was giving their all to just hold out long enough for some reinforcements to arrive, it was to no avail as with one strong attack the enemies managed to blast a large hole in the middle. Even when they tried mending it back together it couldn’t.

“Haha, look at those inferior cultivators, it’s impossible to reestablish a protective formation after it was broken by the emerald flames!”

Just as the Saint Emperor proclaimed the green flames started burrowing themselves into this formation and expanding the hole that was created. Within a few moments, this opening was large enough for a person to pass through and soon enough it would be large enough for one of the large flying ships to get through.

“I Wung Tong of the Enlightened Victory Hall will pave the way for everyone, follow after me soldiers!”

Someone at the level of a nascent soul master charged through he created an opening and unleashed his large glaive arts on the people on the other side. The core formation experts that were hovering on their swords were unable to defend themselves, retreat was the only option but this only hastened the expansion of the fissure and soon enough more enemies arrived.

“You fools, who told you that you could retreat, fight to the last man!”

“S-senior, they are too strong, we need your aid!”

The man responsible for all of this started sweating. Even though he was loud and boisterous he also realized that the masters they were facing were a notch above them. The person that came in first was his match and from what he could tell he was not even the commanding officer. Even if he tossed himself into the fight there would not be much that he could do.

“Useless bastards.”

His pride didn’t allow him to back away though and soon he performed a quick palm stroke on the enemy elder. It produced a violet burst of energy that flew like a spiral towards the man that made it through the opening.
“Hah, weak!”

The man moved both of his palms toward this large attack and started swirling them around. His hands started moving in a circle as he performed a well-known energy-dispersing technique that worked wonders on this attack. Instead of getting hit by the violent palm Qi it was fully dispersed and couldn’t even harm the weaker Supreme Saint and Martial Saints that followed soon after.

“Is this all that all you people amount to? The Azure Dragon Empire? You are no dragons but just small snakes trapped in a tiny well, the phoenix will rise in these lands and rule over them, kneel before us and we might spare you!”

“You damn savages want us to surrender? We know well what you do to people that surrender, you have no honor!”

“Haha, so you know but you would have at least had a chance of becoming a slave or given a quick death, now we will just play with you until there is nothing left!”

“S-senior!”

“I…”

The old elder that kept everyone from retreating was biting his lower lip and drawing blood. He had made a mistake and now everyone here would die for it. The line was broken and the stronghold they were guarding would fall into enemy hands. Throughout his long life, he had never tasted a defeat like this. However, if he was going to die, then at least he needed to take some of them with him to the afterlife.

“We are of the Heavenly Crane Sect, we shall not surrender and we shall not plead for mercy!”

He could see that the people that were with him didn’t want to listen to his last order. They were weak and their fear was showing. It was another fault that fell on him as their leader, instead of training them more he spent most of his days raising his personal power. In battles like this however numbers did matter as with help of battle formations the tides could be turned even by lesser cultivators.

“Hm, good words but you will not die today, old man.”

“Huh?”

Before the carnage could start a voice resounded from above the clouds which made everyone look up. It was clear that it belonged to some kind of powerful master as it carried his Qi with it. When looking to the sky everyone saw him and it would be a silhouette that they would not forget for the rest of their lives…

Chapter 593

‘Hm, these appearances out of the heavens are becoming a bit cliche but they do work on a new crowd.’

Zhang Dong arrived at the City of Panhua fort which was in the middle of a siege. The barrier protecting them had been broken down and enemies were starting to trickle in. Before any serious injuries or deaths could happen he decided to jump in.

In actuality, they had arrived a full minute before the barrier was broken but a problem arose. The Moon Lily and Sun Lily faction elders started arguing about the plan. Kang Yunru wanted to wait it out to see how it goes, it seemed that he didn’t want to go into battle that wasn’t in his favor.

Sun Shi on the other hand wanted to instantly dive in to save his people. To quiet the two down he finally pronounced that he would go into battle while the two could do whatever they wished. He didn’t really care as after a quick scan of the surroundings he didn’t spot anyone that could be his match. The two late stage nascent soul elders would probably have a hard time competing against the multiple Saint Emperors down there, but not him.

‘Saint Emperors… Supreme Saints and Martial Saints… They seem stronger here than when I was in their empire, this is something that was probably intended by the system maker.’

He could quickly tell that these cultivators had been boosted by the Qi from this empire. Zhang Dong had traveled through the Emerald Phoenix Empire after coming back from the previous world but didn’t take that much time to examine everything. It would probably be better to catch some of these experts to examine their cultivation, perhaps he could implement these enhancing methods somehow to boost himself or his people further.

Maybe there was a way to isolate the effect but perhaps there wasn’t. It could have been some kind of racial trait that these people had and it would not be possible without their bloodline. Nevertheless before taking any action regarding their unique cultivation methods he needed to clean this place up. He could see at least two Saint Emperors having broken through the array and multiple Supreme Saints at the late stage.

‘If I recall correctly they only have three small realms in their cultivation, so those Supreme saints are close to half step nascent soul masters.’

The number of Supreme Saint experts on the other side was comparable to the core formation experts on this. However, they were much stronger than their Azure Empire counterparts. Adding the spirit energy boost on top of the half-step nascent soul power level made these quite an army, even nascent soul masters would have trouble with these numbers.

‘So this is probably the main problem, while they don’t have more masters at the very top, their main army base is a lot stronger with all these Supreme Saints around. However… that is if they don’t have a person like me leading them…’

Zhang Dong was slowly coming down from the sky while producing a magnificent radiant glow to blind the people down on the ground. It looked like the sun was rising behind him to illuminate this place that was surrounded by darkness. Only torches from the fort and the colorful techniques had previously given light to this place, now as he was descending it looked as if a new dawn had risen.

“Hah, do you think that I Wung Tong, the Hall master of the Enlightened Victory Hall, would be scared? You mean nothing and will go down as an unknown stepping stone in my path to glory.”

“Uh…”

Zhang Dong didn’t have any time to perform the usual seniorly pose. Who seemed to be the leader of this group of Saint cultivators quickly burst into a monologue instead and stole his limelight. Then just as quickly he flew forward like an arrow drawn from an exquisite bow.

‘Hm, could he have identified me as a threat and means to finish it in one go, or… is he just an idiot?’

He wasn’t sure but it was more probably that the latter was true. If the man knew what he was up against he would have just retreated first and then tried to charge at him with the help of the other Saint Emperors that were still on their way. Shooting at him with the large cannons from those bulky ships that were floating in the background would have also been a better order.

“HA! Die to my blade!”

“Hm, sword intent? It’s not bad but …”

The man surrounded himself with massive amounts of sword energy. It circled around his body and would shred anything that came in contact with it. It was clear that he wanted to bounce any potential attacks away from his body while also performing a quick and vicious attack.

“Huh?”

Perhaps if he was up against Shun Shi it would have worked but this was Zhang Dong, the Golden Dragon and liberator of the west. With two fingers the sharp weapon was grabbed before it could poke through the heart as it was intended. The stop was immediate and the sudden stop caused a backlash against the weapon. The sword tip showed a few cracks as the massive amounts of Qi that it was infused with were too much for it to handle. Before the man could let of his blade this energy also injected itself into his sword hand to cause an explosion of flesh.

“ARGHh…”

Just a second ago the man was flying through the air while looking like a gallant warrior, now on the other hand he was falling down like a deflated balloon. The rebound was tremendous and Zhang Dong made sure to inject his opponent with a large quantity of his lightning Qi. It was now wrecking his body that he was not able to protect.

“H-hall Master!”

“How could this be, how could the General fall this easily, it must have been some sort of trick, don’t let this affect you and charge!”

While Wung Tong was falling down from the sky the voice of another Supreme Saint echoed through the area. When taking another look all the people here were color coded. The Leaders that consisted of Supreme Saints were wearing robes that were purple. Then the next in line that were the Supreme Saints were red and the ones below yellow.

‘I guess they have some kind of color-coded ranking system, considering their Emperor has something to do with emeralds, green will be the most prestigious of them all?’

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure but thanks to the bright colors he knew exactly who to target. The enemies were all wearing the same types of clothes and were clearly part of one army. He wasn’t sure if this was just part of this Enlightened Victory Hall but when listening to some of the shouts it didn’t seem that they all knew each other. It was possible that the army was conscripted by the Emperor’s forces before setting out to the Azure Empire.

While Sun Shi and Kang Yunru were arguing he was listening to his enemies. Even now the man that he one-shot was called a general. On his side on the other hand people still segregated themselves into sect juniors and seniors. This division was a bit less orderly and additions from other sects or clans wouldn’t be easily welcomed. However, if the opponents had a strict army regiment then it would be a lot easier for them to react to orders.

‘I guess that’s another reason why they have been winning so much, the Heavenly Crane Sect’s allies are nothing more than slaves. It wouldn’t be strange for any subservient clan or sect to abandon the fight the moment they had a chance…’

It looked like going forward wouldn’t be as easy as he had assumed. If the enemies had a regiment of trained soldiers that were also cultivators then it would be difficult to progress. It was one thing to fight against people that had no idea how to co-operate than ones that were used to fighting with each other. This was also one of the reasons why his troops were so ferocious, their teamwork was impeccable.

‘These guys seem like they might have been the last hurdle to pass.’

Within a few moments he made his decision, the Saint Emperor that was injured wasn’t let go of the hook as he quickly appeared behind him. A hit to his dantian quickly ended the general's military career. At first, he wanted to play it up for the Heavenly Crane Sect forces and raise their morale. However, these enemies weren’t a joke and could probably produce some nasty war formations to prolong this battle and cause more carnage. He needed to end it and do it swiftly before his enemies could regain their bearings.

Thus instead of using flashy attacks that would cement him as the famous golden dragon, he went with speed. His body became clad in golden lightning as he flashed next to the second Supreme Saint opponent. This man was slightly weaker than the previous one and after delivering a palm strike to his chest he flew right back toward the hole in the array that all of them came from.

Everyone was shocked at what was happening, two powerful experts had been rendered useless within a few seconds of Zhang Dong’s appearance. However, this wasn’t the end as the golden bolt of lightning shot right after the man that was just struck. While using the Supreme Saint as a human shield he burst to the other side where the bulk of the enemy army was waiting for him.

“No one will disturb us here.”

He made it to the other side and after performing a pinching motion with his thumb and index finger the hole he came from began to close. A little something in the form of a chaotic orb of lightning was left in the middle of the opening. From the core multiple electrical lines shot out to grab the opening defensive shield. It created a net of charged lightning that was slowly closing itself. When touched by anyone it would electrocute them and turn them into a charred corpse almost instantly.

“Yunru, Shi, I’ll leave the small fries to you that got to the other side, leave the ones on this end to me.”

“... Y-yes honorable Golden Dragon.”

Sun Shi replied after finally getting out of the hidden ship together with Kang Yunru. The enemies that got through were not on their level. The two elders instantly knew what Zhang Dong had planned and had no reason to refuse. This was a stronghold of their sect and enemies that could kill their juniors were here, the two were more than capable of suppressing them all by themselves.

“Well then, show me what you are capable of.”

Zhang Dong on the other side shot forth toward another Supreme Saint. First, he needed to clear out all the commanding officers, and then perhaps he would be able to take their equipment without damaging it too much.

Chapter 594

“ARGH… he’s going through our ships… stop him!”

“The ships… they can’t take it…”

“U-use the war formation, entrap him!”

“H-how could someone be this fast, the formations are crumbling!”

Shouts of soldiers being knocked out or blown away echoed through the battlefield as a blue of golden lightning energy went through it. No one was fast enough to react and each defensive trap they tried to muster was shattered instantly the golden being of light went through it.

Within a few minutes, the army of thousands of Martial Saints and Supreme Saints was no more. Their large flying battleships that proudly flew an emerald flag with their emperor’s insignia went up in flames. The giant war formations that looked like giants made from energy popped into nothingness the moment the radiant golden glow plunged itself into them. It was a one-sided slaughter and nothing but retreat was on anyone's mind now.

“R-retreat, inform the other battalions!”

“Hm…”

Zhang Dong looked at the flaming ships that were falling down to the ground. They were exploding and burning up before him and the crews that were inside of them were fleeing. Perhaps it was a naive gesture but he didn’t feel like chasing after people that had already lost their will to fight was just.

‘I’ve also burned through a lot of Qi, chasing after them now could expose me to a surprise attack from more Saint Emperors.’

He glanced towards his right hand, there he saw a passed-out man with a bloody nose. It was one of the last remaining generals from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. The man was close to a late stage nascent soul master which at this point was nothing. This battle was won but it was not the end of the war, not in the long shot.

‘Not like I can capture them all or kill them for that matter.’

At first, Zhang Dong was deliberating on performing a large-scale attack and going all out. However, it was better to not show how strong he really was. The technology on the ships that these people had was unknown to him. Perhaps the Emerald Phoenix Emperor would see him fight and find some of his weak points. It was better not to give his enemies too much information about the limits of his spiritual energy or the techniques he uses.

“Well then, Sun Shi, Kang Yunru. I’ll leave the apprehension of the survivors to you, I propose capturing them first and interrogating them.”

While talking he held out the struggling man before him. His whole arm was around the Saint Emperor’s neck. The man was struggling but his body was disabled by Zhang Dong’s superior Qi. At this moment he was not stronger than a Qi condensation practitioner and putting some restraints on him wasn’t hard.

“T-the High-Generals will not stand for this, unhand me you…”

“Hoh? High-Generals? Are they your elite team of elders? Good, I like that you are willing to share information without the need for me to ask but I’ll leave you in the hands of specialists.”

“Huh?”

The man was stunned by the reaction and even more, as strange shackles of light started suppressing his body. They were wrapped around his limbs and also neck to cancel out most of his Qi. In this state, it was easy to throw him into the replica medallion that had now mostly become a prison for anyone he deemed worthy to question.

“We won?”

The hole he blocked didn’t even have time to be restored by the stunned members of the Heavenly Crane Sect. The battle was over before it even started by one man that was now slowly hovering back towards them. Some of them were stunned, others afraid while another group was giddy with anticipation. Almost everyone had heard about the Golden Dragon by this point but seeing the real thing before them couldn’t have prepared them for such a feat.

‘I guess most of them thought that the rumors were overblown, this should gain me some fame and make things easier in the future.’

His image in the west was already cemented in everyone's mind but here on the eastern front, he was still a new rising star. His sticks were now shooting through the roof after he had managed to single-handedly take out a large battalion of soldiers. Battle formations crumbled under his foot and almost all of the Saint Emperors had been taken out within a few hits. Thanks to this the low morale that everyone was radiating started shifting.

“L… Long Dong!”

“...Long live the Golden Dragon!”

“Golden Dragon!”

Soon after he made his way back behind the protective barrier he was greeted with cheers. The tired soldiers that had accepted their deaths were ecstatic. In their minds, he was now a symbol, a hero that couldn’t be stopped by normal means. Finally, there was now a chance at victory as this was actually the first stronghold that had managed to push back the assailants from the Emerald Phoenix Empire.

“Well, I’m glad that you are all in high spirits but this is only the start of this long journey.”
He spoke out in a gentle tone, his voice wasn’t loud and with the help of his cultivation, it was heard by everyone. The cheering stopped and all eyes were on him, there was no time for a grand speech but he needed to say a few words to these soldiers.

“This battle might have been won but the war is far from over. Don’t worry, you will have my full cooperation and I will protect all the other cities that are going through the same struggles.”

Things were handled here with no problem, the Saint Emperors that had invaded this side had been dealt with and were in shackles as well. With Sun Shi and Kang Yunru here this outpost would have enough manpower to even last through another siege. He could not stay here though, there were other forts that were being attacked just like this one. This was only the start but also a chance to deal a large blow to the enemy offensive.

“While I will depart to the other locations, elders Shi and Yunru will aid you in reinforcing the defensive formation.”

“Honored Golden Dragon?”

Sun Shi wanted to comment but Zhang Dong didn’t have time to look over everything. His gaze was on the system map and the next location that was being attacked was already a waypoint. He needed to be swift and the ship that they came with wouldn’t be fast enough.

“Don’t worry about me, I can take care of myself but you should probably try getting some reinforcements from the main sect, tell them about the enemy’s strengths and use one of those guys for information.”

He pointed towards one of the passed-out Saint Emperors that he took care of. There were five generals on a similar level and two were on this side. Another two were defeated by him on the other side with the third one fleeing when he saw that there was no chance of winning. When looking at the map he knew that the other forts would have to deal with similar amounts of enemies.

“Of course honored Golden Dragon but we shouldn’t be hasty. What if enemies that you can’t handle alone appear, it would be better if we waited a day and set off together to the next location.”

“Normally that would probably be the better option but I don’t think that your allies have that much time. This attack wasn’t the only one, the other ones might be slightly delayed but they will certainly go for the other strongholds that offer a good strategic foothold. I’ll see you later then!”

“Honored Golden Dragon!”

Sun Shi stretched out his hand but as he was calling out Zhang Dong’s body turned into a golden beam of light and shot up into the sky. After a large burst of energy, everyone there could see a golden lightning bolt traveling through those clouds in a direction one of the other strongholds was.

The people that were gathered here stood still without saying anything. They looked at the widespread destruction, corpses, and passed-out people. One man had just arrived and taken care of one of their problems in a matter of moments. Some of them were glad that it was over, others were angered that an outsider was needed for something like this and others saw this as a chance to further their ambitions. Nevertheless, they needed to get to work, and finally after Zhang Dong was gone Sun Shi shouted out to get a hold of this situation.

“Everyone, attend to the injured, the ones that are able shall reform the grand protective formation!”

Kang Yunru didn’t want to be shown up so he also started barking out his own orders as everyone got their butts moving.

“We must transport the defeated enemy generals to our prison, I will tend to their grandmasters that the Golden Dragon disabled for us!”

Zhang Dong wasn’t there to oversee things like this as he didn’t have time and didn’t want to babysit anyone. The people he was helping needed to pull their weight in one way or another, he couldn’t be everywhere and at this moment he was more concerned about gaining back his spiritual energy.

His exit was flashy as he needed to use his lightning form to travel faster through the electrical currents in the sky. This way of flying was a lot faster than using the Heavenly Crane Sect’s ship the Patriarch lent him. This of course eat into his reserves that had been lowered due to the quick pace of the fight against the Saint Emperors.

For a brief moment, he returned to his physical form to take out a large pouch filled with marble-sized pills. All of them made their way into his mouth before turning back to the previous energy form. Each one of these pills when consumed by a foundation establishment practitioner could push them through several small realms or even make them explode if they weren’t careful. For him on the other hand they didn’t even amount to one percent of his total Qi.

His ever-growing cultivation base was too much ahead of his pill-making skills. This he could only offset by volume as preparing these pills wasn’t that difficult through the factory mode in his crafting abode. Thus he rocketed back through the clouds to his next destination, with some luck he would get there before their protective formation fell apart.

‘This should give me some time, if they know that there are capable combatants on this side, even the Emerald Phoenix Emperor will think twice before launching another attack!’

Chapter 595

“Our new ally has been working hard, I knew he was strong but I wasn’t expecting him to be so proficient in battle tactics and warfare. Was this the last one?”

“Yes Patriarch, all of the invading armies have been forced to retreat and we managed to capture a large number of enemy combatants, they are being tight-lipped but with time we expect to reveal their true origin and what they are planning.”

“Mmm… good, what about our ‘friend’ the Golden Dragon?”

“After he defended the cities from the initial invasions he was seen going past our defensive land, it seems that he was either trying to scout out the areas that were claimed by the Phoenix Empire or…”

“Is he trying to single-handedly win this war? Perhaps his youthful appearance wasn’t just a trick… he might be inexperienced, how many elders can we spare to aid him?”

“Not that many, our people are having trouble mending the defensive formations that had been damaged during the enemy offensive, it will take us several weeks to mend them. Only then we can start assembling a punitive force to strike back!”

“But Patriarch, would that be wise? Our elders and juniors are tired. We wouldn’t have been able to defend ourselves without the Golden Dragon’s help, what if we suffer a defeat instead? Wouldn’t all the work go to waste?”

“Leader Zhong you bastard, even at this point you would curl up your tail and shiver in fear?”

“Leader Shen, this has nothing to do with fear, I am being logical, how could we offer our people on a platter to that Emerald Phoenix Empire? This is not the time to move yet, we need to interrogate the prisoners, find out about their strategic formations and what they want.”

“Leader Zhong isn’t wrong… we don’t have enough information, we should send in the spies first before making our move.”

“You…”

Sun Shen the Moon Lily faction leader along with the rest were in a meeting. All of them were discussing the situation at their borders and how Zhang Dong was affecting them. Ever since his first appearance, most of the enemy forces had been driven back. They had managed to capture some of their masters and weapons. These were in the process of being analyzed which complicated things.

Just like the last time the council was divided. One side wanted to use this opportunity and push into the regions that they had to give up to the Emerald Phoenix Empire. The other group on the other hand wanted to take this chance to wait. This had given them precious time and they would rather analyze the situation before going in further.

“If the Golden Dragon didn’t aid us and acted, then all of our border cities would have been overrun by now! This is not the time to wait but the time to act! Our enemies are scattered and will need time to evaluate the situation, if we strike they won’t be able to defend themselves!”

“Leader Shen brings up a good point but what if these forces were just a scouting party, what if we get decimated instead? Our cities are well fortified but we don’t have a strong attacking force!”

“But there is no time, we have to…”

The whole area erupted as the old masters continued to argue. It didn’t seem that they would be making any type of decision anytime soon. There was one person disappointed in this turn of events.

‘I guess I won’t be getting any more backup.’

Zhang Dong sat on a large tree branch while listening to the old men and women bickering with each other. It was another equal split between the ten factions as if his influence never mattered. Even when that fortune-telling faction was not neutral anymore, another one became opposite to it when the time to make another decision came. It was as if without him being there, it was impossible for them to make an important decision.

‘Could this be the world setting or an overseer at work? Could it only be possible for them to be moved whenever the Main Character was there?’

Zhang Dong couldn’t help himself from seeing game characteristics in the behavior of the people. He wasn’t sure but it was impossible to not become paranoid due to his knowledge of the people working in the background. There was a possibility of interference and when it came to games backup usually arrived when all was said and done. The same was true now as he wasn’t expecting to get any help unless he somehow made it true by his own power.

‘Hm, I’ve come this far, turning around now would make all that work go to waste, wished they listened to Sun Shen and trusted me more.’

Thanks to his system he could hear what the group were discussing. Sun Shen’s approval rating had been over sixty percent which allowed the use of spirit points. With them, he could hear the council discussing things even when being hundreds of thousands of kilometers away from their location. He was hoping for some backup but they were stalling their decision with continued bickering.

“But now that I’m here it would be bad to leave…”

He had come to the Heavenly Crane Sect not only to help out people but also to enhance his army. The area he was in once belonged to the Sun Lily faction which was known for its spirit metal mines. After making sure that the borders were safe he could with a clear conscience take his reward. If he liberated these lands then the Heavenly Crane Sect would probably try to lower the metal haul but with this place still being under the Emerald Phoenix Empire’s clutches, he had some wiggle room to take his cut.

“Hah… look at me becoming this greedy but I guess I can use these metals more than these people that can’t even make a decision to help their citizens, they clearly know that these people are ruthless.”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh while looking out into the distance. There he saw a smaller settlement that contained around thirty thousand people. What made them unique was that all of them were very weak. No martial artists above the Qi condensation level of three existed and he knew the reason for it.

‘The rumors were a bit overblown but they weren’t that far off…’

This was a true war, something a person from his previous world could mostly only read up in books or see on television. With his superior senses, he could sense it, a large gathering of corpses had been buried near his location, a mass grave.

‘They must have buried all the cultivators that lived here and then covered it up with soil…’

The job was sloppy and after some rain parts of the soil uncovered partially decomposing bodies. Some beasts that lived outside were already scavenging the remains and eating up whatever they could. The only good news here was that they didn’t outright murder the entire population. The non-combatants were spared and in the city, anyone that was weak was given some type of chance to survive.

There was nothing he could do about the situation here anymore. The people here had died a while back and there was no way of bringing them back. Now he had to focus on the problem at hand and the people that were still alive. They were left alone in the city with a few hundred cultivators from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. There weren’t that many but they were at least at the Martial Master level which was more than enough to handle these untrained Qi condensation commoners.

‘They killed anyone that could resist them and enslaved the population, they don’t see these people as human…’

Secret grounds and different pocket dimensions existed in this world. Many times they were rumored to be created by long-dead immortals and acted as trial grounds for the worthy. After capturing some of the people from the opposition at least this fact he did confirm.

‘Perhaps they think that this whole Azure Empire is just an elaborate test made by some powerful immortal millions of years ago, a special place to gain power every thousand of years ago.’

Immortals were like gods in the cultivation world. It wouldn’t be strange for the people living here to assume that they were capable of creating life or something very similar. Perhaps to them, this was nothing more than a facade, a battleground created for their people to gain power and show that they were worthy of claiming some kind of old relic.
‘If that is what they think then it will be hard to reason with them, they might take it as some kind of trial… do they believe that we are some automatons or something?’

Zhang Dong looked at the dead bodies in the badly covered grave but couldn’t see anything out of the ordinary. At least the people that were here weren’t tempered with and their bodies had regular injuries. Demonic cultivators liked using people's bodies as resources but these cultivators were more aligned with orthodox sects like his. They would probably not budge on the moral side either which left overwhelming them with superior might.

“Well then, I should probably make my move…”

If it was the old him he would probably charge into the city and rescue everyone. It wouldn’t be that hard, the strongest person here was only a Martial Saint. All the other powerful masters had retreated to evaluate the situation that he had caused at the border. There was a problem, even if he killed every cultivator there the people wouldn’t really have anything to go to. He would need to somehow transport them out of here or create something that could do it instead of him.

“You’ll have to wait a bit, but don’t worry, I’ll set you all free and you’ll be able to bury your people in peace.”

While the people were captured they were in no immediate danger. The enemies probably needed some slaves to keep the city running and to use it as some type of outpost. Instead of giving away that he was roaming these lands, he had a better idea.

‘If the people from the Heavenly Crane Sect won’t help me and if my own people are busy fighting with those fish people… I just need to make another force, I can’t be everywhere but if I have some backup…’

Further inside at the outskirts of the city there was one location that he was after. It was where a large mine that contained various spirit metals was located. There were many things that he could make with those materials and instead of creating weapons or armor for his troops he had another idea.

“If I don’t have soldiers, I’ll just make them…”

Chapter 596

‘They aren’t really defending it too well, I guess they don’t hold these metals in high regard, I think it has something to do with their cultivation…’

Zhang Dong had quickly moved towards a mining area previously owned by one of the sects in the Heavenly Crane Sect’s region. It looked like a giant gorge with a river running for hundreds of kilometers to the north. The cliffs were steep and looked like swiss cheese with all the holes that were mined out. Simple planks were infused to the sides and used as walkways but no paths led up.

‘Hm, I think they usually use slaves below the core formation level. They won’t be able to fly away and escape and those sharp rocks below are probably a death sentence…’

From what he could tell, the people working here were trapped. He could feel with his spirit sense that the tunnels were long but never led out anywhere. The only way of escaping would be on the side of the gorge where probably a core formation expert was guarding everyone.

This wasn’t anything out of the ordinary. Even his own sect utilized prisoners to work for them but the conditions on his side were a lot better. Sunlight was a very important part of a human’s life and even slaves needed to see the light of day from time to time.

‘Hm… the slaves have been moved and stopped mining? They are holding them at one location.’

After taking out a few guards that were almost asleep he made his way into one of the tunnels. When traveling a bit further he came out at what looked to be an old living quarter. There were beds made of straw there that looked more like they belonged to a tomb. They were carved out in walls like bunk beds and had very little room, sitting wouldn’t be an option and they were all stacked over each other.

‘Damn, people really lived here…’

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what he should feel about this. On one hand, these mining slaves usually consisted of killers and thieves. On the other hand, it wasn’t strange for some young master to just sentence someone to this fate for looking at them funny. It wouldn’t be strange if a large chunk of the people being forced to do this were just in the wrong place at the wrong time.

This reminded him of some of his earlier adventurers when he was up against the Dark Palm Sect. He had done a similar dive into a spirit stone mine and rescued the people held up there. Some of the people he rescued even made it into his sect while others scattered through the world.

“But why wouldn’t they want these, they aren’t the greatest but…”

He could see a few small pebbles made from spirit metal on the ground. These were almost everywhere and probably just minor samples that weren’t worth all that much. The one in his hand would probably at most be Mortal-grade items that a master craftsman could perfect. Further in the mine, he expected to find Earth-grade and even Heaven-grade materials. A craftsman like him would be able to boost them past what they could originally become and the same should be said for the enemy blacksmiths.

“Hm, wait a second, what if their Qi isn’t compatible with our metals?”

When thinking back to the fights that he had with these people he did notice that they were using weapons from a different kind of metal. To test out his theory he brought out one of the swords he took while fighting the invaders and compared it to one made from one of the metals from the Azure Empire side.

“It’s resonating differently to the usual Qi…”

The people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire did have their own spatial rings but he didn’t really go through them due to lack of time. Now when going over them he could feel that there was a difference, their swords could take in a lot more Qi than the ones he was used to.

“Hm… so this means that they get a boost from our Qi… but when it comes to the weapons they are harder to use because they require more Qi.”

It seemed that the metals that were in this empire didn’t go well with the variation of spirit energy from the other empire. It was as if they were operating at 50% of the usual output. Even when he counted on the boost the people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire received it was still worse. It wasn’t strange that they decided to abandon the mines as the metals were highly inefficient compared to their own resources.

“I wonder if it's similar for the pills and the herbs? But if they can absorb the spiritual energy at a rapid pace it might be detrimental to swallow too many at once…”

Consuming pills was a staple of the cultivation world. However there was always a limit of how much a body could take. If too much spiritual energy was consumed it could even mean death to the person using them. It wouldn’t be strange for the bodies of their bodies to not be able to take the concentration but they could also be able to work with less for more. Perhaps low-quality pills would work quite well which would make this a treasure trove when spiritual herbs were considered.

‘I guess more isn’t always better, at least they don’t care about the metal mines, this will be a lot easier and there is a lot of stuff here… I can start out here and create my own force while they are concentrating on other locations.’

He brought up the map of the eastern region. When he was at the Heavenly Crane Sect he had asked about locations of strategic points and ones of interest. The areas with all the mines the Sun Lily faction owned were really far away from places that cultivated spirit herbs. When taking the new information into account he realized that his plan could work before anyone realizes what he was up to.

‘I guess I should start, there aren’t that many guards here and neither at the city, they all should fit into the medallion but I might have to drop them off somewhere else later.’

After nodding to himself he vanished from the spot he was in. Luckily his senses and system allowed him to find every living being that was stuck in these tunnels. It had been created as a prison and would work against the people that had conquered it. They would not have any place to escape nor would anyone be able to hear their shouts.

Canceling out sounds wasn’t that difficult for someone like him so the guards he came across fell like flies. Within a couple of hours, almost every part of the mine had been cleared out with the exception of one area. His one had a high concentration of people in it and was heavily guarded compared to others. Yet, the strongest person here was a early stage Martial Saint.

“Hey…”

“Stop, hold your voice, did you forget what they did to the last person that spoke out?”

“I know… but did you notice?”

“Huh?”

A large group of people was sitting down in a circle. They had been forced into the middle by the invaders that for some reason just left them there. To them, it didn’t really matter who their new master was; the only thing they cared about was survival. They had been stuck in this place for weeks now and some had even died of starvation. Others that tried to go against their new captors were slain almost instantly which forced the rest to wait.

“Why is it so quiet?”

“Right? I don’t see any of the guards either. They usually leave at least one person in that corridor but I can’t see anyone…”

One of the malnourished slaves pointed towards one of the many corridors leading out of this place. They were kept here for a while with not many people guarding them but in their state, any one of the guards could have killed them all by themselves.

“It’s strange, they at least made some noise…”

The mining slaves were started to whisper to each other. Usually, they would hear some sounds, grunts, and other noises from the guards. Sometimes they would pass by this room that connected to many other corridors but now it had been half an hour and no one had come. It was as if they had disappeared but most of them were too afraid to confirm anything.

“Could someone have come to save us?”

“Why would anyone save us? We are just slaves.”
“Maybe this is a chance?”

“Chance my ass, they will kill us instantly if we move.”

“We are already as good as dead, they won’t even feed us.”

The slaves were already malnourished and the only thing keeping them alive was a shallow stream of water that allowed them to at least drink some water. Being cultivators they could last more than regular humans but in a week or two, all of them would be dead. It was a gamble, some hoped that their captors would require the mine to work and have a reason to keep them alive. Others on the other hand only saw survival if they managed to get out of this predicament and perhaps this would be the chance.

“W-wait… did you see that?”

Suddenly people saw a bright flash of light in one of the corridors. They could not hear any sounds but a strange silhouette appeared. It looked to belong to a person but no one was sure and their vision had already become affected by the darkness so they were practically blind.

“It..It’s coming here… be quiet…”

All of them started panicking, they had raised their voices and were probably heard by the person that was coming. The last time something like this happened one of them had been killed, their dead body that was missing a head was in the corner of this chamber and already decomposing.

It was dead silent but they could see the light getting closer. Usually they were used to hearing footprints but this time around it was only a bright light. Was it perhaps a master capable of flight that was coming to dispose of them in one fell swoop?

“Is this really it?”

“No, I don’t want to die…”

Some of them started sobbing and cursing about the fate that brought them here. They were sure that this strange phenomenon couldn’t be anything good. Soon a bright light that looked like a person had revealed itself. It was actually warm and filled out this damp room that they had been stuck in for almost a whole month. Perhaps it wouldn’t be so bad, if death felt like this then perhaps it was better to accept it. The pain was suddenly fading away, could they be dying at this moment while being struck by the master’s powerful attack?

“Hm, I don’t think I have enough room in the medallion, I’ll have to create a temporary portal to move you guys to a different location, give me a few minutes to set things up…”

Chapter 597

“Huh?”

“They look malnourished, quickly bring over the nutrient pills, and after they are done bring them to the cafeteria for some real food.”

“Yes sir!”

“Also dim the light, their eyes aren’t used to it, remember to follow the Patriarch’s instructions!.”

A group of people that looked like walking skeletons were slowly walking into a grass-filled field. In the middle, there was a large gate filled with blue luminescent energy through which these malnourished individuals were stepping through. On the other end, they were greeted by people dressed in white robes with some golden dragon embroilments.

Just half an hour ago they had been dying of starvation in a cold mine. Then a strange person appeared, they couldn’t really tell who he was due their sensitivity to light but the warm glow he gave out seemed to melt all the problems away. Within a matter of minutes everyone started feeling better and were then ordered to walk through the shiny blue light.

They were all cultivators once while their dantians had been damaged they could recover faster than a regular human. Their eyes were quickly adjusting to the blue sky above and the people around them. Some of them were sure that they were being moved to another location to get killed or used for something else. However the people here looked kind and orderly, they didn’t not harm them nor did they bully them like their previous captors.

“What is the Patriarch thinking, could these people be of use to us? They look like common mining slaves.”

“Junior, you are out of line.”

“Ack.”

A young member of the physician unit of the United Element sect got smacked in the back of the head. It was a girl that didn’t look older than fifteen in a gray robe that differed from the bright white ones the other seniors were wearing.

“S-senior Ai, please forgive this junior.”

“I better not catch you calling to question our Patriarch’s will, you’ll be peeling potatoes for the rest of the year!”

“N-no nothing but that.”

“Very well, now take the other juniors and prepare the accommodations for these refugees.”

The woman moved her hands behind her back and quickly flew away on her sword toward the people that were gathering in the middle. The young trainee grumbled but quickly moved to the part where the other helpers were gathering. They were just outer sect disciples and were tasked to tend to the slaves from the mine.

“Haha, you should keep quiet around senior sister Ai about the Patriarch, she has a long history with him and is also part of the original Zhang Clan, you must have a death wish.”

When arriving at the group the other juniors started chuckling among themselves. The young junior girl that got reprimanded started pouting and turning red out of embarrassment. She felt slightly wronged as she only asked a simple question. It was known that the Patriarch was wise but for a new sect member like her, helping people that were punished to work in a mine was strange. These miners were usually criminals and in her mind didn’t deserve the help that they were getting.

“But they are criminals, why should our great sect aid such people?”

“Are they criminals? You are naive.”

“What do you mean?”

“I’m not sure where you came from but it’s normal for the poor to be thrown to those mines for small crimes like stealing rice.”

The juniors continued to whisper while moving towards a large rectangular building. From the outside, it didn’t look like much but it had all the important facilities. It was a similar dorm building that had been used by the Zhang Clan to test their warriors. The design was simple and thanks to it, the buildings could be quickly made and were perfect for large numbers of refugees.

“I didn’t know... the Patriarch must have seen them and shown mercy, he is trouly a generous master!”

“Yes but this is probably not the only reason, these people have interacted with the enemies of our sect, I’m sure they will be grateful for our aid and give us all the information they can!”

“Ah, it’s like giving them a carrot while their lives were only ever filled with the stick?”

“Now you get it.”

“Hey you two, stop talking and get to work, I don’t want to be punished again for being slower than group C.”

The gray-robed junior helpers quickly started going through the rooms and making the beds. The rooms weren’t that big but they were able to fit three beds and some walking and sitting space. Compared to the cramped beds in the mines this was paradise.

“It’s the Patriarch!”

While everyone was busy doing their job a loud shout was heard from the area of the teleportation gate. Everyone that was in the building quickly clamored for the windows or to go outside. To them, the person called the Patriarch was a living legend, the strongest cultivator that was even rumored to eclipse the current Azure Emperor. They chose to believe the rumors as the number of victories under his belt was immeasurable and he never seemed to have lost a battle.

“Q-quickly we must go back, this is a chance!”

“But senior sister told us to prepare the rooms for the injured.”

“Who cares? It’s the Patriarch, we might not get another chance like this in our lifetime!”

The girls that made out the entirety of this small squadron of nurses didn’t know what to do. They had orders but their elusive leader was known for not showing his face out in the public often. Now he was at the teleportation gate they were near and it was a once-in-a-lifetime chance to see him from close up.

Even getting a whiff of that superior radiant Qi could help them push through a small cultivation realm, it was also a chance to have their role model see them in the open. Sometimes masters like him with a glance could tell someone's aptitude for things. There was a one in a trillion chance that they could become his disciple by just making their presence known and some would be willing to die for a chance like this.

“I… I’m going…”

“W-wait for me!”

Suddenly all the young juniors rushed out of the building and were followed by almost everyone that had gathered there. All of them rushed to the hill where the teleportation gate was to see their leader. Even the senior sect members were doing the same and when the juniors noticed this, all bets were off.

When the gray-robed juniors crossed over the hill they could see a mass of other people already kneeling down. They were in a large circle with their heads touching the gentle grass on the ground. They were momentarily stunned at the gallant appearance of their leader. Everyone had seen paintings, pictures, and even holograms of him but the aura he radiated could not be imitated by anything. It was as if a true immortal being descended from the heavens to grace them with his presence.

Instantly everyone that came dropped down to their knees to give him a proper welcome. They felt unworthy to look him in the eyes and felt like they did something bad by coming here. Only one person moved forward, her graceful form glided through the air before arriving before the man in question.

“Disciple pays respect to her master.”

Everyone wanted to rise their heads but no one below the level of the nascent soul had the gall to do it. Without the Patriarch giving them a clear order to raise up they weren’t allowed to. Anyone that was caught taking a sneak peek would be punished, perhaps even banished from the sect. No one was willing to go back to their old lives outside of this Spirit Spring City which was a paradise.

“Oh hey, good that you are here Xue, I need to unload a few prisoners, make sure that they go through the process just try not to break them. They are from the Emerald Phoenix Empire, I placed the cultivation-suppressing shackles on all of them, so even the elders that are on the nascent soul level shouldn’t give you a problem.”

The man’s voice sounded powerful but gentle and everyone held their breath in. To them, it was better to pass out instead of not being able to hear their leader’s words reach their ears in their full splendor. His quick speech was followed by a strange sound of something dropping on the ground. A strange energy was being produced that was akin to spatial techniques.

“Of course, Master.”

“Oh… and don’t tell her that I was here…”

“I will keep my lips sealed.”

In a matter of moments, the radiant presence that was there vanished, and the teleportation gate was closed. He was gone and finally, people started to raise their heads. They saw a large number of passed-out people wearing strange robes. Instantly they knew that they belonged to the new enemy in the east.

“So it was true, the Patriarch is working with the Heavenly Crane Sect?”

“But it hasn’t been long since, how could he apprehend so many?”

Not everyone was informed about the meeting in the east. They couldn’t let their enemies know what their leader was up to but now it was out. Some of the passed-out masters there seemed at the level of some of theirs. However, the chains around their bodies were hindering their Qi flow and rendering them as weak as Foundation Establishment practitioners.

“Hey, didn’t I tell you to prepare the rooms?”

“Forgive us senior sister but we had to greet the Patriarch…”

“... Fine, now get back to work!”

The group of juniors bowed and quickly returned to their work. Luckily their senior sister understood the glee in their eyes. They were finally in the presence of their glorious leader. The strong radiant aura that he was exuding was warm yet powerful. They wanted nothing more to go and cultivate while remembering that golden glow but first they needed to finish the order that was given to them.

…

“How did they get so many people there, that scared me…”

Zhang Dong removed the temporary teleportation gate and placed it back into his spatial ring. He had decided to return to his sect via it to dump off the prisoners he took captive during his travels. To his surprise, there were hundreds of his sect members there bowing their heads at him. Luckily he could quickly dump the prisoners onto his disciple before getting out of there.

“I guess time moves on and more people will be joining my sect, I can’t let them down…”

With newfound resolve, he delved back into the mine. There his plan of making a secondary force would finally begin…

Chapter 598

“Hm… does this look a bit too… creepy?”

Zhang Dong looked at a piece of paper on which he was drawing a face on. He was aiming for something calming yet powerful but the design that he came up with was giving him the creeps.

“I guess unless it looks fully human it’s going to have that uncanny part to it, maybe I should ditch the realistic idea. What if I just give it a face of a skeleton…”

When thinking about the next design he drew up a humanoid shape made of pure metallic bones. It was quite similar to an old movie series that kind of went downhill after the second movie. A group of automatons that looked like this would probably send a message but perhaps make his side seem like some demonic cult trying to take over the lands.

“Better not… I need something soothing to the eye, that won’t tarnish my good name.”

He pondered this topic, his image could be useful if he used it right. For the time being, people around the world viewed him as the brother of the Azure Emperor. The Golden Dragon was his title and his fame was made by saving others and acting like a hero. This view wasn’t fully cemented in the people’s hearts quite yet but it was possible to push it further.

“Quite the nefarious scheme I’m thinking about here but not like I actually have any underhanded motives besides setting the people free and stopping more deaths.”

His only wish was to get this bloody war over and then get ready to take on the Overseer and whoever was behind the creation of this world. There were some titles he had gained beside his golden dragon one. Some called him a spirit of light or the radiant one. This made him think about angels which could become the design for his new robotic army.

“An angelic army that helps people… sounds a little bit campy but it would work, even people in this world have prejudices. They will be more inclined to trust something that looks like an angel than a demon.”

There were no angels in this culture per se, they were replaced by bald men called buddhas and saints. They were seen as people with good karma that did good deeds. However, not every one of them was good. There were ways to interpret good deeds for everyone and most of the time a person didn’t perceive themselves as evil. There were always ways of justifying acts of violence so this area was muddled.

“Would a more feminine or masculine one be better? They don’t need to all be the same, I could relegate them to a few roles.”

Zhang Dong felt inspired and took some of it from some old games he used to play. First would be the warrior angels. They would possess bulkier armor and carry various armaments. A shield and a sword combo would probably be the best combination but he was also planning to give some of them spears or glaves.

Then the thinner variants would wear hoods to cover their faces and be relegated to the background support. He was making puppet automatons made out of metal so healing wouldn’t work but this didn’t mean that they wouldn’t be able to use these energies to heal humans. Instead, they would pelt everyone with a myriad of radiant long-range spells as he was not limited to only cultivation techniques.

One type was the melee brawlers that fought at close range, the other long-range glass cannons for support. Then there would be the last type, the leaders. These he gave a combination of both, bulkier armor with hoods over their heads, and instead of angel wings made of feathers they would be made out of energy.

These were more for show and to signal that his army was coming. The wings would be able to take the form of the traditional bird ones, they would just be made out of golden energy. But they could also look like a large cape or squiggly energy beams that fluttered while the leader angel moved. It would look like a mass of golden lightning was wiggling around their backs and even a way of attacking people.

“Hm… I might have gotten a bit carried away with these…”

It didn’t take long but he made a lot of designs, too many to actually create. There wasn’t much time for his creations to prosper and there were many more mines to get to like the one that he took over. Thus for the time being he decided to go with some of the slicker designs, the warrior would look like a fantasy hero with a centurion-like helmet that was on fire. There would be no face under the helmet as it was part of the automaton puppet.

The mage type would have its face covered by a white hood made of softer spirit metal. The flames of gold would be coming out of the shoulders instead of the head. Then the leader type would be a combination with wings of light shooting out of the back. Later he was planning to give the other leader types a more intricate design but for the alpha version, this would do.

‘Luckily this crafting abode makes things very easy, I just need to alter some of the old designs that I’ve already used and it will do most of it for me.’

While his crafting abode had been reset to its bare bones settings, thanks to the spirit point farm it was back in full swing. He just used some old designs and the knowledge he had from making power armor for himself and his friends. Within a day of scribbling around, he had the two common base models that were quickly shifted into production.

‘This holographic testing rig is really helpful, I don’t even need to make prototypes and can just let the factory build them in bulk.’

His system was inferior to Wang Longs in a sense of gathering points and getting new techniques, yet when his faction system and making treasures were involved it was actually superior. A system was in place to produce various tests on the automatons. After making the first design and running the test through the Ai he could see all the weak points. It was easy to correct the joints and armor plates to fit his wants and needs.

‘Good, this will do… making variants that are better at taking hits or more speedy with these prototypes is quite easy.’

The warriors that were supposed to be bulk models could be customized. Ones with shields could be made more robust while the ones that used spears faster on their feet. The mages were less resistant to stress but they could hold bigger batteries to fuel their magic techniques. Now he only needed to throw in the mined minerals and spirit stones to create his army.

‘Well then, off to the next mine.’

Thus his quest continued, before his army was built he needed materials. His crafting abode continued to produce soldiers while he sneaked up to the next mine. The slaves that had not been killed were freed and their captors dealt with them. With the influx in materials, he could let his factory do all the work while he concentrated on things outside.

‘I guess, it’s time to test them before my location becomes known to everyone.’

“What should I call you? The Heavenly Revolutionary Army?”

Behind him stood a swarm of floating puppets. They combined the knowledge that he attained in this world and in the magical one. There he worked on large robots and smaller ones which made this task a lot easier. The biggest problem was supplying energy to these flying weapons.

For this, he decided to create support structures that looked like flying triangles. They would send out waves of energy that when absorbed by the machines would power them. It was similar to modern-day charging and allowed to reduce the risks of the metallic puppets exploding from their batteries being overcharged. The only problem was that this was a weak point of his entire army, if the flying pyramid was disabled then a whole battalion of soldiers would not have any energy.

“I’ll have to live with this, as long as I’m here then the structure is well protected, I just need to get the ball rolling the more resources I get the more of these power pyramids I can make…”

Starting out things was always the hardest. At the moment he was aiming for locations with spirit stone mines and metals that were less defended than the ones with spirit herbs. In reality, the large forces were mostly meant as a distraction to focus the attention away from the leader, which was him. If he scattered the enemies, even if his armies continued to lose as long as he took out the Saint Emperors and stole their weapons to act as a base for his leader puppets, everything would be fine.

‘There they go… let's see if that Leader Angle can take out those Supreme Saints.’

This time around he would be helping out his newly made army of automatons. He was wearing similar armor to the leader angel but hanging out in the back on top of a floating pyramid made of precious metals. It looked as if it was made from gold and inside it had a large scrape generator that was feeding a large quantity of spiritual energy into his puppets.

“Fear not, the Heavenly Revolutionary Army has arrived, we will drive out the invaders and bring divine wrath upon them!”

‘That is a bit embarrassing…’

The leading angel was holding a long spear which was a heavenly-grade weapon made by Zhang Dong. The mechanical warriors had a few pre-recorded messages but were mostly controlled by this AI helper Bob. Each puppet had a compact version of the Ai integrated into its control module. It allowed them to fight and make judgments faster than most cultivators in this world.

This army was divided into smaller battalions of around 300 units. Each of them had a mini-leader that could coordinate with them and order them to perform battle formations and tasks. Above them were the true leaders that controlled these battalions and made the real decisions. If a mini-leader was destroyed the battalion wouldn’t falter as its program could be uploaded to one of the existing units. It was like a hydra, even when a head was cut off another one grew in its place.

Finally, the clash between the invaders and the mechanical bearings commenced. This would be the final test and decide if he could actually push further into the defensive line of the Emerald Phoenix empire or if retreat was a better option.

‘After I’m done with this, I should see about that backup plan, I should make them work a lot harder for this one.’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 599

“Master General, there is a situation!”

“What is it now? Can’t you fools handle a few weak cultivators without the main force getting involved?”

A group of men was sitting inside a large tent and looking over a large map. On the map there were pieces representing various locations, structures, and even armies. It was a war map created to document their progress and also for making strategies. Not that long ago their first failure had transpired as they weren’t able to push into the middle of the enemy defensive line as they had planned.

“What is it this time? A mysterious master on the level of the Emperor Appeared again? You already know what happened to the last group who spouted those lies.”

The man that entered was a high-ranking officer that was close to a general. There were five other people at around his level inside this tent all capable of dislodging his head if they wanted to. The leaders that retreated with their tales between their legs had been punished by getting their cultivation destroyed. They were then tossed out to wander through the wilderness and probably eaten up by the many beasts that roamed these lands. Retreat and failure was not allowed in this army and everyone was quickly becoming aware of it.

“This better be good.”

“Y-yes Master General, I’m here to make a report, our first defensive line has been attacked and we have lost some of the previously captured cities and strongholds…”

“We have lost our strongholds? Which ones?”

The man doing the report started to sweat but he had to continue. Even though he was scared of the people gathered here, if he didn’t do his job it was the same as signing a death sentence. Even these Saint Emperors that were at the pinnacle of power would be crushed under the Emperor’s foot if they failed.

Everyone had the incentive to win and conquer these lands. Back at the Emerald Phoenix Empire, there were many other warriors waiting to replace these that couldn’t take this chance and advance. Even spending a few days in this spirit energy rich environment could allow a person to break through a small realm. Everyone wanted to step into this region but there was a limited amount of space on which the Emperor decided on.

“The attacks started slowly, an unimportant outpost had been wiped clean by an unknown army of strange beings. They called themselves The Heavenly Revolutionary Army and were led by a strange powerful being calling themselves, Archangel Michael.”

“Archangel Michael?”

“Yes Master General, not much is known about this person just that they are capable of overwhelming even our Saint Emperor generals. Their forces started out small but with each passing day the number had been increasing, they have been targeting the metal mines that we had control of and we are sure that they will continue doing so.”

“They are after the mines? What of the spirit herbs?”

“They didn’t seem to be interested in them yet, however, we don’t know what they will do after securing all the mines.”

“Hm… Is that all?”

“No Master General, another force from the south has started pushing. It’s the people wearing golden armor, who had suddenly become active again we believe that they have something in common with this Archangel Michael as both sides use divine arts.”

“Hmm… first the Golden Dragon, now some Archangel… Do they take us for weak fools? I have made my decision, the High Generals will act, we can’t allow these people to embarrass us any longer, we will take care of them and make way for our Emperor.”

“For the Emperor!”

The man stood up from his throne-like seat and grabbed a large glave from the side. His physique was comparable to the demi-human emperor with muscles upon muscles. The other Saint Emperor generals followed after him while taking out their own weapon of choice. There was no way that they would let this stand, if their army failed then they would be the ones to pay the price. To take care of things without issue the decision was made, they would take on the unidentified force themselves and nip it at the bud before it became a real problem.

…

“Hm, It seems to be going well, this is the last mine in the area and the others are just small ones. What do you think Michael, should we change our target for now or just continue?”

“Enemy forces are approaching, this unit proposes a defensive measure.”

“Is that so? Well, at least we forced them to split them up, Lucius and Argus better work for that Aegis shield. The bulk of their forces is coming here though, they probably don’t want me near those spirit herb gardens they had taken over.”

Zhang Dong looked at his map and could see a blob of red moving toward the northern parts of the eastern region where he was. A smaller group that looked like a red fog was going to the southern parts where Argus and the magical knights were attacking. He was using the fact that he had found another object they wanted, the magical holy shield. For it they would do almost anything, even attack the Emerald Phoenix Empire to lure some potential threats away.

This allowed him to take some heat from his new army which continued to quickly grow in numbers. Once his factory inside of his crafting abode ramped up in production it was easy to create his automatons. The regular units were mostly at the core formation level but just like their human counterparts, they could combine their power into formations.

“The only limitation is the power required to run them, this is the limit for now but… there is a way to expand this limit but the time isn’t right yet and I think we also have some guests.”

The flying puppets that were exuding radiant light turned in the direction of the incoming armies. Zhang Dong retreated inside the largest floating pyramid to act as the main source of power for these automatons. The army had become so big that he wouldn’t be able to control them otherwise. While inside he could monitor what they were doing and see if they were capable of defeating a large force made up of multiple Saint Emperors and quite a high number of Supreme Saints.

“Well, I’m not really controlling them, Bob is doing all of the heavy lifts, if I tried I think my brain would overheat.”

It was possible for a cultivator to control battle puppets like these. The more intricate the design of these automatons was, the more varied orders they could react to. Usually, they were only meant for battle and reacted to things like ‘attack’ or ‘protect’. However, with the help of his Ai, this could be taken to another level as a large number of them could coordinate with each other. In a sense, they could move like a trained army and carry out all sorts of battle tactics.

Then there was one of the greatest strengths of this robotic army. It knew no fear and didn’t question any of the creator's choices. Even if the plan required some to get destroyed they wouldn’t care. Their destroyed bodies could even be recycled or restored if it was possible. If half of them were destroyed in a victorious battle part of the puppets could be made whole again and their programming would continue to evolve. With each battle they would be able to read into the enemy formations more and react faster, this was the true power of this autonomous army.

“I might have created a monster if I use the Dolden Dong Palace as a source of energy and grab some other resources, this might become an easy victory…”

The battle had started and the swarm of puppets attacked the cultivators from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. Bob his Ai program had existed for a while and it was given a lot of battle dates through their travels. All of this data made it into the machines that he made and they were quite proficient at copying his fighting style. Even if they were a lot weaker then the original, the numbers made up for a lot. The bodies that would make body refiners jealous were also an added boon.

“What are these things?”

“T-there is nothing inside, these are battle puppets!”

Emerald Phoenix Warriors were being tossed around by the angelic army. However, some of them were also being destroyed and quickly it became apparent that they were some kind of automatons. After ripping out their heads the lack of flesh became apparent. The bodies looked bulkier on the outside but a lot of hollow areas existed inside. A slicked-jointed skeleton more similar to the usual wooden puppets was inside the armored suit that protected the automatons from harm.

“They must be being controlled by someone or something, find it!”

One of the generals shouted out while slicing up over ten of the warrior-type puppets with one swing of his large glave. Even when the swarm continued to come at him they were only turned to scrap metal. However to the man’s surprise, there was some suspicious movement, some of the automatons moved in to catch the destroyed bodies of their allies and flew off toward the large floating pyramids.

“What are they doing…”

He could see the large structures floating in the background. They were generating protective barriers that weren’t easily breached. Even their large ships and Saint Emperors that were trying to get through couldn’t. The damaged puppets were carried in through an entrance that opened and then from another one the man could see new metallic enemies emerging.

“Could they be…”

“Hm, did he figure it out with just one glance? Not bad, it would be better to get rid of someone like that…”

Zhang Dong witnessed everything while looking over this battle. He focused on who looked to be the commanding officer and with the help of the system could hear what he was talking about. In reality, the insides of these pyramids had been turned into puppet factories. The damaged bodies could be almost instantly melted down for resources and new models were assembled in their place. The loss of materials was high but thanks to this the army could maintain a high number of active units at all times.

‘They are already trying to break through the barricades, he is even willing to sacrifice his men to destroy the factories, I can’t let him do that… I guess it’s time.’

“Michael, you are up, go get rid of the enemy commander.”

The leader unit that he spent a lot of time designing released a radiant glow from its back. A golden aurora filled the whole area as a large set of golden wings appeared. In the middle, a warrior made of golden alloy appeared with a huge sword in its hand. The power it was exuding was at the level of a nascent soul master at the great circle realm and it was ready to chop its target up.

Chapter 600

“How can this puppet be so strong…”

“You shall be purified!”

“And why is it repeating the same five words constantly?”

“The light will bring everlasting peace to this world.”

‘Hm… didn’t have time to design the speech pattern too well, putting in those one-liners might have been a mistake…’

Zhang Dong watched as his ‘Archangel’ leader unit battled the enemy general. It was equipped with a pocket version of the Bob Ai and was capable of understanding almost everything but when the words that it was spewing had been pre-recorded. During battle, all speaking functions were limited and all resources shifted to the puppet's battle mode. Conserving energy and processing power was paramount to victory and for that reason, it just continued to spew out a few one-liners, like a boss in a video game.

‘The leader is around the level of a tribe leader from the demi-human empire, I guess all these empires have a similar level of power, the only ones that were different were Argus’ group…’

The battle was in full swing and his puppets were battling it out with the large force from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. His allies were down in the south but this time around they were alone. They had a small elite force of fighters but there weren’t that many of them. Considering that all the other Empire’s had Emperor class leaders on their side, the people from the magical kingdom were a bit strange.

‘They kept their kingdom rather vague, would they only send help if this party failed?’

Argus and his knights would not be able to take on the Emerald Phoenix Empire by themselves. They were a bit stronger than the group that he was fighting here but with a couple more Saint Emperors, even the golden armors would start giving out. He could only attribute it to their forces not fully committing to this side. Probably after acquiring one item, they also didn’t see the need to ask for reinforcements.

‘It’s not strange to see this type of setting, only when the miniboss is destroyed will the real boss appear.’

Just like all the other Empires, the one Argus came from also had a leader. They had a king instead of an Emperor but he could be on the level of the demi-human leader as well. Other than that, they could have some other powerful warriors on the level of Lord Lucius. If there were ten at his level, even Zhang Dong wouldn’t be able to win. Before he was having trouble with one Lucius and his squadron of golden warriors, if they increased in number, they would be a formidable force to be reckoned with.

‘I wonder if they will notice something, I did take inspiration from their armors.’

He had captured some of the silver knights and after working with Argus he had ample time to scan the golden armors. They wouldn’t let him borrow any but he had captured the silver variants and could somewhat understand the principle they worked with. Now his new creation was in the process of getting pushed back by the enemy commander.

‘I guess it needs some more juice or battle data…’

It was obvious that his Archangel Michael was a powerful creation but it could not fully contend with a Saint Emperor at the pinnacle of their power. The man was a general that had probably spent hundreds of years mastering his craft, a machine that was made within a week and had no hopes of beating him. At least not at this moment when it was still in the process of figuring out how to utilize its armaments. Even the best Ai needed time to process the information it was given and this was the first time it faced off against a Saint Emperor like this.

‘I guess, I’ll have to go in instead.’

Zhang Dong, who had been previously stuck in the main floating pyramid decide to make an appearance. A thick golden ray of golden light exploded upwards and pushed the clouds to the side. From within he appeared and was already dressed in his own power armor that he used to battle against Wang Long.

“Leave these lands!”

The enemy cultivators shuddered under the pressure, they instantly knew that the being in the golden armor was not something they could handle. However, retreating was not an option. Instead, all of the generals started moving toward each other, in their minds if all of them added their power, victory was possible.

“Everyone, we need to work together, for the Emperor!”

All of the generals shouted while gathering. They assumed an attacking formation that caused their spiritual energy to skyrocket. Together with who they called Master General, there were six Saint Emperors in total. Their eyes were flaming with passion and their muscles twitching with anticipation. They knew that the person floating in the sky was the real enemy and if they managed to kill him, then everything would be over.

“I see, you do not wish to leave nor do you wish to surrender, how do those guys always say it? Ah right… KNOW YOUR PLACE!”

He acted like a villain while his spiritual energy rose. His approach was faster than a bolt of lightning and only after the collision occurred did a thunderous roar echo through the battlefield. The formation that these six were so proud of couldn’t last through a single hit and some of them even retreated while spitting out blood.

At this point in time, Zhang Dong had already advanced past what the normal denizens of this world should be capable of. After defeating Wang Long for a moment he had taken a glimpse at the realm beyond realms. And even if his foot was not in the door quite yet, he got to peek through the hole which allowed him to dominate this battle.

The six Saint Emperors didn’t know what hit them as they got tossed around like rag dolls by this blur of golden light. Before they could muster enough spiritual energy for a counterattack, they were already flying through the air. There was no time to form a strategy or to examine the attack pattern Zhang Dong was going for, they couldn't only protect their vital points while turtling up.

“The generals can’t do anything?”

“Watch out!”

“Argh!”

One of the Supreme Saints that was glancing at the battle taking place, screamed out in pain. While his attention was pulled away for a moment, the golden puppets resumed their attack. The pyramids in the background kept pushing out more models as the battle continued. Their greatest warriors were getting tossed around like little children and couldn’t aid them anymore, this meant that the army composed of cold automatons could have free reign now, even the Archangel that was close in power to a general, was now keeping them busy.

After the golden one entered the fray, the battle quickly shifted. The Heavenly Revolution Army had clearly started winning and the forces from the Emerald Phoenix Empire were faltering. Soon enough, the morale wavered and some of them started backing off. Without the generals there to stop them, some of them prioritized their lives over the mission. Perhaps they would be seen as traitors but they had better chances of surviving if they ran.

“What are you doing, keep fighting!”

One of the Supreme Saints shouted while punching the hard skull of an automaton. The hit dislodged its head but didn’t stop the puppet from moving as it grabbed the man’s arm. While clinging to it, another three automatons approached with long spears to plunge them into the cultivator’s back. His death only cemented the decisions made by the retreating warriors, the battle was over and they had to abandon it.

‘I guess loyalty gained by might only amounts to this much, they still have around half of their forces left, they could make a stand and potentially turn it around.’

Zhang Dong was holding onto the head of the Master General. It was a bloody pulp that he had a hand in. The people on the other end didn’t realize that they weren’t doing that badly. The puppets he made wouldn’t be able to keep up their numbers for too long. During the process of re-assembly, they were losing a lot of energy and it wouldn’t last forever. As he saw it, there was a possibility to win this but a price would need to be paid for it.

For a moment he felt bad for these people. They were only here for shallow reasons like gaining power and prestige. Some of them were probably forced by their upbringing to believe that the biggest first was always right. The fear of getting punished and greed was the only driving force in this expedition of theirs.

‘It crumbles this easily, huh?’

He looked at the grown men fleeing in panic and not even looking if they could save anyone. There were some people getting manhandled by the puppets but they were just ignored to aid the others to escape. It was clear that the Emerald Phoenix Empire was very similar to the one here. Most of the clans and sects would act in a similar fashion as the survival of their line was more important than people below them. The moment their powerbase crumbled these prideful cultivators crumbled instantly.

‘What would happen if my people saw me lose?’

Zhang Dong was curious, it was close during the Wang Long encounter where his allies aided him in his battle. However, would they continue to fight and even stay in the same sect if he was finally vanquished by someone? He did not know but he had to assume that it would be a mixed response. While part of his sect had a fanatical view of him, others were milder in their beliefs.

‘I guess it will be better to never lose and find out.’

The defeated Master General was tossed into the medallion with the other five that he knocked out. Some of them were missing limbs and had crushed bones but were all alive. He would use this group of officers to find out the truth behind the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and his true motive.

“Everyone stop pursuing, gather up the destroyed units and everything that could be useful.”

His army of automatons started chasing after the fleeing cultivators but instantly stopped when the order was given. The second weakness of this army was the range, without the slow-moving pyramids around them, they would quickly lose power and most of their fighting potential. Even if he wanted to capture all the capable fighters from the enemies, he couldn’t.

‘This will probably be the last time they underestimate me… I should probably get what I can and return to the Heavenly Crane Sect, now perhaps I’ll be able to make them move.’

Chapter 601

“This is…”

“It’s one of the high-ranking generals of your opposition, the Emerald Phoenix Empire. He was in the inner circle so he should know a thing or two if you can make him talk. I have chosen to keep the leader of that army for myself though.”

“Release me you damn… ARGHHHh!?”

“Sorry, they are a little feisty, they still don’t understand how they could have been defeated.”

Zhang Dong zapped one of the generals that were together with the Master General from the Emerald Phoenix Empire forces. After clearing up the mining areas he decided to retreat back into the Heavenly Crane Sect lands where he left Sun Shi and Kang Yunru behind. The two were quite stunned to see a powerful cultivator like this be treated like a fly.

“Don’t worry, he is wearing bindings that are able to suppress his cultivation, I have produced a few of them.”

“Honorable Golden Dragon I’m not sure what to…”

“Haha, no need to thank me, just take them as a gift but I’m sure you understand that I’m not doing these tasks for free.”

“Of course not, I’m sure the faction leaders will prepare a proper reward for your help.”

“That’s the thing, I don’t want any treasures, I want something different. I’ll be short, take this man and the ones you already captured, and make them talk. I’m sure your leaders will get the bigger picture then and send some reinforcements here before time runs out.”

“This is?”

“Some presents, give the letter to your Patriarch and have him send forces over already, you probably don’t want someone like me roaming your lands.”

“That is…”

After tossing a spatial ring filled with specialized chains and reworked slave collars he decided to part ways with these two elders from the Heavenly Crane Sect. He was somewhat convinced that with these gifts the sect would finally decide to make a move. They had been on the retreat for mostly one reason, uncertainty, and fear of losing their main base.

Now, on the other hand, Zhang Dong had presented them with war prisoners that they could poke for information. The strong enemy from yesterday had been turned into a docile little puppy. He had done one thing and shown that these Emerald Phoenix Empire generals weren’t that scary. This would give the sect the push forward that they needed, it would convince them that they could win even if they send out some of their stronger masters into battle.

Cultivators were skeptical individuals and the longer they lived the more pedantic about their own safety they became. They would certainly not move without having a good reason for it. Now with the enemy on the retreat, it was time to reclaim their lost lands. It also made them look bad that a cultivator from a different sect was the one liberating their cities. If this continued it would make them look weak and unable to handle their own lands and that was not something these old farts could stomach.

‘If they don’t send troops now, they will take a hit to their face, their pride is always the thing that makes them move. While they get their things sorted out, I need to contact my other friends’

While his robotic army was patrolling the lands he needed to make a detour down south. They had numbers but lacked some power when it came to the higher-ups. The Archangels couldn’t compete with someone like the Master General but he knew someone that could. If he could get his other allies to bolster his angelic army then things would go much smoother.

‘Wish they were part of my own faction so I could just teleport to them…’

Zhang Dong brought up the map of the entire empire. Thanks to his system he could set up several save points but these were also limited. At one point he could have at most ten of them. Luckily thanks to his faction system he could use his people as teleportation hotspots and place the ten limited ones at several strategic locations.

One of them, for instance, was still at the Azure Palace, if he ever needed to sneak in then he would probably be able to. However, at that location, the Overseer had her base. It wouldn’t be strange if she had some way of tracking his movement. Thus it was something he needed to be careful of as he wasn’t sure what his next run-in with that woman would foretell.

‘I guess this is the closest to their base, I never actually visited their main headquarters, so this will probably be a good time to do this…’

Previously when interacting with the magical knights they met up at outside locations. Either it was some kind of small bastion built up by their workers or out in the open field. They were given a pass to travel through some of the United Element Sect teleport gates but were still seen as outsiders by most of the cultivation world.

He had left one teleportation point at the old location where he ran into Argus the first time around. It was quite surprising to see actual magic in this world and he was also discovered by it. Now when he appeared here there was nothing much but deserted buildings and overgrown grass.

‘I should probably give them a heads up, knowing Lucius he will think that I’m here to attack them or something.’

While Argus the Wizard was on his side the blond-haired Knight Commander wasn’t fully a fan yet. This showed that he was the right leader for the job, for this mission to succeed he needed to keep people at arm's length. There was no telling when a betrayal could occur and these unknown lands could quickly become their grave if they weren’t careful. They could not be sure that Zhang Dong wouldn’t betray them in the end.

However currently, they were allies and the sword was gained thanks to his involvement. Even if they didn’t trust him, he was their best chance of finding the other secret relic which he already did. Previously the same thing happened but this time around he didn’t want to beat around the bush. He would not lie about already having the item they desired but instead just use it as a proper bargaining chip.

‘There, message sent… I wonder if they’ll actually let me into their base, probably not but perhaps their mission is more important to them.’

With his plan in mind, he turned into an arch of golden light in the sky. His traveling speed was tremendous but it would still take at least a full day of flying through the air to get to their base. Not much was known about this fortress but from the rumors and his spies, he knew that it could be seen from far away. Thus with his enhanced senses he was able to see a giant structure that reached up to the skies even before arriving at the location.

‘Is that a giant tower?... it looks like a giant sword.’

Was it a sword-shaped tower or a giant sword that was turned into one, he wasn’t sure. However, before he would be able to examine it further he was intercepted by a group of knights. Lucius was not among them but instead, two of the other golden knights he once beat up were there. The rest was a full battalion of silver soldiers that were mostly around the core formation level.

‘Hm… I guess they are here to either guide me inside or keep me from going in?’

From his perspective, these people were probably not here to stop them. The two golden knights were at the level of nascent soul experts but they wouldn’t last a minute if he decided to attack them. They were more than likely here to either guide him inside or stall him until Argus or Lucius actually got here.

“Is Argus and Lucius not here, I’m sure I gave your Wizard the message.”

“Lord Lucius is awaiting your arrival, he has ordered us to guide Lord Dong to the Holy Citadel.”

“Hoh? He did, well then, guide me.”

To his surprise, they were actually willing to welcome him inside their stronghold. He was more inclined to believe that they would stall him but perhaps his visit would be short-lived or happen outside of those large walls. Zhang Dong also didn’t fully trust these people, it seemed that they were doing some heroic quest but it wouldn’t be strange if something unsavory came to light at the end. Perhaps they were the true end boss of this entire four-way war.

‘Well, this will be a good chance to confirm all of this. Bob, be sure to scan everything you can see, they are our allies for now but better to be safe than sorry later.’

While he didn’t go through many betrayals, for now, he knew that even people from his own faction would turn on him if he was gone for too long. It wouldn’t be strange if Lucius had a different reason for letting him enter his domain. He needed to be ready for any signs of betrayal and he was also sure to leave the item they desired in a safe location.

“That’s quite the city you build up here…”

The knights didn’t answer as they approached the giant tower that looked like a sword with its hilt stuck in the ground. The blade went all the way up into the sky and pierced the clouds. It was quite the sight as the same clouds up in the sky looked like they were being parted by this sharp blade made of stone.

‘I don’t remember any mentions of such structures in this location before this war started and it looks like the ground around here had shifted, it might have been buried underground and waiting for them to arrive.’

It wasn’t hard for him to spot the tossed-up soil, they had covered up their tracks but for an expert of his caliber, it was child's play. The large sword wasn’t the only thing here as a massive wall stood before him. It went around the sword tower in an almost perfect circular shape and was manned by many archers and siege weapons. Behind it, he could see some buildings that looked like they belonged in 14th-century Europe.

‘I can sense Argus coming, I hope this goes well.’

His wizardly friend was on the way, perhaps with him around he could figure out what these people were truly after and if he should be worried. Nevertheless, he needed to barter for their help and take care of the Emerald Phoenix Empire before more time was lost.

Chapter 602

‘It’s similar to a defensive formation but entirely made out of mana, must be Argus’ handiwork. I don’t think anyone besides me would be able to make it through this barrier without forcing it.’

Zhang Dong was inspecting the mana structure that surrounded the whole area. While the walls were high they could not halt anyone that was capable of flying. For this purpose, large barriers were always created to protect large settlements like this from all sides. This one was quite powerful as he could see himself having trouble blasting his way through. It would probably take a few battleships focusing their beams in one spot to leave and make a small opening for people to slip through. The time required and the energy expenditure would be tremendous.

He had made it past the wall where he saw something that looked like a medieval city. Luckily there were no farm animals walking around and no excrement was on the side of the street. At first glance, he noticed something off, while the city was quite large there weren’t that many people living here. It was as if they didn’t have enough manpower to fully use this place.

‘Hm, was my assumption correct?’

Previously he assumed that perhaps due to his involvement he changed the setting slightly. The golden knights when counter together weren’t all that strong compared to the enemy empires. Lucius and Argus would not have been able to defeat the demi-human emperor even if they combined their strength with some of the other golden knights. This side just didn’t have that emperor-level unit and the reason was probably that they discovered the secret blade with limited help.

‘It wouldn’t be strange for someone stronger to arrive after they start failing, the same thing happened to the demi-humans. The Emperor only showed up after several of their tribe leaders were killed.’

Perhaps Lucius and Argus weren’t the strongest but they still could put up a fight against the Saint Emperors. Luring in a stronger knight commander than Lucius also had drawbacks. The blond man was already stubborn enough, Zhang Dong could only imagine how prideful someone in a higher position could be. Then someone that was on an emperor-level could turn their fangs against him, it was probably better to work with these two.

‘Better to have weaker allies than stronger enemies.’

“Greetings Lord Dong.”

“Salutations to you Argus, did your beard get longer?”

Finally, someone that he knew appeared, and as always it was the wizard that greeted him first. Lucius was probably busy with some other stuff and still trying to act cool and collected.

“So then, I’m sure you got my message, I wanted to present it here as I was in the area…”

“Of course but… have you truly found the sacred aegis?”

“It should be it, it gave me the same impression as that sacred blade and it reacted to my holy energy in the same fashion.”

“It reacted? Do you actually have it with you?”

Argus’ old eyes lit up with excitement as it was revealed to him that the item they were looking for could be right here. Zhang Dong would have to disappoint the old man as he had no intention of handing it over just yet. This time around he didn’t want to beat around the bush. Perhaps it would be possible to toss it out after defeating the Emerald Phoenix Emperor for them to find but these were his allies, he wanted to give them the benefit of the doubt and just bargain with them instead.

“No, I don’t have it on me; however, your secret relic is in my possession just at a more secure location.”

“It is? This is grand news! , we must tell it to Lord Lucius and gather the knight order, this… this!”

“Now hold on there, I didn’t say that I would just hand it over now did I? But it would probably be better to not discuss this matter here right?”

“... Yes, we should change locations please follow me.”

Argus was stunned for a moment but quickly realized the meaning behind Zhang Dong’s words. A deal needed to be made and this area close to the entrance gate was ill-suited for bartering. The two took off into the sky with some of the soldiers using their flying horses to keep up with them. They were going toward the large sword shape tower in the background which gave him some time to examine the surroundings even more.

Just as his senses had told him, the city wasn’t fully populated. At most twenty-five percent of the buildings were populated. Most of the people here were military personnel but he could still see servants. These were even weaker than the common people that resided in these lands. Without the magical armor that the soldiers were wearing, the power level of these people was quite low.

Finally, after flying through the air for a few minutes they arrived at another large wall. This was a wall within a wall that separated the outside city and this citadel. Inside he could sense a lot of magical power along with a high concentration of troops. Even though he considered himself to be quite powerful he didn’t think that he would be able to get out of there alive without using his teleportation feature.

This didn’t stop him from setting up a safe point within the compound. If he ever needed to infiltrate this place in the future it would be possible. He had decided to place it within the residential area while flying through the air. Putting it inside the giant sword structure crossed his mind but it was always better to measure the threat level from the outside. If he popped into the fortress directly and got surrounded then even he would have a bad time. There were ways that his teleport escape could be blocked, Wang Long used some type of blocking measure.

‘So this is probably their headquarters, something is blocking my spiritual sense.’

While Argus was talking with the gate guards he tried inspecting the giant sword tower. He couldn’t peer into it from the outside and now when he was closer the same effect persisted. There weren’t many things that could block his senses which made him believe that something powerful could be inside the tower. This he would probably not figure out yet as their destination didn’t seem to be the tower. Instead, they were going to a nearby palace that looked like it came from some kind of fairytale.

There was quite a bit of space inside this area surrounded by the second wall. It somewhat reminded him of how some sects build their inner sanctums. In the middle was the giant sword tower reaching all the way up to the clouds. Around it was seven castles and palaces, one of which was the one that they were going to. It didn’t take him much to put two and two together to figure out what this meant.

‘It’s similar to the Heavenly Crane Sect and their ten lily factions.’

These seven castles look different and probably belong to six other knight commanders like Lucius. The one he was flying to was surrounded by a wide moat that looked more like a lake. One white bridge that had a vast amount of arches on it led to the only gate entrance on it. The walls were pure white and had angelic undertones to everything. Inside it, he could feel the presence of his acquaintance, Lucius.

‘So, there are six other people on his level that would reside in those castles. The question is if he is the weakest one of them or not…’

Zhang Dong had an idea about the true power of these magical forces. Together with Lucius, there would probably be seven knight commanders. Then whoever resided in the sword tower was their leader. It was more than likely that this person was at emperor-level and he could appear at any point in time.

‘One thing is clear, whatever that person says my two friends would carry out, I need to be careful.’

While Argus didn’t seem like a bad man, he was only one of many subjects of this magical kingdom. If their king appeared they would have no other choice than to listen to him. Luckily for now there was no one above Lucius in prestige and everything that he decided would be carried out.

‘Hm, these castles are like clans and they probably operate in a similar way. Seven duke families and one king, it’s that kind of setting?’

“Lucius it has been some time, how have you been?”

“Zhang Dong, what have you come here for? I have heard that you are in possession of the aegis but are unwilling to part ways with it? What is the meaning of this.”

“Haha, I’m happy to see you too, now put down that sword and listen to me.”

He had finally arrived at the palace courtyard. He was surrounded from all sides by the golden knights that he had previously tussled with. They were all wearing their armor and ready to jump at him at any moment. It wasn’t strange for Lucius to take this approach but he had hoped that the blondie would have a bit more trust in him.

“I do have your shield and I will hand it over if you help me out.”

“Help you out?”

“Yes, you scratch my back and I scratch yours.”

“Huh?”

Both Argus and Lucius were confused by the saying from his modern world. He could only cough into his fist while shaking his head before continuing with his point.

“I mean, that I’ll help you if you do something for me in return.”

“How do we know that this isn’t a trick? What evidence do you have of possessing the aegis?”

“Wasn’t finding your sacred sword proof enough already? You could say that I have a knack for finding holy relics.”

Zhang Dong smiled at the grumpy-looking knight in armor. He had proven himself by finding the first item and they didn’t have to know that it was just by pure luck. This however in their eyes was probably nothing more than a coincidence. Thus to make this more believable he decided to do a little demonstration.

“You will have to produce some evidence if you wish us to believe it.”

“That’s fine with me, just give me a moment, I’m sure Argus will be able to confirm my claim if he sees it.”

He reached out with his hand to produce a blue ball of energy. At first the knights and Lucius were ready to draw the weapons but Argus was quick to stop them.

“My lord, that’s a miniature teleportation gate, it’s harmless.”

“Teleportation gate?”

“Yes, and what do you think is on the other side?”

Argus was quick to move closer as he realized the item that was on the other side. It was clearly the aegis that they desired but before he could reach out to take it, Zhang Dong closed the connection to that location.

“Not so fast, first we make a deal, and then you’ll get your item!”

“... Name your price.”

Lucius had no reason to not believe Argus that was almost foaming at his mouth after seeing the sacred treasure. Now it was up to them to not get scammed too much but Zhang Dong on the other hand would make them work for it.

Chapter 603

“So let me get this straight, you want us to work as your army? Are we lowly mercenaries for you to call upon?”

“Hey, I didn’t say that, it’s more of a symbiotic exchange don’t you think? You will get your holy relic when the mission is complete. I helped you with your sword already, I think that should be enough to prove that I’m an ally.”

“I’ll be the judge of that, it is true that you have helped us in the past but…”

“What, you still don’t trust me? Well, I can’t do anything about that part but one thing is clear, you need this aegis and I have it, so do we have a deal or not?”

Lucius looked at Zhang Dong with a scoffing gaze. It was clear that the knight commander didn’t want to take on this mission but also couldn’t refuse it. His whole purpose for being here was to get the holy relics and this was a chance to get them. Zhang Dong wasn’t sure but he was expecting Lucius to be rewarded handsomely if he returned home with the divine items. Perhaps the sword had already been moved to the magical kingdom as he couldn’t feel its presence anywhere. However, it also could be inside this sword monument as he couldn’t peer through it.

“Lord Lucius, Lord Dong has been an honorable ally, I think we can trust him on this matter.”

“Hmph… very well.”

“Haha, I knew you’d see it my way but don’t worry, my forces and my other allies will do the bulk of the fighting, you will just act as a distraction to spread out their forces, it should be an easy task to perform for your warriors. However, we don’t need to rush things yet I still have to talk with my allies so this could take some time. Don’t worry, your relic is in a safe location.”

He wasn’t quite sure what his plan for the future would be just yet. The Heavenly Crane Sect still needed to give him an answer to his call and what the Emerald Phoenix Empire would do was still up in the air. For all he knew, they could decide to go into a more defensive battle and bunker up in the lands they already captured.

This would probably be a better solution when going up against forces they didn’t have much information on. His army of robotic angels was going around the less-defended cities and slowly liberating everyone that was still alive there. This did give the Heavenly Crane Sect some incentive to make a move as it would look bad on their side if someone else was doing the liberating.

“At a safe location? What will happen to the relic if something happens to you?”

“Don’t worry about it as long as my sect is in place, someone will know the location to your treasure”

“Hm… You leave me no choice but remember this, if you betray our trust and fail to relinquish the treasure…”

“Haha, don’t worry I don’t want to have you guys as enemies, have a little trust in people, otherwise you might get some hemorrhoids.”

“H… hemorrhoids?”

“Yeah, How will you find a good woman if you got those Lucius?”

Zhang Dong could see Lucius getting red in the face and the other golden knights being taken aback by what he had said. It was strange for them to see someone talking to their glorious leader in such a way without any reservation even more when the topic was his behind.

‘Hm… does he really have hemorrhoids? Their reaction is a bit strange.’

The soldiers were whispering to each other as if Zhang Dong had discovered a secret that their commander was trying to hide.

“Wait, do you actually have hemorrhoids? If you need some help, I could make you some ointment, it should get rid of them within a few days if you apply it directly or I could make a pill but that one would have to be inserted a bit further in.”

“... Further in…”

“Yeah, it’s not that big so you shouldn’t feel a thing, I gave it to my grandfather and it worked wonders, he was like a new man!”

“S… stop spouting nonsense!”

Finally, Lucius had enough of it and even went for his sword. The other knights backed off as if he hit a nerve. Zhang Dong knew that it was probably better to distance himself from this group but even he had trouble in holding his laughter in.

“Well, I have some things to do, I’ll get back to you after I have everything figured out…How about you show me out, Argus?”

“Y-yes, that might be a good idea, please follow me.”

While flying away he could see Lucius waking up from being stunlocked by the conversation and shaking his fist at him in anger. Luckily some of the golden knights managed to hold him back before he could embarrass himself even more.

“Hey Argus, I’ll send you over that ointment, give my regards to Lucius.”

“Maybe that’s not such a good idea…”

The old man gave out a cough while flying through the air. Just as fast as he arrived at the white palace, he was already leaving. This was enough to get an idea about the defenses that this place had as well as the other six remaining palaces that were mostly empty. They had some servants and silver knights here and there but no leaders.

‘I should probably get everything sorted out before they decide to call for backup. If the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and the Cerulean Empress are gone, even if their King appears it shouldn’t be an issue anymore.’

His power continued to grow while his enemies remained stagnant. If this continued he didn’t see a way of losing this scenario, that is if the Overseer didn’t get involved. That was always the dark horse in this situation and something he was trying to avoid. The contact with his brother was nonexistent. He had no idea what would happen after everything was over, perhaps his brother would be the actual end boss of everything and for that occasion, he also needed to prepare.

“Lord Dong, are you busy? I still have to return that book that you lent me, why don’t you join me in my tower first?”

“You have your own tower?”

“Yes, it might not look like it but I’m part of this circle of wizards that is renowned in our country.”

“Sure, lead the way, I have a moment.”

While he could just teleport away, it wasn’t bad to know Argus a bit better. The man was a magician that was on the level of a nascent soul master. In contrast to the knights that wore magical armor, he was actually capable of producing powerful spells without the use of any outside sources. It was strange that he wasn’t given proper respect by those knights as they treated him more like a lackey.

It was something that he was very much interested in. Argus looked like a combination of some fantasy wizards from some books he read in his youth. A white beard, gray robe, and a large pointy hat were just a few things that made him look like a generic magician from fictitious worlds.

He also seemed to have a whole magical tower that was not part of the white castle nor any of the other ones around the massive sword. Instead, his residence was in what looked to be a guard tower, one of six that were built on top of the second circular wall. This made him believe that five other wizards would be joining them in the future if things got rough. Perhaps even one more if perhaps their leader had his own grand wizard.

“So this is your tower? I can feel quite the concentration of mana around it and also inside of it as well…”

“Lord Dong, I was meaning to ask you, where did you pick up the arcane arts, you are the only person in this vast Empire that seems to be knowledgeable about our field of studies.”

“Ah, well… let’s say that I’ve journeyed beyond these lands just like you and learned a thing or two there.”

“To lands beyond? Could you have come to our kingdom?”

“No, it was another one, perhaps after everything is over, I’ll tell you the story of my travel.”

“I’ll be sure to remind you of that.”

Argus smiled as he was quite intrigued by this fact. Luckily he understood that Zhang Dong was still a neutral ally and it would take more for him to relinquish his secrets. The two were working on that art as they had traded some books. Zhang Dong offered Argus some knowledge about spirit summoning as he was actually something similar. He received some basic magical knowledge in return which he could compare to the books he absorbed in the other world.

The magical system was almost identical but there were some subtle differences. It was clear that at a base point, the two world’s magic was very similar. They all probably had the same origin point but when spreading out, they became different and the focus varied. In the case of Argus, he was more capable of producing attacking spells that caused immediate damage and didn’t have much knowledge about summoned spirits which in their kingdom was more of a side job.

“This has been quite the read, I have even managed to perform a summoning act to conjure up a spirit, it’s truly interesting and quite different from a familiar!”

“Oh, it’s a fire spirit, not bad.”

The two arrived at the magical tower. At first, it seemed that it didn’t have any entrance door but with a wave of his hand, Argus produced a large door that swung open. To Zhang Dong’s keen eye, the illusion that was placed there was easy to discover but other cultivators would probably have trouble identifying the spot with their lack of knowledge of mana. Inside they moved to a large open space surrounded by floating books and a flaming spirit that looked like a lion.

“Hoh, it seems to like you…”

“I was always good with cats and dogs.”

The flaming lion jumped forth only to get petted by Zhang Dong’s arm. Anyone would get third-degree burns when attempting something like this but his body which had been refined into a treasure in itself, would take any damage from such flames. The lion rolled over to its belly as it was petted which was quite a surprising sight to Argus who decided to cancel the summon.

“You do have a lot of interesting books are you proposing another trade?”

“You know me too well, Lord Dong.”

Both of the men smiled at each other, they both had their own agenda but at this moment the only thing they wanted was more knowledge. Zhang Dong started producing copies of the books he ingrained in his brain while Argus allowed the flying texts to rest inside of some bookshelves that suddenly appeared from out of nowhere. It was time to take in some knowledge and perhaps become even better at using magic.

Chapter 604

“Keep your hips up… don’t drop the weights!”

“Yes, uncle!”

“That’s it, keep it up, remain in this position for the next hour and if you spill the water, you know what will happen!”

“Yes, uncle!”

‘...He looks really motivated… but aren’t those methods a bit extreme?’

Zhang Dong was looking at a scene playing out before him. A handsome young man with white hair was shouting at a young child. This young child had weights strapped to both his hands and legs. While they didn’t look that bulky, they were made of special heavy material that weighed ten times what iron would.

The boy was standing in a horse stance with his hands to the sides. On his head, he had a large jar of water that was filled up to the brim. If he moved slightly the water would pour out and he would fail in his training. It was a standard training method to build up a martial artist's core and balance but when performed by his own son that wasn’t even six, it was hard to watch.

‘Should I tell Zhang Liu to chill out with this sort of training? But he probably went through something similar when he was younger… Little Jun also has that special martial physique that makes him more robust than other kids…’

He wasn’t sure if it was pure luck or if the body he was given by the system had something to do with it but both his kids were considered special. His son had a natural talent for martial arts and at this age, he could start actually learning some of the basics. His sister was ahead of him but it wouldn’t be strange if at some point the younger brother caught up to her eventually.

After having a talk with Argus and getting some more magical books into his library he decided to return home for a moment. His plan of surprising his kids was interrupted by their training. At first, he went to check up on his daughter but she was also busy learning some lightning arts from Zang Xue. Both his disciples were here for the time being and took some time off to train his own children while he was busy.

This wasn’t anything out of the ordinary as usually fathers didn’t train their own children. What they did was mostly give them some old texts before leaving their offspring to train by themselves. Then when the time was right they would see what the children had learned and correct them if they so desired. The Life of a family head was somewhat very lonely.

They were supposed to remain the pillar that everyone could lean on when times became rough. In this world filled with actual demonic beings, monsters, and cultivators that would murder you for almost any little thing, it was paramount to remain the strongest. Thus at this time of war, no one would think it was strange that his children didn’t see his father.

He was actually the oddball out of the bunch, other fathers would just lock themselves up in cultivation chambers while pondering the Dao. It wasn’t strange for some children to not see their parents for months or even years before they came out of self-imposed training. This couldn’t be helped as the strongest fighter needed to remain at peak condition, ready to swoop in whenever their family needed them.

‘I guess, I should leave him to his training.’

Zhang Jun’s expression was very motivated, not something he would expect to see on such a young child. When he tried to remember what he was doing at that time, it probably revolved around watching TV or playing video games with no worries in the world. However, he somewhat knew that this little guy was doing all of this to impress his old man.

This brought him immense pride while also shame. To everyone in the sect, he was a big hero that sacrificed his life for the people. He had worked tirelessly to achieve his power and status when going against evil sects like the Dark Palm Sect. The truth wasn’t really out there as he knew that his strength was given to him by the system. He had entirely skipped through a lot of steps that would force him to work like his son was working now.

The body he had would just get more powerful by absorbing treasures and he could even further his cultivation by spending spirit points. His starting point was a cheat in itself as he didn’t really need to focus on training all that much. He bought skills and techniques through the system and could even copy scriptures directly into his brain. Skipping so many steps others needed years to spend on was really what made him what he was today and when watching this child that was trying too hard, it made him feel somewhat inadequate.

No one really knew this part of him, not really even his wife that had met him when he was already quite strong. The only thing he could do was now act as something his family and sect could look up to. If he managed to not shatter this superman like persona that he built up, then his people would have something to aspire to. While his power was given to him by underhanded means he could still use it for others. Wang Long would remain a cautionary tale as to what not to do while he tried to strive for greatness and act as a beacon for his family and friends.

‘Hm… well this will cut my visit short, Liena is still helping people in the north and I only had an hour or so…’

His visit was supposed to be a surprise but instead, he would cut it short. This didn’t mean that he would go without doing anything. Instead of speaking with his kids, he decided to leave them a little souvenir instead. He had been working on the angelic puppets quite a bit which left him with some scrapped material. This was enough to make two dolls, one a bit cuter for his little girl and another one a bit more manly for his boy.

He wasn’t set on the design but after interacting with his kids they did seem to prefer a difference in the toys they received. After leaving each doll that could actually perform simple orders and a letter behind he decided to head out. The issue in the east was not resolved yet so he could not spend more time here. Now that his army of puppets was loose he needed to reel in the Heavenly Crane Sect some more.

‘They are going to have another meeting, I guess I’ll pop up and push them in the right direction otherwise, nothing will ever get done here…’

With that in mind, he went to his system window and activated the teleportation feature. His body blurred and quickly vanished to appear at another location. It was a luxury inn that was usually not used by anyone by people in high places. He spent some time there waiting for those old farts trying to decide on things without killing each other. Now it was a spot he could teleport to and perhaps a mistake by what he was seeing.

“Oh mister, don’t be so hasty.”

“How could I not be hasty with such a tasty morsel in front of me… hehe… huh?”

“Well, this is embarrassing… Does your wife know about this, Sun Shi?”

A scene was playing out before him, the elder that visited his sect was trying to loosen up the clothes of a younger lady. He had no idea who the woman was but she had a lot of makeup on and looked like this world's version of a courtesan. Zhang Dong didn’t want to assume but it wasn’t anything strange to see things like this. His own grandfather was someone one of those elders that couldn’t keep his pants closed for a day and it seemed that this old man was the same.

“... Honorable Golden Dragon… w-why are you here…”

The color drained out of Sun Shi’s face as he saw Zhang Dong before him. The woman jumped back trying to cover herself up with a nearby bedsheet. This was quite the unlucky moment to appear in this place. He would need to make a note to never leave teleportation spots inside of rooms of inns.

“Ah don’t mind me, I’m just passing by… I was looking for Faction Leader Shen but for some reason, I ended up here… I’ll take my leave…”

“No, this isn’t how it looks!”

Sun Shi stood up from the spot as he had previously found himself in bed. To Zhang Dong’s dismay, the man forgot that he had lowered his pants. A pure white loincloth was tightly wrapped around the old man’s nether regions. It was quite the tight fit as the old man had been caught in a moment of arousal.

“Oh boy…I need to go!”

Shouted Zhang Dong while turning his face towards one of the windows. He did not want to stay here any longer nor ask why Sun Shi had returned to the main sect. It seemed that it was worse than he anticipated if they were pulling out important nascent soul elders from the frontline. Someone needed to put an end to all of this bickering as this was the time to act. Thus he turned into an arc of light in the sky and headed over to where the meeting place of all the faction leaders was.

Perhaps he was not invited to the meeting but he felt that after liberating so many lands in the Heavenly Crane Sect’s name, he was owed something. It didn’t seem that they would come to a conclusion without him forcing the issue. Now that he had saved their people, returned lands to them, and even given them war prisoners, they owed him something in return.

“We must act while we have the momentum, Long Dong had given us this chance, we can reclaim our lands!”

“No we need to wait, now that the Emerald Phoenix Empire has finally taken losses they will surely switch to a defensive battle, our losses will be staggering!”

“You damn old fools!”

“No, you are the fool!”

‘I see they are at it again…’

He wasn’t sure if he should smile or frown after hearing his two favorite faction leaders bickering back and forth. It was the same as the last time and nothing was being done. However, just like the last time he had the intent of shifting their ideas. This he would start with a powerful landing and he was already preparing for it by making the clouds above to gather.

Chapter 605

“What is happening?”

Suddenly a loud thunderclap was heard by the ten nascent soul masters from the lily factions. The clouds above them started circling around their gathering location and changing color. Soon a strange deep yellow glow that resembled gold appeared in the middle. Inside they noticed a person, he had his hands behind his back and was standing on the clouds like a ferocious sword.

“It’s the Golden Dragon? Was he part of this meeting?”

Everyone looked towards Sun Shen, the faction leader of the Moon Lily faction. The old man shook his head as he had not been informed of this. Even the old woman from the faction known for their seers looked surprised. The only thing they could do was wait while slowly reaching for their weapons. Could this be some kind of attack, perhaps the Golden Dragon had been coerced by the enemies? He had spent a lot of time in those lands and that strange army of angels had also appeared out of nowhere.

“Are you this surprised to see me? What’s with those looks on your faces?”

“Honorable Golden Dragon, why have you appeared before us without informing the council about your presence in the sect? We would have of course welcomed you if we just…”

The Patriarch was the one to speak out but the two guardians that were behind him started to move as well. They had mostly recovered from their wounds and were now aching for a rematch with the person that gave them their first loss in a while.

“You just what? Threw a big feast? Wasted more time bickering here? When will you make your move, I already set the stage for you, do you really want me to do everything myself? Is the Heavenly Crane Sect this week?”

“Weak? Long Dong, you are going too far!”

“Hoh, did I touch a nerve? But isn’t what I’m saying true? How do you think your sect will look if all the lands that you previously owned are liberated by me? Well… to be honest that might not be a bad idea, I could just turn them to my vassals instead, the resources there aren’t bad…”

Zhang Dong was slowly floating down from the sky while going into a monologue. He knew that these people didn’t pose a threat to him. After he one-sidedly beat up their twin duo all of these masters were scared of him. If they came at him together as one unit and had some good teamwork then perhaps they would be victorious. However, the ten were divided. One side was even in favor of what he was doing and he could see the old lady even joining his side if a fight broke out.

“What are you insinuating, do you mean you wish to take over our lands?”

“Do I wish to take over your lands? No, that is not what I want, my intention from the start was to get rid of the Emerald Phoenix Empire but if you are not willing to give me aid, I will take care of everything myself.”

Just as he was about to land his body became a blur made of golden lightning energy. His landing shattered some of the ground and produced some smoke. It looked like he was attacking which made the Patriarch and his bodyguards that he appeared next to flinch. However, this was the end of it, no follow-up attacks and no talking, just silence. It was as if he was saying to them that he could have taken their leader’s head if he wanted to and they would not be able to do anything about it.

“You must excuse my actions but this is an issue I will not back away from, the Emerald Phoenix Empire will continue their way to the north and west after they are done with you. Alone you will not be able to stop them, but with my help it is possible, so let me help you and I will promise to leave everything as it was.”

“So, your goal is the eradication of the invaders?”

“Yes.”

“Do you really want us to believe that? What is the real reason?”

Leader Zhong once more was the person to doubt his words. Zhang Dong wanted to give the man a slap across the face but attacking this group of people would just ruin the whole plan. While he could let the Heavenly Crane Sect perish while taking out some of the Emerald Phoenix Empire armies, it would be a net loss in his eyes. They could do so much more if they worked together and fewer people would have to perish.

It wasn’t strange for Zhong to be skeptical about Zhang Dong’s motives. Saints existed in this world but they never really got to the level of a nascent soul master. Each and every cultivator sooner or later had to walk over someone else to gain their position. To him, there had to be some kind of hidden treasure or something that Zhang Dong or his sect would gain from helping them.

“You want a reason? Shouldn’t you be asking yourself a different question though?”

“A different question?”

“Yes, is this a bad deal for you? How about you stop worrying about what I’m getting for this and think of what your profits will be? It’s fine if you don’t trust me but is it a bad deal for you?”

“The golden dragon isn’t wrong… the weapons of those invaders are quite peculiar, perhaps we could gain their wisdom and adapt them to work with our techniques!”

“Yes… the samples of their pills were also interesting… there is much that we could gain from this.”

“See, now you’re thinking in the right direction, you get your treasures and the only think I will ask for, is their Emperor.”

“The Emerald Phoenix Emperor?”

“Yes, you can have the rest, but their leader is mine.”

“Hm…”

The Patriarch and all the other elders started thinking. They knew that the leader of the enemy empire would probably have the best treasures on his body. It wouldn’t be strange to want what was the best for them, considering they were one of the big three in the empire. However, they were in the presence of Zhang Dong, the great Golden Dragon. It was clear to them that they wouldn’t be able to defeat him in a fair fight.

‘Hm… They will probably agree and when the time comes weigh their options again.’

“I think what the Golden Dragon is saying isn’t a bad offer, there will be many treasures to be gotten.”

“I also agree, those pill formulae are already good enough and will help us bolster our sect for generations to come!”

Soon some of the factions that were on the fence started to agree. Their greed was strong and when given the option of gaining potential treasures in the form of weapons, pills, and techniques they weren’t able to refuse. The only thing they needed to do was to give Zhang Dong the belongings of their leader.

Even this was a potential chance, he knew that they were hoping for the two leaders to take themselves out. When the two most powerful cultivators fought to the death, there was always a chance for a third party to snatch it all at the end. If Zhang Dong won and was gravely injured, they could swoop in to take the prize.

The same rule applied if he lost, as long as one of the scary Emperor level threats was weakened they could attempt to take everything. In either scenario, they would be gaining a lot, thus their decision swayed towards sending their troops. Even if there was a chance to lose some people, the chances of gaining more power outweigh any potential deaths of their sect members.

“I see your point Golden Dragon but you will have to leave us so we can vote on this matter as our traditions require us.”

“Of course but keep this in mind, it won’t take much more time until their counter-offensive.”

“They plan to attack us? Do you have proof for this claim?”

Leader Zhong shouted out from the distance as always as he had been planning to bunker up instead of charging in.
“Proof? No, I don’t have anything substantial, this is just an opinion made on my own observation.”

This time it was the Patriarch who was interested. They still didn’t really know their enemy's true motives. Were they after something specific or were they just warmongers trying to capture more lands? Some would probably be fine in giving up some of their lands if they retained the more critical locations that were closer to the center of the Azure Empire. It wasn’t strange to back off and wait, cultivators were long-lived so even waiting for hundred years wasn’t anything new for them.

“Then what is the basis for your actions?”

“I would say, their nature and lack of time? I, I forgot that you are not the Long Clan, you still do not know what is happening.”

“Golden Dragon… could you explain it to us then?”

All the elders here were quite intrigued by Zhang Dong's claims. What were this true nature and lack of time he was talking about? They still didn’t know about the fact that within a hundred years, the bridge would be closed and the Emerald Phoenix Empire would need to evacuate. They also didn’t know of their hundred of thousands of years of prep time. This he could quickly explain to them which would probably push them in the right direction.

If they knew that their enemies resided in another section of this world that was only accessible every hundred thousand years, they would surely get interested. They were just like them if they could, they would probably like to invade the Emerald Phoenix Empire lands if they could. It would be an intriguing place to visit that could even have various different treasures that could be received by them.

Zhang Dong had to actually persuade his own people to not cross into the demi-human empire while the bridge was still there. The option to plunder their lands while they were in the process of a civil war was enticing. Their leader had been killed and most of the tribe leaders were as well. It wouldn’t be hard to take over their lands but it would also split up their resources. However, perhaps if the northern sea creature problem was done with, then perhaps the demi-human empire could act as a secondary source for spirit points.

“Well then, sit tight as this one might take a while, let me first explain the bridges that have appeared all over the empire and the great divide…”

Chapter 606

“This subject greets the Supreme General!”

“I hope you bring good word, otherwise my father won’t be pleased…”

“My liege…”

The moment of silence caused the man sitting on a throne made of green jade to frown. The chamber he found himself in was vast, and many guards were forced to spread out as if it were empty. At this moment they were slowly reaching for their swords as if ready to punish the messenger of bad news.

“Fine, talk.”

“Y-yes Supreme General! Our armies have been forced to retreat ever since a strange master appeared.”

“The Golden Dragon was it?”

“Yes, Supreme General, the same… after driving our forces back an army of strange metallic warriors appeared which have been quickly driving our people back towards this region…”

“Are you saying that our generals can’t handle one person and some army made of puppets?”

“I…”

“I heard enough!”

The man on the throne snapped his fingers and just as the snapping sound ended the head of the man that brought the message landed on the floor. The supreme general looked at the body sprouting a fountain of blood before sprawling out on the ground with disgust. Only after another wave of his hand did two servants move forward to take care of the mess one of the soldiers made.

“I want you to bring me all the information you have on this ‘Golden Dragon’ . My father left this mission to me and I will tolerate no failure, let this be a reminder to all of you, failure is not an option!”

“Yes, Supreme General!”

A group of other men dressed in armor saluted while looking at the body and the head of one of their own being dragged away. With their spiritual sense, they could see it going towards a row of pikes that was placed in front of the supreme general’s palace. The bodies of the commanding officers that had retreated were lined up there and this one would be added to the pile. It was clear that retreat was not an option anymore, it was better to try and fight it out than return here and be beheaded by the Prince.

“Elder Brother Kong, you shouldn’t bully the generals, what if they decide to run away when we need them?”

“Yahui? Hah, they wouldn’t dare.”

“That is true, they don’t want anything to happen to their little clans and sects back home~”

A woman of immeasurable beauty approached the Supreme General from the side. No one else dared to move while the two were interacting. They continued to follow the subtitle movements of this beauty who was a forbidden fruit that they could never have.

“So this is the man that stands in your way, brother?”

“Yes…”

“Let me have him.”

“I know that look, you should take this seriously.”

“I am, do you actually think I would lose to a single man? He is just my type that’s all, I won’t play with him too much~”

“Fine, take care of it.”

“Hehe~”

Both of them were looking at a recording of one of the fights at the border. They could see the golden warrior going through their large ships and performing feats outside the norm. However, to these two he was still only a slightly larger bug than the rest.

…

“You won’t regret the decision.”

“I hope so, our sect will lose much otherwise.”

“Yes, but if you are victorious then your power will skyrocket! Try thinking about all the treasures and new powerful cultivation techniques you might gain. As you have seen, these cultivators abilities to use our Qi are greater than ours.”

“This is true, if we could harness this power… we would be…”

The Patriarch from the Heavenly Crane Sect covered his mouth as he didn’t want to finish the sentence. It could be taken as a challenge to the Azure Emperor if this sect became too strong and Zhang Dong was still considered part of that faction. The group had finally come to a conclusion and decided to engage in battle and rid these lands of the Emerald Phoenix Empire.

‘Just the idea of getting a bit stronger is enough to move them, suddenly all caution flies out of the window when resources and power are involved.’

While their goals were sketchy they were willing to activate their army. Some of the Lily faction leaders would be joining the counter-offensive together with him. Both Sun Shen and Leader Zhong were part of the initial troops. He was not sure how the two would do when fighting side by side or commanding troops. Both of them hated each other's guts and this might lead to some friction.

‘The Patriarch isn’t going to move for now, and those twins won’t either… Well, this is better than nothing. I just need them to keep their soldiers busy while I take out their leaders.’

He did not have too much faith in the Heavenly Crane Sect. If he wasn’t here along with his angel army to back them up, it would have been better for them to actually bunker up at their base. However, when he was at the scene they had an ace up their sleeve. The opponents were also cultivators, when their most powerful elder was defeated their morale would plummet.

“I will excuse myself then while you prepare, we shall meet out in the field of battle.”

“As you wish, Golden Dragon, we have informed our elders about the allies from the south that wear robes made of metal.”

“Good, let us discuss tactics later.”

After a small back and forth with their Patriarch Zhang Dong decided to head back out to the field. Lucius and his squadron of golden knights would arrive in a few days from the southern region and the Heavenly Crane Sect would need some time to mobilize their forces as well.

The large war machine was now activated but it would take some time to gather all the soldiers and weapons. Soon people would be getting letters and communication jade messages that they were to assemble. This was just the first draft that required all of the sect members to gather. They were all experienced warriors and required no further training, what they just needed to do was to meet up at a specific location and wait for orders.

Zhang Dong expected this to take around a week. At such times some of the sect members would choose to flee. Not everyone was willing to risk their lives for resources and glory, without the nascent soul elders breathing down everyone's neck it would probably be impossible to progress. There weren’t that many sects like the United Element Sect that loved their Patriarch to the point of throwing themselves into harm's way blindly.

However, thanks to the recent victories the morale wasn’t low, even people that were on the fence could see a reason to fight, and a chance to make a name for themselves was possible. Deserting was always an option later but if they found themselves on the winning side, their value would skyrocket.

Even the weakest soldier would be handsomely rewarded at the end of the battles and for a lot, this was enough to take the risk. Most people saw themselves as the heroes in their story and the thought of death was a minor possibility if their side was stronger.

Time started passing as he retreated to his golden fortress. It was a good time to see how many spirit points his troops have harvested. The sum was quite staggering and would even allow him to upgrade the bastion to the next stage. For the time being, he decided to postpone the upgrade. The cost of teleporting the palace toward the Eastern Front from the North would be quite staggering.

This was one of his trump cards that he needed to hold on to, only after having enough spirit points for a two-way teleportation and the upgrade would he spend them. It was better to hold onto this load as teleporting the masters from his sect around was also a possibility. The distance was quite tremendous though and would burn through the reserves he had his forces farm for him.

News of the Heavenly Crane Sect armies on the move started reaching other people in the empire. It wasn’t something that could be hidden away, however even though the old powerful sect was on the move, someone else's name was on the end of the tongues of everyone. The name Long Dong and Golden Dragon had become even more popular among the populace.

If Zhang Dong could see his approval rating in the whole empire he would see an arrow going straight up. His popularity was skyrocketing which brought its own set of pros and cons. He could not worry about it, for now, the Emerald Phoenix Empire needed to vanish from within these lands. What would happen after this, needed to wait.

‘We do have an upper hand here…’

Zhang Dong floated in the sky and looked at the horizon. There he saw a storm approaching that in the past would make him dive inside to absorb the lightning's energies. They weren’t in range for his senses but he new that from that direction a large army of cultivators was flying in this direction. It was vastly more numerous than the ones that were trying to push into the border region.

Thanks to his map he was able to follow their every move and relay that information to his new friends. He had even produced a replica of the region to make it easier for them to devise a good strategy. While they could see the main force on the map, it wasn’t that easy to make out smaller squadrons that could have split up.

‘But what will they do, they will probably be a bit more strategic about this engagement than last time, the brute force approach didn’t work…’

Zhang Dong had prepared some surprises for his new enemies. One of them was waiting below ground for a moment to strike. It was easy to predict where the bulk of the army would arrive to place some traps and some formations. All they needed to do now was wait and let their web close around the invaders.

‘I should probably get in place too, let’s see how they fare without my help.’

He glanced at a war tent made by the Heavenly Crane Sect. Inside were four of the Lily Faction leaders discussing the battle that would transpire. He did not want to use these people as the lure but going solo against a proper army like this would not work out too well even for him. Thus until the right moment arrived he would bide his time and then strike swiftly to end it all.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 607

‘This is just like that one time… will it be as easy though? The scale is a lot different, they did bring a lot more people… and what is this, I think they actually thought things through…’

Zhang Dong was looking at some rocks after digging himself into an underground cavern. Above ground, there was a storm coming and along with it a bunch of enemy cultivators from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. He had decided to prepare a few traps beforehand and the underground tunnel he dug himself into was a part of it.

His finger moved around in a strange pattern before a magical symbol appeared. The symbol embedded itself into the rocks while making them glow with energy. Many were pushed to the side of the wall and they produced a pentagram-like symbol with many strange rune-like symbols around it. Just as fast as these magical letters appeared did they vanish again and the glow died down.

The plan wasn’t that intricate, just a few formations boosted by his knowledge of mana from the other world. This knowledge he intended to use to get one over the enemy cultivators that weren’t versed in ways of mana. They would have probably had ways of countering formations that used traditional knowledge from this empire as their own wasn’t that different.

While the effect that was produced was similar, the way of going about it was different. It was like saying the same words in a different language. Without knowing the language a person wouldn’t be able to decipher what was being said. Perhaps they could vaguely read into the situation but the true meaning behind the words wouldn’t be able to go through. It was the same with these altered formations, before they figured out how to go around them it would be too late.

He had hoped to just wait here until the enemy armada was on top. With his current powers, he could hide his presence from all conventional means. It wouldn’t be strange to assume that the only thing that could pick him up would be an Emperor-Level threat that was close to his power. However, a problem appeared, the enemies had decided to go below ground and it was not a small force at all.

‘Hm, they are quite bold. Going this deep underground in a location they don’t fully know could be very disadvantageous… Though they did capture this area for a moment, did they take the maps with them to learn about all these natural tunnels?’

Zhang Dong had his system which could pierce through the ground to show him all the various tunnels down here. Some of them were eroded through millennia by underground streams while others were dug through by large beasts. Such corridors as the one he was in weren’t that uncommon but maneuvering through them without a map like he had wasn’t easy.

‘Hm… this is a chance, but if I start killing them then the guys on top will know that they are moving into a trap, I will have to be careful.’

With the help of his mapping system, he could easily follow after his enemies. First, he needed to figure out what they were up to down here. Only after that would he make a decision on what he would do. Thanks to his high cultivation level and some higher knowledge he gained in the Dao of Earth, he sunk into the hard rocks and began to swim through them.

While it looked as if he was diving into water in reality his body was surrounded by a thin layer of spiritual energy. This energy would push the earth in front of him out of the way as he flew forward. Then after all the rocks and soil were out of the way, more spiritual energy would connect everything back into place. It was a constant process of disassembling the earth and then assembling it right behind him that made it seem as if he was swimming through it. No tunnel was left behind in his wake which would make following him quite a troubling task.

‘There they are, around twenty people but some other groups are in other directions… I see, they had a similar plan as me.’

After waiting for a few minutes he rose out of the ground in a location previously occupied by people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. They had traveled through these tunnels doing the exact same thing as him. At the spot that he was in he could see hidden formation pathways in the walls and even a flag was left embedded in the rocks.

‘Hm… what a peculiar formation… when activated it will start affecting spiritual energy of a certain wavelength… I see so that’s what they are up to.’

At first, he assumed that they were planting some traps just like him but this wasn’t their battle strategy. Instead, this formation would create a large area that would only affect the denizens of this empire and their spiritual energy. In simple terms, it was a kind of spiritual energy-dampening formation, not something people of the Azure Dragon Empire would really ever use.

It wouldn’t really make sense as this affected every person in the same fashion. It would lower the power output of any Qi-related skills by about twenty percent. Only people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire would be safe from the effects as their cultivation methods and how they used spiritual energy were slightly different. In short, they wouldn’t be affected by the formation while his allies would suffer a long-lasting debuff.

‘Wait a minute, I can probably use this to my advantage, I don’t even need to take them out… if I change it around a bit… then this will be quite the surprise when they activate the formation.’

Zhang Dong started grinning as he realized that this gave him a better chance at winning than his own previous plan of activating trap formations. His enemies would do all the work for him while he just slightly altered the formations. After they realized what was happening it would already be too late. If all of their people remained alive and healthy they would not be aware of the subterfuge.

Thus his plan started to be implemented, following these people wasn’t hard. Even though they had some powerful experts with them, no one was able to detect his presence. At critical junctures, he would pop out from a wall of the ceiling to change a few things around. There wasn’t even that much for him to do besides keeping to the shadows.

…

“Faction Leaders, the enemies are upon us!”

“Where is the Golden Dragon? Wasn’t he supposed to lead the charge?”

Asked Leader Zhong when looking at Leader Shen.

“He said that he wanted to prepare something for them but don’t forget that he had left some of his own forces behind.”

The two nascent soul elders decided to leave the tent where they were deciding on a strategy for this battle. Their forces were all on one side while the enemies from the Emerald Phoenix Empire were on the other. In their eyes, they were on the losing side, at least if Zhang Dong wasn’t with them. To bolster their forces they were aided by new allies, one was a large army of strange metallic warriors and pyramids. The other was a small group of armored men riding on winged horses. Each group was radiating power worthy to call themselves their allies and with them, they could see victory.

“They do seem capable…”

“They do, don’t worry while the Golden Dragon is powerful I will not stand idle if our sect members are slaughtered, we must be ready for all possibilities Leader Zhong.”

“I agree…”

Both men that usually weren’t on good terms nodded at each other. To them the survival of their sect was very important, if victory became shaky they were ready to abandon their newfound allies and even use them as a shield while they retreated. They were still on the fence about the whole situation but the treasures that could be gained seemed worth the risk that they were taking.

“Heavenly Crane Sect, advance!”

“For the Sect!”

“Long live the Heavenly Crane Sect!”

The warriors started shouting while moving to the skies. Their fleet was composed of flying ships and various attacking formations created by core formation cultivators. Many nascent soul masters were also on their side, all ready to push in when the time for them to act arrived. There wasn’t much strategy involved in this clash, just two large forces meeting each other in an open field.

A clash between spiritual energies caused the ground to rumble. With these many flying vessels and powerful cultivators around the whole atmosphere started morphing before finally, everything exploded into a frenzy. First, the ships started to fire their spiritual cannons from afar, the defensive formations were the first line of defense.

White spirit bullets shot away from the Heavenly Crane Sect and collided with a bright green shield. In response, cannon bolts of green spiritual energy were shot right back and collided with a semi-transparent defensive formation on the other side. It was a race now, the defensive shield that broke first would be the first devastating blow and a sign of the tides shifting in one direction. Only after both shields were unable to offer any defensive advantages would the place erupt into a massive brawl.

Both sides seemed to be somewhat equal without anyone being able to advance. That was before it appeared, a massive beast clad in golden scales and surrounded by the lightning of the same hue. It was a massive golden dragon, presumably the soul best of the man with the same title. It gave out a massive roar before gathering golden light within its maw. A beam of condensed energy soon appeared from within and collided with the green defensive shield of the Emerald Phoenix Empire.

“Their defensive formation is crumbling, everyone attack!”

The tide started shifting, and with the help of the giant dragon the Heavenly Crane Sect felt invigorated. Their forces started pushing inside while the Emerald Phoenix Forces were in disarray. With the dragon pushing in first and the metallic angels following after it the others followed soon after. It didn’t seem that they would need to weaken their enemies with their ranged attacks anymore, the golden dragon was just this strong.

The enemy forces were retreating and trying to escape. It seemed that they were actually too scared to continue fighting. While some saw this as a chance to show their might others with a more keen eye for strategy found this strange.

“Leader Zhong, doesn’t this look strange?”

“Yes, why did they abandon their formations this easily… wait, what if they… tell everyone to halt their attack, this is a trap!”

Just as Zhong had shouted out the orders a strange field of energy appeared all around them. It was then quickly followed by the appearance of a beauty of unprecedented proportions that started laughing.

“Haha, Is this really all you can do? Just like little flies inside of my spider web~”

Chapter 608

“It was a trap, they have surrounded us but… their forces are too thin to stop us, their formation won’t be hard to break, what are they planning?”

Leader Zhong shouted out while floating up in the sky. Their forces attempted to engage with the fleeing Phoenix Emerald Empire forces. It seemed like all of them were scattering to all sides after their protective shield had been broken. However, after a few quick maneuvers, they had encircled them. It was as if they wanted them to break into their formation. The only problem was that they didn’t seem to have enough manpower to block them. There must have been more to this tactic than met the eye.

“Be careful, that woman isn’t simple…”

Sun Shen retreated back to where the other faction leaders were floating and looked towards a certain woman that had appeared before them. At the moment the net closed on them she appeared up in the sky. She was wearing a very long emerald dress that was being held up by two powerful female cultivators that were giving these two great circle nascent soul masters a bad feeling.

“You danced on top of my palm very gratefully, I wasn’t expecting that dragon but it won’t be a problem. Where is that handsome man though? I wouldn’t have come here if I knew that he was just using them as disposable pawns.”

The woman started going into a monologue while the battle stopped. This didn’t sit too well with some of the masters here. It seemed that she had decided that victory was already in her grasp without even trying or taking part in the battle. While she was talking some of the ships that were flying there took aim with their cannons.

“What uncultured little bugs! Do you really wish to die sooner? Very well, this has already become a trivial matter, activate the formation and kill them all, your Princess commands you!”

The spirit cannons rained towards her location but instead collided with some kind of secondary shield that was around the giant flagship she was hovering above. It seemed that the grand barrier they broke through was just a distraction and that each ship had its own field that needed to be broken. Their attacks didn’t leave much of a dent while previously they saw some cracks forming after the first volley.

Right as she finished the sentence a strange force took over the whole place. A massive formation that was under them started appearing and giving off a strange energy signature. The people were stunned, how were they lured into such a simple trap without knowing?

“Did the Golden Dragon betray us?”

The Heavenly Crane Sect members had previously discussed tactics with the man in question. He had told them that he would prepare a few trap and illusory formations under the battlefield before they started. However, since his disappearance, there was no word from him and instead, the massive creature appeared. They thought that it was there to guide them to victory but perhaps this was all a trick.
If it was just a soul beast it could leave the battlefield at any moment. Zhang Dong wasn’t there and perhaps his true goal was for the Heavenly Crane Sect to be eradicated instead. This was what some of the faction leaders were leaning toward but others weren’t quite sure.

The puppets were still there and had put themselves between the invaders and it didn’t seem that they were turning around to attack them. It was the same for the men clad in golden armor, they weren’t doing anything sketchy. This would be the right moment to turn their blades towards the Heavenly Crane Sect but they didn’t.

“Wait… nothing is happening? Do you feel that something is off about this trapping formation?”

“Yes… it’s not affecting us… but look at their ships and soldiers, don’t they look tired?’

To everyone's surprise, the ones that were getting weaker or entrapped weren’t the forces of the Heavenly Crane Sect but the ones from the Emerald Phoenix Empire. Right as the formation was activated they started charging toward their army and using their own ships in charge. However, after a few moments, they stopped as if they weren’t feeling well. The shields that were previously absorbing the cannon fire from their ships started wavering.

“What is happening, why is the formation affecting my army? Who is responsible for this, who dares betray the Emerald Phoenix Princess!?”

The woman in charge started shouting out in anger as she noticed that something was wrong. Her expression changed from a cold beauty to an angered brat within just a second. Her aura burst forth making most of the opposition experts to fall back, one of the beings there didn’t flinch through. Instead, it opened its toothy mouth to shoot forth another concentrated beam of golden energy right at the woman.

“An overgrown lizard dares to attack this Cuilu Yahui?”

Cuilu Yahui's eyebrow shot up while she remained in place. Instead of moving forward herself the two attendants that were behind her acted. First the beam of energy collided with a green shield that was produced by the flagship under them. Even though it managed to pierce through it, the moment it arrived before the two battles maidens it was severally weakened. They had no trouble dispersing the energy that quickly turned into radiant bubbles around them.

“Hoh, you managed to block it?”

“Who is there?”

They heard a voice of a man echoing through the whole battlefield without any proper spot to pinpoint. This soon turned out to be just a ruse as a massive amount of energy had begun forming directly under their main ship. Due to all the chaos that ensued from the trap being altered a chance was presented. A massive beam of energy that looked like a sword pierced out from the earth and went through the massive esthetically pleasing emerald ship.

It happened in a fraction of a second and didn’t give anyone a chance to react. This was not all, while this energy sword was the largest it was not the only one. Soon after the flagship was hit, smaller sword attacks appeared from under them, all going for the largest flying vessels with the highest fighting potential on this battlefield. Before the tide of battle could shift in favor of the Emerald Phoenix Empire’s troops, they took a large hit to their fighting potential.

“Well, this turned out better than expected, I didn’t have enough time to analyze this formation of yours but it should still work at around seventy percent capacity on your troops instead, quite an interesting idea of disrupting spiritual energy, I’ll have to study the concept later.”

Finally, the voice that was echoing became clearer and all eyes focused on the man that it belonged to. He was standing on top of the giant golden dragon’s head with his hands behind his back. His body was radiating an unfathomable cultivation base that could not be denied. The invaders were stunned, even their princess that was considered a matchless genius could not produce a staggering amount of Qi as he could. Even before the battle started everyone was inching away, they knew that more than likely if they tried to engage this man, they would die.

…

‘It’s always easy to go against ‘smart’ people, they always think that they are ahead of everyone and never expect to be beaten.’

Zhang Dong had finished his preparations and waited for the enemies to activate their formation. Only after it was running did he go after them, Bahamut took their attention while he dealt with the cultivators that were underground. After making sure that there was no one there to disable the cracked formation, he decided to join in the battle.

Instead of their forces suffering a weakening in their cultivation base, the people of the opposing army were. It wasn’t as strong as the original formation but it was enough to give him time and destroy some of the more important ships. With time the enemy cultivators would figure a way to either stop the formation or block its effect from affecting them. However, before that could happen he and his allies would put an end to this.

“Don’t let this chance slide, the enemies are weakened, give them hell and join me in battle! Leave their leader to me!”

“You heard the Golden Dragon, don’t give them a chance to recover!”

“For the Heavenly Crane Sect!”

Soon after his allies shouted their orders and the encirclement that was supposed to be a trap became a perfect opportunity. The forces outside were weakened and not prepared to fight enemies in this fashion. Their shields were faltering and their war formations wouldn’t properly take shape, they were quickly getting pushed back. It was clear that if this continued that they would lose.
“Don’t you dare surrender, I, Cuilu Yahui have never known defeat and this will not change!”

As their morale was at an all-time low a burst of energy exploded from the Emerald Phoenix Princess. It was so powerful that it managed to send out a shockwave that pushed the Heavenly Crane Sect’s and the Army of Angles back. However before any damage could be done it faded away, not due to not having enough power but due to Zhang Dong that decided to cancel this energy out.

“So your name is, Cuilu Yahui? If you surrender now, I promise to let your people live. Be smart and don’t prolong this struggle, enough people have already died for your greed and hubris.”

“You want me to surrender? The Daughter of the Emperor? The most powerful woman in the whole Empire? You overestimate your abilities, after I’m done with you, you will be nothing more than a slave below my heel!”

“Sorry, but I’m happily married and I’m not really into that stuff… but I’m not sure if my Grandfather wouldn’t indulge in something like that… Nevertheless, you will not win.”

“Hah, empty words, nothing more!”

Many things were happening all at once but as the two most powerful fighters started talking, everyone else stopped. It was clear to them that if any of them died and the other survived it could sway this battle in another direction. This was just how powerful they were, each one of them was a one-person army.

Zhang Dong parted from his dragon’s head and took flight. In his hand, a shiny sword appeared which he intended to use against the woman that he was facing. While he wasn’t happy about having to fight a woman, this was war. She was a capable fighter that could not be ignored, even he would be in trouble if he didn’t take it seriously.

Cuilu Yahui in response waved her hand to disperse that long wavy dress into a type of energy. It surrounded her body to produce a more tightly fit battle robe, something more suited for this confrontation. With a second wave of her hand a mass of swords appeared behind her, there had to be thousands of them and each one radiated a force equal to a heavenly treasure. The clash between the two experts was soon to start and everyone started holding their breath while hoping that the master from their side would be victorious.

Chapter 609

‘She is a bit better than the others… but not much stronger than a demi-human tribe leader.’

Zhang Dong was flying through the air while evading a swarm of swords. There were thousands of high quality weapons zooming around in strange patterns. Sometimes they would combine into other geometrical shapes, and other times into large hands and fists while trying to kill him.

Any of his allies would have probably been dead by now, and even Lucius would have probably fallen to these attacks as even the woman’s defensive capabilities were quite high. Each time he fired back, the mass of metal would set up a shield to counter his own sword energy. Even if some of the weapons broke they were quickly replaced by a new batch.

‘It seems she has a limit of how many swords she can use but has more of them to replace the broken treasures…’

Below the area, they were fighting it started sprinkling sharp chunks of metal. The swords were cut up by his own superior one that he was using with his one hand. The metallic chunks looked like confetti after being shredded by him and dropping down to the ground.

‘Hm, I could probably arm my angels with these, most of them are low-grade heavenly treasures but some are higher quality…’

It was clear to him that the swarm of lesser-quality swords was meant to act as a distraction. The weapons that were actually meant to kill him were mixed in with the attacking wave. During each exchange one or two such swords would go for his head or chest in an attempt to pierce it.

He was managing to evade each and every one of them or just smack them away with the help of his own sword. Some even made it inside his spatial bag for sampling. This seemed a good opportunity to gain some easy weaponry. All these swords could be given to masters from his sect or to outfit the angelic puppets later. However, first, he would need to win this fight and as it looked, he wouldn’t have trouble performing this task.

“You are a very slippery man but I like it when they play hard to get!”

“Hoh, some people might misunderstand those words if they heard them out of context… now I think this has continued for long enough…”

Just as always he liked to get a good feeling for any new opponent that he was fighting. This woman gave herself the title of Princess and was apparently related to the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. She would probably be worth a lot more as a war prisoner than die. Perhaps the Emperor was a family man and would pull his forces back for a trade. While he didn’t like the idea of blackmailing a father with their own child, too many people had already died here.

It was clear that his enemy was strong and if he wasn’t here to take care of her himself, even Bahamut his dragon might have not been able to defeat her. She was a true expert and powerhouse that would have been probably able to turn the empire upside down. There was only one problem for her, she was facing someone above the norm. Zhang Dong had realized it already, he had become strong, far stronger than even these people.

As it stood now he wouldn’t be surprised if he wasn’t already the most powerful regular cultivator in both of the Empires. Perhaps the Overseer was above him but he could not even see himself losing to the Azure Emperor anymore. Ever since he had defeated Wang Long it was as if a tiny fraction of his being had ascended into a new realm. Even this tiny amount was enough to propel him onto a new playing field that these people were locked out of.

“Long enough? Oh no, handsome. This is only the start, you will become one of my man servants and serve me for the rest of your miserable life!”

“Hah… I refuse.”

“Huh?”

The woman named Cuilu Yahui was stunned as for a moment Zhang Dong’s body vanished. She considered the man to be a worthy opponent but he wasn’t doing anything besides dodging her attacks. Considering that she didn’t yet fully commit to the fight it was reasonable to assume that she would have been victorious. That was before he had appeared at her side and a fist made its way toward her gut.

“Hueck…”

Zhang Dong’s fist connected with Cuilu Yahui's thin waistline. The woman was a lot smaller than him and her body didn’t seem to be in the possession of a comparable body refining technique as his. She was clearly a cultivator focused on her Qi and control of high-quality treasures. If she was a character in a game then she would be a glass cannon mage. High ability to do damage but no defenses to speak off. It wasn’t that she was weak nor did she underestimate Zhang Dong this much, the difference in skill and power was just this vast.

One punch was all that it took, on the outside, it looked rather anticlimactic. Cuilu Yahui’s body started slumping forward as she started to lose conscience. A small shockwave was produced by the impact and the moment the woman fainted her hold on the swords was gone and they started dropping down to the ground like dead birds.

In reality, the hit wasn’t as simple. It took a lot of Zhang Dong’s spiritual energy to take this woman out with one hit. The moment the concentrated punch landed on her gut he injected his energy into her body. For a fraction of a second two types of spiritual energy started battling for supremacy and his had won. Without her Qi protecting her body she wasn’t much and quickly lost all her fighting capabilities.

“T-the Princess… she lost?”

“How could this be… she is one of the most powerful cultivators of the Empire…”

“Their commander has been defeated by the honorable Golden Dragon, now is our chance, attack with all your might, drive these savages out of our lands!
While the people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire were stunned at the quick loss, the ones from the Heavenly Crane Sect took this chance to fan the flame. Their masters let out a loud battle cry and started pushing as hard as they could. Everyone knew that whenever the strongest fighter from a side fell, then victory was almost assured. It was their chance to take over and it didn’t seem that the enemies had counted in this variable.

“They aren’t retreating even when their morals have dipped? They look afraid… they must really fear their Emperor…”

Zhang Dong placed some Qi-suppressing shackles on the passed-out woman before throwing her into his medallion. Soon after he looked at the faces of his enemies, they looked afraid as if they didn’t want to continue this fight. It was as if someone was holding a spear to their backs.

“Do they think they will be killed if they dare to abandon the fight? So that’s how they run things back at the Emerald Phoenix Empire…”

He had his own way of treating his people and it contained some respect. Here on the other hand it was clear that defeat was not an option, the people fighting here were doing it out of fear. If they retreated they would have probably been treated as deserters and probably killed for it. It was a way of forcing people to remain fighting, it was better to try their luck against their enemies than to return to certain death back home.

This of course didn’t mean that they wouldn’t start retreating and would be quite beneficial to Zhang Dong’s plans. It meant that these troops could not return to their base but instead remain outcasts. Their only way of surviving would be to hide their association with the Emerald Phoenix Empire. As long as they didn’t show up in front of their old leaders there was a chance of living and to some, it was a more reasonable plan than to die here when winning was not an option anymore.

“I… I didn’t come here to die…”

Soon the first Nascent Soul level master from the opposition turned into a wisp of light and started running. Even though the fear of being killed by their leaders was high they didn’t see a way out of this predicament. If they returned they would be done for and if they continued here, either they would be dead or become slaves. For them, a life of a vagabond was still better than whatever they would have to go through when confronting their old masters.

‘I guess this method only works as long as there is someone there to punish them…’

It was very eye-opening to Zhang Dong, he saw the limitations of ruling people through the sword. Perhaps there were some merits in some places but when it came down to it, these people would not sacrifice their lives for a tyrant. His forces on the other hand were more willing in that regard as they had a closer relationship with their fellow sect members and superiors.

This didn’t mean that everyone was willing to desert and each had their own reason. Zhang Dong wouldn’t be surprised if some had some soul-binding contracts placed on them. Others could have had their families back home that would be murdered if it was ever found out that they deserted. Nevertheless, as long as some broke the formation the enemies would crumble away.

He was not part of the Heavenly Crane Sect so he could not order them to be merciful to the people that had massacred their people. They started chasing after the escaping invaders while he focused on taking down the enemy generals and the flying ships. Some of them didn’t need to be destroyed and would be a great augmentation to his own army of automatons. The battle was coming to an end and a victor was obvious but before a total collapse was achieved a voice echoed through the battlefield.

“Forces of the Emerald Phoenix Empire, your Prince orders you to retreat.”

It was a very short announcement but instantly the people that were still frantically fighting for their life started fleeing. All sorts of treasures that aided in escaping were used and the enemy soldiers started scattering in various directions. To his dismay the ships that he wanted to capture started going up in flames while also being thrown in their direction and exploding.

‘So their commander is at least smart enough to conserve his troops to some extent… and he would rather blow up his ships than leave it to use huh?’

The battle had ended and he ordered his army of puppets to not pursue. A lot of them had been damaged and he needed to see if there was some usable material around this battlefield that he could use to restore them. One battle won but others still remained on the horizon and this prince would perhaps be his next opponent.

Chapter 610

“Honorable Golden Dragon, may I ask why that woman is with you?”

“Ah, don’t mind her, she is harmless in the state she is in.”

“Big brother, why have you taken me here.”

“My precious sister, I just need you to tell our generals the plans our father the Emperor had in store for us, also don’t forget to inform them about my own orders.”

“Oh brother, you are so forgetful.”

“This is… mind control?”

“Similar but not quite, she thinks that I’m her brother Cuilu Kong. That man is the current Supreme General of the Emerald Phoenix Empire forces.”

“I see, fascinating.”

The group of faction leaders from the Heavenly Crane Sect was looking at a beautiful woman. She was named Cuilu Yahui and just a few days ago was captured by Zhang Dong in the confrontation between their two armies. It was clear to them that she was under some kind of mind spell as she was treating them as part of her army.

“Hey, are you listening to me?”

‘Remember to play along, call her princess and give her a few bows. She thinks that you are generals from her army that are subservient to her. She told me that they normally put their seniors up on pikes if they are being rude.’

“Y-yes, Princess.”

Zhang Dong sent a hidden message to Sun Shen and the rest of the faction leaders in the room. They were quick to straighten up as they didn’t want to have any part in getting themselves impaled on logs.

‘But Honorable Golden Dragon, how did you achieve this…’

‘Oh, it’s just a little trick I picked up along my travels, she is under an illusion spell, to her we look like the people from her army. I told her that she passed out during the battle and that I as her older brother had managed to slay the horrible Golden Dragon’

‘I see!’

While under his spell it would be impossible for her to catch their hidden conversation. The elders were quite fascinated by this interrogation method that didn’t use any drugs but just showed the person a different version of the world. However Zhang Dong knew that it had its limits, he would need to hire some good actors to play the parts of the prince and the generals if she had a closer relationship with them all.

Luckily the two didn’t seem to interact with each other that much. The other generals that he captured gave him some input on the state of their royal family. They were seen as horrendous spoiled brats with their own power bases. They were rumored to never interact with each other besides in family meetings. It was a stark contrast to the relations his own son and daughter had.

‘So, is this what happens when the parents are not present?’

Zhang Dong was still a new father, he only had a few years under his belt. His five-year disappearance also complicated things and made him lose precious time with his children. On the other hand, the Emerald Phoenix Emperor didn’t seem to treasure the two as much. Even sending them here without any proper supervision and help was already a sign that he wasn’t that perturbed by their fate.

‘That or perhaps his belief in his children is so strong that he thought that they would be able to complete the mission without him? Could it have been some tough love of a parent to teach them a lesson?’

He wasn’t sure and at his current stage of parenting, he was still taking care of pre-teens. It would be hard for him to send his children without their mother being present. The only reason he was willing to go stay away from them like this was all thanks to his system. Otherwise, he would probably be scared that something could happen to them while he was away from the sect.

‘But, these two are already adults, I’ll have to learn to let go in the future…’

The woman he was using to get more information from was actually close to four hundred years old. She might have looked young on the inside but after capturing her he was able to identify her physiological structure thoroughly with the system and his spirit sense. Her brother was supposed to be a hundred years older which would make their father even older. His next enemy was someone at the peak of their power and with a lot of experience to go with it. While he might not have the raw stats like Wang Long he would probably have better battle sense.

‘Well… that or he will be too used to being the top dog and easy to surprise. Maybe one blitz attack will be enough.’

He could only hope that his new opponent would underestimate him as all the others did. The element of surprise was one of his better tactics and in a world filled with old monsters that became too prideful for their own good, it was something that usually gave him an edge.

“F… for the Emerald Phoenix Emperor!”

“Bother, these generals are being rude we should…huh?”

“I think that was enough for now, go back to sleep…”

Zhang Dong snapped his fingers next to the woman’s ear, making her pass out in an instant. She was still a powerful cultivator that could go berserk at any moment. On her wrists were spirit energy-dampening shackles but they could only lower her power to the level of a core formation expert. It would be possible for her to make a run for it if she realized that something was off and he had gotten enough information out of her in this way.

“What will you do with her Golden Dragon?”

“Nothing, for now, was planning to use her as a bargaining chip, perhaps her family is sentimental enough to back off into their own empire.”

“The chances of that being are…”

“Yes, probably very low, when I was playing her brother she was always on edge, she doesn’t show it with that haughty attitude but in reality, her fear was almost palpable. It was the same whenever the Emperor was mentioned.”

“Yes, her heartbeat did increase whenever she mentioned her father…”

The other nascent soul masters here used their own spiritual sense and techniques to see if the woman wasn’t lying. Some of them even got into the role quite well while others like leader Zhong continued to be awkward and disgruntled. However thanks to this act they all heard some good information about their new enemy.

“Yes and also this, Prince Cuilu Kong will be the next opponent if they don’t agree on the trade.”

“Well, about that trade… think it won’t be happening…”

“Honorable golden dragon?”

“I did send one of my puppets to send a message to their leader but it seems they have destroyed it instead but it’s better if I just show you.”

Zhang Dong wanted to speed things up so coming here was just a little presentation. He had already heard the woman out and knew about everything. A few of his angel puppets were sent out to meet with their leaders and send them a message. However, before they could actually discuss things the automaton was destroyed. This was quite unexpected as he expected the man to at least hear them out, maybe even a trade could occur. While they wouldn’t turn back, perhaps some of the enslaved citizens from the Azure Dragon Empire could be set free.

“So that’s, Cuilu Kong?”

“Yes, he does look like someone that would let his sister die…”

“Those eyes have no mercy in them…”

A small holographic image of the last few minutes of the puppet's life was played in front of the people gathered here. There wasn’t really much as it arrived at what looked like a massive throne room with one man sitting on the end. The pre-recorded voice of Zhang Dong played informing the man of his sister’s capture. Right as the part with the demands was about to play the puppet’s main camera started flying through the air. Someone in the room had cleanly sliced it off and the last part it captured was the Prince’s foot crushing its head.

“I think he is the type to not negotiate with terrorists.”

“Terrorists, Golden Dragon?”

“Ah, just ignore that, think we need to prepare for the next encounter, I don’t think they will just rush into combat now after losing so many people and equipment.”

Zhang Dong nervously coughed into his hand after his joke fell on deaf ears. It was clear that the man didn’t want to hear any of it and was probably already preparing a counter-offensive. It wouldn’t be strange that even if they tried using the princess as a human shield the enemies would just ignore that fact.

“Hm, I don’t think we can use that woman as a bargaining chip.”

“Leader Shen might be right but we can’t discount the enemies just trying to disorient us.”

“It could have been just for show, you mean? Hm… I’m not sure if that’s possible, for all he knows we could have instantly killed her just for that.”

“That might be true but…”

“Don’t worry, I’m not going to kill her. Perhaps they think that she is already dead or something, it's worth a shot but we shouldn’t base our tactics on this point anymore.”

Everyone in the tent nodded. They needed to account for all the options, perhaps the Prince would get a bit more sentimental over his sister if she shows up on the battlefield. Zhang Dong didn’t want to become the villain of the story but people's lives were at stake and even if he would dangle her as a damsel in distress he would not endanger her life. This was probably more than his enemies would give him but he was not someone that killed off prisoners of war. After everything was over they would serve their time and depending on their sins, be released.

“Well then my friends, we have more work to do, I don’t think that our enemies will try to assemble another regiment to get here, instead they will probably retreat.”

“We confirmed this with the map you supplied us, some of their scattered forces have started retreating towards the outer regions, just where the bridge to their Empire is located.”

“Hm… this will become harder but in my opinion, it would be better to cut off the head of a weakened tiger before the dragon appears.”
Zhang Dong knew that if he didn’t push now then the Emerald Phoenix Emperor would surely appear. The only problem was that he was cooperating with people that weren’t so keen on battling it out. They were not desperate enough to see the bigger picture and after the recent victory were content on resting their troops before the next engagement. It was now up to him to either convince them otherwise or face his enemies alone yet again.

Chapter 611

‘This went better than I expected, normally they would try to debate the issue for at least another week, I guess when it comes to actual war they know to strike the iron when it’s hot.’

Zhang Dong stepped out from a large tent that was moved onto a new flagship. It was sent out by the Heavenly Crane Sect and was flying next to some of the acquisition battleships of the enemy. Their talks have ended and the Heavenly Crane Sect had decided to make a push for it. It was clear that their motives were not pure but as long as the empire was clear of any invaders, it was fine.

‘I just need to be careful, calling over for some backup when the time comes won’t be such a bad idea either…’

“How does it look, has their Empress made a move yet?”

“No Patriarch, we are fighting the same exact waves of enemies, their strength doesn’t seem to be increasing either but…”

“Is there a problem?”

“Yes, we noticed that while their forces remain the same, the intervals between the attacks have become slightly longer.”

“I guess they reached a plateau and their resources might be running out… good, I might have to pull you to my side, be ready for anything.”

“Of course, Patriarch, the United Element Sect will always be with you!”

“Haha, that’s good, talk to you later Zhang Zhi.”

Zhang Dong cut the connection to his own general that was still out north and fighting against the fish people. There was a possibility for the Cerulean Empress to appear but for the time being, it was a repeating wave of fish monsters and clones. It was a true grindfest meant for the system holder to gather enough spirit points.

‘Zhi said that they are getting slower with the counter-attacks, this grind spot will probably dry out soon enough…’

It was clear to him that this world didn’t possess infinite resources. The northern Cerulean Empire could have been set up as a spirit point farm but it probably had its limits. Perhaps if he allowed them to invade their lands to get some resources back it would last for longer but that was not something he would do.

The Cerulean Empress might start making new moves if she starts running out of soldiers but that also wasn’t set in stone. She was strangely passive when it came to showing herself, instead only cloned generals and troops made up of sea creatures appeared. It wouldn’t be strange if after these armies all fell she would actually not appear. Perhaps she was a stationary boss that never moved from their initial base. The defenses would probably be quite hard to get through but it also gave Zhang Dong enough time to clear out the eastern side first.

“Well then, I should check up on my other friends.”

After taking flight he started moving towards a ship that looked like a floating Spanish galleon. It was much bigger than the counterpart from his world and had a knightly crest of a lion on its sails. Even though it was larger than most galleons, its size was only a fifth of the flagship he just left. The owner of this ship spotted him floating towards and didn’t even offer up a smile to greet him.

“Zhang Dong.”

“Lucius”

It was a flying vessel from the magical kingdom, the knights that were gathered there didn’t appreciate the way he didn’t speak out Lucius’ noble title but couldn’t really say anything about it. If a fight broke loose they knew that Zhang Dong would probably be victorious or at least that their victory would be a hard-fought one.

“How long will this take?”

“I’m not sure, if we are lucky we might be able to drive them back after that Prince is gone.”

“What if we are not?”

“Then… I’m not sure either but it would be better if their Emperor is kept from entering this side, then I’ll just have my troops block of the bridge and it will be done… hey stop looking at me like that, you’ll get your shield after, I made you an oath and I’m going to keep it.”

“Hmph…”

“You’re such a tsundere…”

“What?”

“Nothing.”

There wasn’t much he came here to say and spending more time would only annoy the Duke even more. After relaying the plan of pushing towards the eastern side their meeting was concluded and the war was resumed. The following few days were quite boring as the enemy forces were on a path of retreat.

‘That guy is trying to send a message…’

It wasn’t long until they arrived at the first big settlement or at least what was left of it. One of the large cities that previously contained millions of people was not burning before them. It was one of the war tactics used, burning everything so the enemy couldn’t gain back their lost resources and lands. Everything was being destroyed by the retreating forces and Zhang Dong was unable to arrive in time to help.

This was the first time he was in these lands and splitting away from the forces was not a good idea. It wouldn’t be strange if his new enemy was a crafty one, doing such things was meant to anger his side. People from the Heavenly Crane Sect were enraged at the loss of life but he wasn’t sure if they were more concerned that this made them look bad. If cities under their name were eradicated from existence together with the people living there, then would put them in a bad light.

There was nothing there, the only thing in the air was a large amount of residue energy from Qi. Massive amounts of it were just shot everywhere but it seemed that life did find a way as hidden beneath rubble and sand there were some survivors. Perhaps this was done on purpose or just showed that they didn’t have enough time for everything while evacuating.

‘I can’t just leave them to die…’

Zhang Dong had charged in front of the rest of the army and acted like a scout. His morals wouldn’t allow him to abandon these people but this would slow their approach. Perhaps their enemy was counting on this. Even as he was using his spiritual energy to raise up the rubble and pull out injured people he was looking around for an ambush. When scanning the area he could see small pockets of people trapped underground, some were in the process of drawing their last breath.

‘I can’t do this alone…’

The city they were in was huge, ten million citizens had lived here before and now only a few thousand were scattered everywhere. The Emerald Phoenix Empire or in this case the Prince Cuilu Kong, didn’t seem to have a conscience. To allow this much carnage and wanton destruction to occur a certain idea had to have taken over his mind. He must have seen himself as someone superior, as a god among humans to be okay with such atrocities.

Perhaps he was even worse than Wang Long, who convinced himself that the people living in this world were NPCs and not actual intelligent beings. He was someone that lived in this world for long enough to know better. This only made him angrier at the part that he played in all of this. Even though he knew that he didn’t really have anything to do with their deaths, perhaps if he had taken things slower more people could have survived.

“What are you doing, do we really have time for this?”

“Lucius? Don’t just stand there and tell your people to help me you know healing magic.”

The whole army was stopped as they saw Zhang Dong’s puppets flying around and taking injured people to the side. Lucius and his knights were the first to descend to ask about what he was doing. In their eyes, this was still a battleground and it was unwise to leave yourself open to an attack.

“You should leave this to your servants, this is no place for a leader.”

“No place for a leader, huh? Want me to remain as some sort of radiant symbol that appears when the time is right or something? If you don’t want to help then it’s fine, continue with the chase, my puppets will still assist you and I can always get there when I’m needed”

The Duke nodded his head but to Zhang Dong’s surprise instead of just leaving he actually called some of his men over. A bunch of knights wearing silver armor along with people that looked like servants started aiding the injured people. He did not expect them to actually listen to his proposal but more help was always welcome.

Time was being wasted but most of the army continued with their chase while he remained here to establish a teleportation gate. His own sect was mostly up in the north but that didn’t mean that he couldn’t activate some of his own medical staff. His sect was quite content in their healing and regenerative arts. The medallion around his neck wasn’t the only one they made and it would aid in evacuating everyone here.

After giving his people some orders he finally decided to join back with the main army that had actually encountered some resistance on the way. The small skirmishes were all won but there were far too many for them to not be a distraction. At strategic locations, they would be attacked and stalled for as long as humanly possible. Then the attackers would either flee or fight to the last man.

They would even perform a strange suicide art that left their bodies exploding like bombs, it was clear to him from that point that this Prince was stalling them. This became more apparent the further they advanced into the lands that the Heavenly Crane Sect once owned. There was nothing left for them to gain there besides more injured people that needed rescuing. What the Emerald Phoenix prince was up to still remained to be seen but it wouldn’t be strange if he was waiting for some backup to arrive.

Chapter 612

‘This isn’t as easy as I expected, they decided to fortify themselves here…’

Zhang Dong looked at the volleys of spiritual cannon fire going back and forth between the two armies. One was composed mostly of flying ships and attacking formations while the other was a fortress. This time around he was the one performing the siege while the people from the Emerald Phoenix Empire were on the defensive.

“Everything is going according to our plan, Golden Dragon, we should be able to crush them in but a few months!”

“A few months, huh?”

“Yes!”

He looked towards Leader Shen and the other big wigs from the Heavenly Crane Sect. More of them had appeared, bringing the number up to six of the leaders being there. It seemed that they were becoming more and more convinced of their victory. The invaders that murdered their people were on the retreat and they were even able to capture some of them to gain more resources.

“I hope you are right Sun Shen.”

“Is there something troubling you, honorable Golden Dragon?”

“I’m not sure yet, I’ll let you know if I find some proof, for now, remain vigilant.”

“We will.”

The elders clasped their hands at him while he decided to fly over to his own army of puppets that had managed to be expanded in scope. Even though the enemy combatants went through the trouble of destroying everything, metals and materials for his factory couldn’t be damaged that easily. Whatever he could use to create more of these automatons to help the refugees were taken in. Even though he had to make weaker medical units they weren’t meant for combat and allowed him to resume the offensive.

While they were starting to win he couldn’t help but think that there was something wrong. They went through some reinforced cities and even came across Saint Emperor generals. Usually, a commander would not throw away their troops so wantonly. He expected to be stalled by a skeletal army with maybe a few treasured items to back them up. Instead they were fighting full regiments not much weaker than the one the Princess arrived with.

‘There could be an easy explanation for this but usually, they don’t catch on this fast…’

There was one main reason that they were able to continue to push back into the eastern regions and that reason was called Zhang Dong. Without him around the Heavenly Crane Sect would be quite equal to the other troops composed of Saint Emperor, Martial Saints, and Supreme Saints. He always went for the strongest fighter in the group while everyone else had an easy time against weaker opponents.

Normally people like the Prince would gather all their forces in an attempt to drive him back. At that moment he would let his allies stall the others while he contended with their leader and some of their most powerful aids. He always took out the heads of the hydra and left the rotting body to his allies. Now on the other hand they were slowly cutting off the heads one by one. This probably left the main body some time to regenerate its head with perhaps an even stronger one.

‘Is this guy actually wise enough to see that he wouldn’t be able to beat me in a fair battle or even in one skewed in his direction? This does require some knowledge or he might be scheming something else…’

After capturing the Princess he had some idea about what kind of a man this Prince was. From her point of view, he was a schemer but he could also be something else, a coward. The two didn’t exclude each other and it was possible that after the easy defeat of the sister, the prince decided that the juice was not worth the squeeze. He was an old monster at the ripe age of half a millennium. Perhaps he was dead set on living out the second half of it and facing Zhang Dong would not be the brightest idea.

‘Asking for reinforcements would be the smart choice but these cultivator types usually try not to do anything that would make them look weak…’

His expectation was for the Prince to not call for the Emperor’s help. It would make him look like a weakling that could not do anything without his parent around. This move would however be the correct one if he measured Zhang Dong’s power to be at the same level as their emperor. He would certainly not be able to win in a direct confrontation thus these stalling tactics were probably meant for this.

‘Shit… it would be nice if I didn’t have to face any more of those guys and he might not even be the one that I need to watch out for.’

Perhaps the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was not as strong as the Demi-Human Emperor but there was a difference between the two, one of them had a more organized army. Zhang Dong felt that even if this leader were to perish or run he would still have a fully functional army to contend with here. They were made up of other cultivators from many smaller sects, it wouldn’t be strange for them to scatter or join the Prince faction to spread chaos through the lands.

He was not sure if he did the right thing now. Perhaps if he had gone with a more quiet approach things wouldn’t be escalating this fast. His assumption of the cultivator's hubris working against them was probably wrong. With them running back to their fortress things would become a lot harder. At least when he was fighting the demi-human’s their numbers were quite low and concentrated. They might have been the weakest of all the enemies he was to face with the exception of Lucius and his people.

This didn’t mean that he did the wrong thing. If the plan was altered then more of the Heavenly Crane Sect cities would have been captured in the time he took in investigating the eastern region. It would take time for him to sneak up and prepare the teleportation gate for his own forces to arrive. With how the northern region was becoming harder to predict the more time he spent the more lives would be lost.

‘Should I toss out safety and go for it? How many troops did they leave to keep us here and when will their reinforcements arrive?’

Time was running out, the longer this war continued the more likely it was for the last boss to arrive. There were two options that he had, either he continued at this pace and slowly helped the Heavenly Crane Sect to push back their defense line. His power was still limited, there was no way of him just charging there and defeating everyone by himself. If that was possible then he wouldn’t have had to seek help from Lucius and the Heavenly Crane Sect.

‘If I fail, it will be over for everyone involved…’

He could only grit his teeth and set out into the battlefield. Instead of doing a maddened push by himself, he decided to keep with the current slow and steady approach. Even if the Emerald Phoenix Emperor arrived it wouldn’t pose a problem to him, that was what he truly believed. The Prince that decided to retreat was probably still underestimating his power or had another plan in motion that he couldn’t entirely dismiss.

…

“So these are the promised lands?”

“Yes, my Emperor!”

“The spiritual energy is indeed refreshing but besides that, it’s a shit hole of nothing… were my stupid son and daughter really that inept?”

“Y-yes, my Emperor!”

An awkward silence filled the large room where a bunch of Saint Emperors were standing around. In the middle, there was a giant throne veiled in mystery. A figure of a somewhat thin man was radiating a greenish light while he was talking but his form could not be seen by anyone in this huge chamber. In front of the throne was a giant window through which everyone could see the massive lands before them.

“Can someone give me an answer, why do I the Emerald Phoenix Emperor have to be dragged here to clean up after those two brats? Did I not give them enough? Were their masters inept at teaching? The pills and elixirs that they devoured cost a fortune and this is all that they amount to!”

A surge of ferocious Qi filled the entire chamber. The Saint Emperors that could easily be masters of their own large-scale sects fell to their knees. Their hands started clutching at their hearts which were close to bursting out of their chests. Their Emperor was enraged and they could not muster up even one word when under this much pressure.

“I have paved the path for those ungrateful brats, bring them over now, where is my useless son now?”

“P… please E-emperor…”

Even though the people wanted to reply they could not. The magnificent window that was presenting the lush forests and mountains outside started cracking before finally bursting into millions of tiny pieces. What should have been able to last through an assault from Saint Emperors could not resist the angered man’s aura.

“Hoh… I might have lost myself a bit there, Ho ho ho… I’ve become irritable in my old years, this is unbecoming of an Emperor.”

Soon the anger turned into laughing which made the Phoenix Emperor Sound like a jolly old man. No one besides him was laughing though, they were only glad that they weren’t getting squished into the ground anymore by their enraged leader that had been losing it due to his advanced age. They knew that he had already reached an age that shouldn’t normally be possible but no one was certain how.

“Now then, where is my son? You there, answer me!”

“Yes my Emperor, The Prince is already waiting for you at the nearby palace, it had been created in the image of the capital…”

“Ah, yes… it does look like that shitty palace… quite the eyesore it is, so wasteful, maybe if he invested that in the army he wouldn’t have failed…”

“Yes, Emperor…”

A scared Saint Emperor general continued to nod while hoping that his life was spared. Neither the Emperor nor his son was simple and most people considered both to be worse than the other. They could only show fake smiles and continue with the charade while the old man went on another rant about his useless children. The Emperor was finally here and everyone knew that things would become difficult for anyone that opposed him.

Chapter 613

‘I was too slow…’

Zhang Dong had to stop his push into the enemy defensive line to take a look at his map. There he saw a large red dot appearing right at the edge of the empire. It was coming right out of the bridge between worlds and belonged to the person he hoped to avoid. The map detected Qi signatures in the whole empire and this one was the largest he had seen.

‘I couldn’t see Wang Long’s Qi on the map so this doesn’t have to mean that this guy is stronger but it might not be an easy fight.’

It was certainly true that when he compared this area it was radiating more power than the Demi-Human Emperor did. It wasn’t certain that all this spiritual energy was just coming from the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. It was possible that there were a lot of powerful experts around him or that some beasts were there. Perhaps he was in possession of a powerful treasure that didn’t necessarily have to have battle use, just like the immortal-level dimensional regalia he came in contact with.

‘I guess there is no use to rush now, I should have a talk with my allies about this and prepare for the last battle.’

Zhang Dong had no time to mope about his first plan going up in flames. Perhaps if he pushed it hard into the eastern region while ignoring all the destruction it would have been possible. Though, when he considered the time it took for the Emperor to arrive, it made it seem that he wouldn’t make it anyway. The Prince had decided to retreat quite fast which would force him to face more than he wanted.

‘They lost a lot of troops during the escape, it wouldn’t be strange if that little prince sacrificed more than half of his troops for this stunt. Is he that much of a coward or is he planning something?’

Without meeting with the man he couldn’t really make a good assessment of his character. His sister was transported into his own sect and was stripped of her cultivation level. After it became clear that she could not really be used as a bargaining chip, there was no use keeping her as a potential threat. Without her power, she would not live for that much longer. Her age was rapidly increasing and it was clear that her beauty was artificially kept up with some beauty elixirs.

It was quite disheartening to see a sister be abandoned by her brother but Zhang Dong wasn’t sure if the siblings had been corrupted by their circumstances. Their father was the leader of the whole empire and in their childhood, they had been fed information in a peculiar way. They never interacted with each other and were considered to be special. Maybe it was not that somewhere along the way they became monsters but had been brought up as ones from the start. He could only see this as a warning and not have his children follow suit.

“Honorable Golden Dragon.”

“Patriarch Guan, it’s good to see you and the guardians too.”

“Yes, we couldn’t leave all the glory to you, these are our lands and we will recapture them.”

Zhang Dong smiled after seeing Tao Guan. The Patriarch had finally decided to move on his own accord. In the Heavenly Crane Sect’s eyes, victory was right around the corner. They had managed to push all of the enemy forces back toward a small region. Before them was the citadel in which they would receive their rewards.

‘It would be nice if they did this for something else than just fame and fortune, still this is better than not having any help.’

He didn’t fool himself into believing that these people were doing all of this out of the goodness of their hearts. It was also clear that their perception of his motives was the same. It wouldn’t be strange if, after the final battle, they would actually betray him in some sense. If he was at death's door they might even be inclined to present him with the last hit. They would just have to explain to his brother that he died during the confrontation with the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and died as a hero protecting the lands.

Things like this were quite common in the cultivation world. Every alliance was razor thin and whenever a side was on top they could change the details of their contract. No one could be trusted in this world and this was a reality he had to accept for now. The other side was probably thinking the same, if they were weakened then they would be up for the taking by Zhang Dong and his sect.

“Haha, that’s good to hear, the enemy will surely be close to breaking apart.”

“Yes but their fortifications aren’t simple, we haven’t been able to continue at our usual pace. The ships are continuously firing but those shields aren't going down.”

“You are right, Patriarch Guan. But as long as we get those down we should be able to surround their main base, after it falls it should be over.”

“That is true but I need to ask you, are you confident?”

“Confident in defeating their Emperor?”

“Yes…”

“It shouldn’t be a problem.”

Zhang Dong shrugged while playing it off as child’s play. He needed to remain confident and not show that there was even a possibility of defeat. These people from the Heavenly Crane Sect were very skittish. If they were even ten percent uncertain of their victory they would instantly pull out their troops. It wouldn’t be strange if they even abandoned him during the final battle if they saw no way out of it. Luckily for him, after so many victories they were convinced that he was at the level of the Azure Emperor.

“Glad to hear that, I will join my sect members now, if you wish to discuss something…”

“Sure, I’ll let you know, first let us just get through this protective shielding without wasting too many resources.”

Both Tao Guan and Zhang Dong parted ways. He could see the two guardians looking at him funny as if they wanted a rematch. The enemy had set up strange tower-shaped markers that produced a huge protective shield that went up into the stratosphere. Usually, a barrier was in the shape of a dome but this one just went straight up.

In this world, there was some type of force that didn’t allow even a nascent soul master to go past a certain threshold. Besides spiritual energy thinking out the higher a person flew, there was no air and some kind of strange pulling force that wouldn’t allow a cultivator to leave.

From Zhang Dong’s perspective, it was a safeguard put in by whoever made this planet. It didn’t allow anyone to see it from a high enough vantage point to spot the other empires. If they could leave the atmosphere of the planet it would also be possible to circumvent the bridges between the various empires. It wouldn’t be strange if only a being at the immortal level would be able to break through these shackles.

‘At this point, I wouldn’t even be surprised if we weren’t on a planet but in some kind of huge fake dimension…’

While looking at his replica medallion he was reminded of the huge space in the original. The area in that one was almost as big as the planet he came from but it was not round in shape. It was just a massive chunk of land floating in nothingness and it continued to increase in size with more energy being fed into it.

This could be the same for this world, with the only difference being the scale. If a being of power wanted to make a new world it could conserve energy in this fashion. Otherwise, there would be a need to create a solar system with a working star and other planets around it. If they just put everything on a floating island and divided it with some magical barriers, it would save a lot of resources.

It was not possible to scale these walls as they were out of reach of anyone. The triangle-shaped monoliths looked like they were actually not transported here. Instead, it seemed that they rose out of the ground as if they had been placed here beforehand.

‘Could it be a safe zone established for them to make this last longer?’

This shield was quite sturdy and it was possible to rip a hole for a moment to get through. If a person wanted to have a whole army to travel through it complicated things. When looking at this forcefield it made it seem like it was meant to keep armies out but let strong cultivators through. It would be certainly possible for him to power through it in one quick burst of energy but it would be draining.

At the moment he wanted to conserve his power for the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. Pushing in through the front door by himself was now off the table. This time around sneaking in to place some traps and maybe encountering the prince and princess would have been the better option. As it stood now, he had activated the last boss of this questline and he would have to take care of it the hard way.

‘How does it look back there?’

‘Patriarch, as you ordered we have pulled our troops back after the last wave of enemy troops has been defeated.’

‘Good, if they appear again, let them push in a bit while you conserve your strength, have the palace move back towards the mainland, and wait.’

‘Yes Patriarch but how will we make it in time?’

Zhang Zhi asked while being a bit confused. Zhang Dong had ordered everyone to stand down and get ready for a potential attack in the eastern region. The only problem was that if they wanted to get the Golden Dong Palace there, it would take several weeks as it was not a very mobile fortress. Due to the focus on being a defensive bastion, it wasn’t very good when it came to speed.

‘Oh, don’t worry about it, remember how we got it during the Wang Long pursuit?’

‘Yes!’

‘It took some time but I made my preparation, so just be ready to fight some cultivators, have the troops look through the battle records.’

‘Yes, Patriarch!’

During his travels, he was sure to have the puppets record all of the battles they had. With the data, he could have his soldiers ready for when the time came. His main plan was to take care of it with the help of the Heavenly Crane Sect but it wouldn’t be wrong to have a backup plan when things went sour…

Chapter 614

‘It’s really strange that they don’t seem to be interested in any of my recent moves…’

Zhang Dong looked at the huge army and flying ships that were almost through the protective shielding. He could see one of the pointy towers generating it starting to crack. At the moment he wasn’t thinking about the Emerald Phoenix Emperor that had probably arrived but his counterpart the Azure Emperor. Ever since his encounter with his wife, there had been radio silence.

Even when he continued to push to the north and then to the south no one from the Long Clan came to complain. It was as if they checked out of this war between nations or that they were busy with something else.

‘Could they be preparing to swoop in and take out the victor? That’s not a bad strategy but would they attack my sect with no warning?’

The Long Clan and their leader could not be just ignored. Zhang Dong was pushing hard into the eastern front because he wanted to finish everything before more people were hurt. It would have been quite easy to just rest his forces and bunker up in the western region.

The demi-human scourge had been defeated and without a new Emperor, they would be busy with their own politics now. Unless a strong leader appeared he didn’t feel like they would muster enough forces to attempt a crossing through the bridge. Going against someone that managed to defeat their undefeated leader was not the smartest idea.

Hundred years was a lot for someone that spent his life in the modern world. Even though Zhang Dong had achieved a lifespan of a thousand years he had not really partaken in this longevity. His time in this world didn’t even go over ten years. To him waiting for so long was quite a bit and the number of people that would die if he didn’t act kept him up at night.

It was the right thing to do but maybe not the best thing if he considered his own people that had already gone through a lot of hardship. As he was looking at the bursts of spiritual energy colliding with the shield he kept thinking about it all. Was it right to endanger the people that believed in him? Why should they be forced by him to partake in this fight that they could avoid?

As it stood he believed that even if the Emerald Phoenix Emperor continued he would probably not be well-equipped to take on the western lands. While the Heavenly Crane Sect would probably fall they would take some time to dominate their lands before probably pushing toward the center where the Long Clan was.

Perhaps the Azure Emperor would not be able to defend himself alone but at that moment he could lend him some help. Apparently, they had some kind of super weapon that the two dragons could operate together. It might be enough to defeat their forces and clear everything up without the western region even getting involved.

If he considered himself as the Western Emperor then perhaps he would be inclined to do that but the Empire was much larger. As it stood now, some people actually liked him more than the previous Emperor that had done nothing to aid anyone. It was not the Azure Dragon that was liberating the lands but the Golden Dragon. Some even started whispering of a new Golden Emperor arising if the war in the east was won by him.

He was not deaf to these rumors and they somewhat made sense. If Zhang Dong managed to help the Heavenly Crane Sect win this war, then from people looking from the outside, they would be considered sworn allies. The scale would be tipped in favor of the United Element’s Sect as it was already part of the big three.

The Soaring Dragon Sect that had previously been in that position could never find common ground with the Heavenly Crane Sect to go against the Azure Emperor. People believed that if two factions decided to work together with each other, then even the Azure Emperor would not be able to stop them. Thus it would be strange if the Long Clan was part of that side and didn’t try to somehow intervene, that is if the overseer didn’t exist.

It was possible that the Empress was somehow keeping everyone from acting. If she was there to keep the scenario running it made somewhat sense. The Long Clan felt like they were allies meant for anyone with the system. They safeguarded the Golden Dong Palace for him and perhaps were never meant to be a roadblock for him. They were very passive in keeping to themselves in the center of the empire and had some sort of way of preserving themselves even if the whole palace was overrun.

‘There is one way of lasting out without people being able to reach you…’

Zhang Dong looked up into the sky where the large barrier was flickering. It was close to breaking and he needed to push his thoughts back and get ready. The map that he acquired from the Long Clan continued to give him a strategic advantage. They already knew that the Emerald Phoenix Emperor remained stationary due to the large red dot remaining close to the bridge.

“The defensive barrier is wavering, concentrate on the large monoliths and take them under our control”

He could hear leader Zhong Shouting at his people as it was time to battle once more. The barrier was quite powerful due to one reason, it didn’t allow the defenders to go through it either. Usually, the Qi signature was aligned with the cannons on the side of the defenders. This weakened the barrier structure slightly and made it less powerful. This one on the other hand had just one purpose and that was to be a defensive stopping point.

Finally, after it was about to flicker out of existence the enemy troops started firing back. Many cultivators were gathered at the giant spires in hopes of repairing them. It would be a fight for time, could they destroy the barrier mechanism or would they be pushed back by the other army?

“They really have the manpower on their side, didn’t expect them to have this many soldiers and masters left behind… if they gathered all of them at the start…”

It was strange to see this many enemy soldiers still left. They just kept coming like there was no end to them. He had seen a red fog moving from their main base on the map to bolster the defenses. They had been on standby and now after the field of spiritual energy was broken, they started fighting back.

“They must have not expected us to drive them back this fast, it seems natural considering the lower regions not having the best defenses.”

“Mhm.”

Sun Shen was with him and the two were floating in the air close to some of the battleships that were moving in. It seemed that these forces were part of the Prince's entourage. It would make sense that when the Emperor arrived with the true army they would have been discarded to act as a wedge to keep Zhang Dong busy.

“I’ll join with the troop, I can sense some strong masters among them.”

“Strong masters? Could that cowardly prince be among them?”

“I don’t think so, he might have retreated to his fathers side.”

“For a future emperor, that man is quite gutless.”

“Perhaps he is but I wouldn’t be surprised if he wasn’t planning something, his sister wasn’t weak, it would be better if we didn’t underestimate him when the time comes.”

“As always the honorable golden dragon gives wise advice.”

Sun Shen clasped his hands and the two parted ways. Zhang Dong joined his army of angelic puppets that acted as the main attacking force and the faction leader from the Heavenly Crane Sect ordered his forces to push after them. The lifeless automatons were perfect at taking the initial hits and even if they were damaged after gathering all the scrap metal from the surroundings, it was easy to repair them.

Thus their push continued, and the large defensive structures were quickly swarmed by the metallic angels. The soldiers stationed there did their utmost at defending but without the help of their powerful masters that were being kept busy by Zhang Dong, they were not able to defend their position.

After one of the monoliths fell under their control it was finally safe to have their flying armies push in. Soon enough the second one was also secured and the path was clear. Their troops received some minor damage here and there but their progress could not be stopped, certainly not while Zhang Dong was there to tower over everyone.

With his aura spread in all directions and their strongest masters incapable of beating him, victory was assured from the start. It was a truth in this world led by the minority of powerful cultivators, one person could decide the faith of many.

‘They really don’t have any intention of surrendering, their fear of the Emperor must be tremendous…’

A common sight was before him, even when he shouted out that they could be spared no one reacted. The mangled troops that were being showered in spiritual energy were unwilling to back off. It was as if they had a sword at their throat that would slide their necks open if they dared to back off.

After spending some time out on the battlefield and comparing it to the way his own sect members looked, he knew that this was different. His people had a sort of passion in their looks, even when he wasn’t there they were fighting not with desperation but with hope in their eyes. There was no hope in these people's gazes though, it was just desperation.

‘The interrogations confirmed this already but seeing this so close… I need to end this fast and not only for my people's safety but also for theirs…’

This desperation could only arise due to bad leadership. He already knew that these people were terrified of the Emperor and what he would do to them and their families. In one way or another the soldiers were coerced into abiding, they would either lose their life if they failed or their families would be in jeopardy. To end this cycle of carnage he would need to push forth towards his confrontation with the Emperor.

Chapter 615

“You are a disappointment.”

“Forgive me, father, I…”

“I didn’t allow you to speak. So, pathetic, you left your sister to die and retreated by yourself. This might have been the best choice considering what you were against but you should have been able ”

“Y-yes…”

In a large throne room surrounded by many guards that were all experts at Saint Emperor level a sound echoed. The Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s old palm connected with the Prince’s face while he was kneeling down. No one dared to utter a word while seeing this exchange between probably the two most influential people in their empire.

Now that the Princess was gone, Cuilu Kong had become the prime candidate for the throne. Everyone knew that the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was in the twilight days of his life. Regretfully for his son, this secret space had opened up in their lifetime and the order came to put his life on the line for victory. The prince was known for not taking any risks, and when he encountered someone who could defeat his sister in single combat, he decided to run.

While Cuilu Kong was the crown prince it didn’t mean that he was the only one that could take on that role. Other branch families and even the Prince’s own children could fill out that role if he lost his life here. The Emerald Phoenix Emperor had no siblings left; after taking the throne, he promptly dealt with any opposition. Everyone was at least certain that the whole empire would become really busy after his demise and that the rivers would flow with blood.

People were getting ready for a war, the factions had already been formed and this venture that appeared only once every hundred thousand years was also calculated. Many young emperors had perished inside it but some were also victorious. The current line of nobility had survived ever since they had been victorious and brought back various resources. Cultivating in this domain was known to boost spiritual energy to an extreme. Even the Emerald Phoenix Emperor looked a bit more lively. In the past, he would probably have someone else strike his son but after arriving here he was becoming active again.

“Now… I can feel that someone strong is approaching… but this place… it truly is fascinating, I feel a hundred years younger, I must absorb more of this spiritual energy!”

The old man that usually kept his face hidden started standing up from his throne. His visage was revealed once again to everyone, even though he was moving and saying that he felt invigorated, his appearance was less than stellar. He was nothing more than a lanky bag of bones with a long white beard and lack of hair. Only thanks to his large hat and long robes was he able to hide most of his weak features.

However, there was some kind of change, with a wave of his hand the huge glass window that was in front of them shattered into many tiny pieces. The old man that looked like a corpse flew up into the sky, the long emerald phoenix pattern on his robe continued to flutter in the wind while everyone watched. They weren’t sure what he was doing but soon they realized as the amount of Qi in the vicinity started to drop.

They were all experienced cultivators and could feel all the energy rushing in the direction of their leader. He was eating it all up, all of what was in the air in a radius of several kilometers around them was being sucked up by the emperor. The Qi turned into tiny balls of pale light which started turning green when they appeared next to the old Emperor’s body.

“More… I need more… bring me all of those herbs and pills, I need more!”

His voice which was normally quite silent started booming through the entire fortress. People started scrambling almost instantly to the warehouses where they had stored all of the spiritual herbs and pills they stole from the natives. Even before bringing them over all of these items started floating up as they were drawn into the small black hole the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was producing.

People started dropping down to their knees soon after. While the energy was being sucked up by their Emperor it still was there. Soon the concentration was making it hard for them to breathe as their leader didn’t do anything to protect them. Only thanks to all the generals that were present were the lesser cultivators able to survive through this ordeal.

“Hah… if I knew it was like this, I would have never told my useless son and daughter to come here.”

Soon the sound of the Emperor’s laugh was heard by everyone. The ones that glanced up were greeted by a green glow. This aura of spiritual excellence was brought forth by a flame that was gently spinning around the man’s frame. Muscles and a healthy complexion replaced the previously lanky appearance. This man that looked like he would die when hit by a breeze now looked mighty and ready for any challenge.

“Hm…”

Yet after getting a good laugh the Emperor calmed down, the energy that surrounded him started to thin out once more. It was as if he had a problem in containing all this might and of this, he was aware. Without saying anything the radiant emerald glow died down and he descended down to the ground.

Even though he was now containing the new gained power inside of his body, the experts that were around here knew that it was only a temporary boost. All of them had gone through a similar intoxication with their newfound energy but it also had its limits. In the case of the old emperor, it wouldn’t last as long due to his advanced age. There was no way of beating time, nevertheless he had gained some by coming here and his old power had been restored. With their leader in such a state there was no reason to believe that their enemies would be able to defeat them.

“Unwelcome guests are coming… one of them… how interesting…”

After mumbling some words to himself the old emperor returned to his previous throne room. It was time to face his new opponent which had appeared before him. The other generals and masters knew this well, their enemies were done taking care of the remnants of Cuilu Kong’s forces. They would soon appear here to lay siege to their fortress but with the Emerald Phoenix Emperor being here, they knew that their enemies stood no chance.

People started cheering at the display of power, after weeks of nothing but losses they knew that victory was at their fingertips. Not everyone was glad, there was one person that wasn’t looking at the Emperor with reverence but with disgust. His face was somewhat similar to the man that had regained some of his lost youth.

“Engorge yourself in this moment of glory, it will be short-lived…”

Soon he vanished into the shadows without anyone being the wiser. With so much happening around them and the enemy army quickly approaching there was just no time for anyone to pay attention. Soon the gong resounded through the encampment and the huge flying fortress that the Emerald Phoenix Emperor arrived in started moving, it was time to show why this Emperor had managed to place a whole empire under his boot.

…

‘What is happening there, looks like the red fog is getting sucked into that middle dot… and it’s growing in size?’

Zhang Dong had previously identified the Emerald Phoenix Emperor as the big red dot on the map. Now it was gradually increasing in size while the other smaller red symbols started getting smaller.

‘Is he absorbing the spiritual energy around him? These guys do get a power boost when coming to this side…’

He remembered that just by stepping foot into the Azure Empire it was possible for the people from the other one to get a power boost. This was another chance that he probably lost, if he moved faster then perhaps he could have battled the Emerald Phoenix Emperor while he was in his incomplete state. Now his power had risen further and perhaps could even rival his own. Even when being still far away from their base he could feel a powerful being in the distance and he was sure that he had been spotted by that person.

‘Hope this Emerald Phoenix Emperor likes duels, if I have to fight him and multiple Saint Emperors it might go badly… but not like I’m alone and there is always that option that I can activate.’

It was getting close to the last showdown, the enemy was at their base which would make it more favorable for them. He was at the helm of the attacking army with his angelic automatons, on the left were the Heavenly Crane Sect forces, and on the other Lucius with the golden knight squadron. His new allies had actually committed quite a lot of resources to this and had already gained a lot of rewards along the way.

Regretfully there weren’t that many reinforcements along the way. The Emerald Phoenix Empire forces were quite diligent in murdering any cultivators from the Azure Dragon Empire. There were no prisoners to liberate along the way, only injured women and children that were left behind as servants.

This didn’t mean that they didn’t garner any help from others. When word started reaching that the invaders were being eradicated many sell swords decided to join. It wasn’t anything new for people to join the winning side, it was an obvious choice to the cultivators living in this world. They weren’t all that strong but they did offer some help and also could bolster their defensive or attacking formations with their spiritual energy.

“Hoh, so they do have one of those… I might have to get my bastion over here a lot faster than I expected…”

Zhang Dong and his forces started slowing down as the enemy fortress appeared before them. While there were some defensive structures down on the ground along with defensive towers this was not what he was looking at. Up in the air was a massive flying structure that was even larger than his own Golden Dong Palace. It was truly massive and produced a massive shadow over the land it was hovering over.

“Everyone, stop!”

His words echoed through the whole army which instantly reacted. It was time for a quick talk between leaders. Naturally, he didn’t believe that this could be talked through but if even a minuscule chance existed, then he had to try.

“Emerald Phoenix Emperor, I am Long Dong, the Golden Dragon, I wish to have an audience with you!”

“Hah, so you are the brat that drove my useless son back… interesting…”

Chapter 616

The sky started rumbling as black clouds filled with rainwater appeared. All attention was towards two people, on one side it was a man clad in a white battle robe and radiating golden energy. On the other, an old man was surrounded by a haze of emerald flames that made him look like he was on fire. The old man was at an advanced age but for some reason had managed to regain some of his youthful demeanor. Instead of looking like a corpse he had reverted to an appearance of a seventy-year-old.

‘He is strong but… I don’t think this guy has the stamina for this fight, I can use this to my advantage.’

Zhang Dong was of course the one clad in golden energy. He could feel that his opponent was facing him on borrowed time. Perhaps he had made a mistake by not pushing in harder before the Emerald Phoenix Emperor achieved his power boost. The Qi his current opponent was radiating was truly tremendous, it was certainly not below his own and this was probably only the tip of the iceberg. However when focusing really hard he could feel that there was something off, the bountiful spiritual energy was decreasing with each passing moment.

No one besides Zhang Dong could probably tell this but the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was slowly running out of juice. He was like a bright candle shining the most before it was burned out. The deterioration process was very minuscule but it was there. This made him believe that if he managed to stall and get his opponent to perform large attacks he would eventually gas himself out. A defensive strategy was his best bet of winning this as the power the old man was emanating was perhaps even above Wang Longs when they fought.

“So you are the Emerald Phoenix Emperor? I can see why they would fear you but… that title is a bit bothersome, do you perhaps have a name to go along with it?”

“You dare talk to me in such a fashion?”

“Why wouldn’t I, old man? If you’re not willing to give me a name, I’ll just call you … how does, old fart sound? Oh, judging by that vein on your forehead it’s not to your liking? Would, Old farty emperor be better then? You know, cos farts are green and you are the Emerald Emperor and stuff…”

“Y-you…”

Zhang Dong’s first tactic was easy, it was always better to make an opponent mad at him. In a fight between cultivators, focus was something that needed to be kept. Charging in with fist swinging and Qi blasts firing was a good way of getting killed. Normally people expected old monsters like the Emerald Phoenix Emperor to be more stoic but the reality was mostly different.

They usually came from a long family line that was used to looking down on others. They expected everyone to bow down their heads when they appeared and be on their best behavior. Thus when they were against someone that offered them nothing else than ridicule, they didn’t know how to react.

“Me? Farty pants gramps, are you feeling okay? Maybe we should get you an adult-sized diaper, you are looking rather pale…”

“How dare you ridicule me, Cuilu Fenghuang, I am the Emerald Phoenix Emperor, I will rip out your spine and keep your head alive in a jar! You shall know my wrath for the reminder of your pathetic life!”

Everyone could sense the rage building up in the Emerald Phoenix Emperor as the whole place started being filled out with greenish flames. Even though Zhang Dong was only mocking him, the name of the old man was revealed to be Cuilu Fenghuang. However, that would just give Zhang Dong more ammunition to continue egging on.

“Was that so hard, Fartyhuang?”

“My name is Fenghuang! It’s going to be the last name you remember! I had enough! Attack!”

“You should watch your blood sugar gramps! Everyone, it’s time, attack with me!”

There were two sides to this fight and they were waiting silently for the two most powerful experts to finish talking. Both needed to shout their orders for the battle to truly commence. Finally, the large number of metallic puppets reacted to Zhang Dong’s call and was then followed by the Heavenly Crane Sect and the focus from the magical kingdom led by Lucius.

On the other side were the Emerald Phoenix Empire forces. Their fighting potential was quite similar to their opponents but they had more ground fortifications. Due to the retreat, they had lost a lot of their flying ships that were now even being used against them. Nevertheless, the whole place was brighter than a fireworks show.

Various colored spiritual energy blasts started flying around the whole place. Attacking formations that took the shape of dragons were quite prevalent on the Azure Empire side while ones that took the appearance of legendary birds on the other. The clash between the many powerful cultivators and treasures started warping the space around this area. The ground could not sustain this mass of spiritual energy and it started to crack. The last battle had finally begun.

…

“For someone with such a foul mouth, can you only run?”

“But if I get too close to you, I’ll get engulfed by those green farts!”

“You still dare mock my emerald flames?”

Zhang Dong continued to run his mouth at the old man that chased him up into the air. They moved far out of the range of the battle that was taking place just like he liked it. Without anyone around him, it was possible for him to let loose. When fighting around an army there was always a danger of his attacks killing some of his allies. Cuilu Fenghuang didn’t seem like someone that would care about killing his own men, so angering him was the first step of getting him away from the battle.

This was of course noticed by some of the Saint Emperor generals from the Emerald Phoenix Empire army. Though they would remain unable to aid their great leader as Lucius along with Argus and some of the Heavenly Crane Sect masters were there to keep them busy. This was a strategy they agreed on before this whole attack even started. They would isolate Cuilu Fenghuang from the rest while Zhang Dong battled him alone.

‘What’s with this feeling, something seems to be off here… I’m not losing but this is a bit too easy…’

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what was happening but the victory was coming too easily. Everything was going according to his plan and he was managing to slowly drain his opponent of precious Qi. They had already clashed a few times and with every confrontation, the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was growing weaker. To keep up with the facade he also made sure to lower his own power level to his opponent. Through this and continued insults he was able to fool Cuilu Fenghuang into believing that he was actually keeping up during this confrontation.

The fight wasn’t easy and there were a few instances in which he received real damage. The gash on his cheek was barely healing as his opponent actually had enough spiritual energy to make it hard for even Zhang Dong to heal. Even though it didn’t take long to heal small wounds, during a confrontation like this which was taking place at high speeds, it could be the difference between life and death. It was better to let some of his blood to spill than to risk a bigger injury if he tried to apply his healing arts.

His enemy was using a large double glave and he was quite proficient with it. These invaders had a different cultivation method so he didn’t need to worry about any unexpected soul beasts. Bahamut who could help him was aiding the army that was able to hold out for now. However even when his plan seemed to be working, there was something that was missing. Without any proof, he could only stall a bit more but the more he waited the harder it would be to win this confrontation.

He was trying to fool his enemy into making a big mistake. Only one was needed to turn this into a one-sided slog and he had offered up some wounds to gain this opportunity. Even though there was something bothering him, he could not confirm this bad premonition with anything substantial. Zhang Dong needed to trust his allies to keep any potential help from coming to the Emerald Phoenix Emperor.

‘He is going for it… I must make it count.’

The time to strike back had come, after bouncing multiple techniques between each other the Emerald Phoenix Emperor raised his glave into the sky. There a massive phoenix composed of flames started to appear. It was some type of grand attack that took some time for him to generate. The time to counter would come after this, the moment their attacks collided with each other there would be a tiny timeframe for him to land a deadly attack. He had lowered his speed just for this moment and was hoping to catch the Emerald Phoenix Emperor off guard.

The emerald phoenix wasn’t just formed, the man himself was being pulled into the massive bird of flames that was even larger than Bahamut his familiar. Even the heavens were being charred by it, the stormy clouds that were generated by Zhang Dong’s Dao were forced back by the appearance of a strong wind. His current opponent was proficient in both winds and flames, with the two working together the flames could be enhanced even further.

Even though his body had reached a new realm it was still human at its base. He was not able to contain all of this heat which made him sweat. This attack if not dodged would really hurt, he wouldn’t be surprised if his enhanced body that was as strong as a heavenly treasure wouldn’t just melt outright. It was also a chance for victory as the moment his own spinning energy ball that was emulating a star collided with the emerald phoenix, it would be the time to strike.

This was at least what was supposed to happen but at the moment that the phoenix started forming something strange happened. A thin ray of black light shot forth from the large floating fortress the Emerald Phoenix Emperor had appeared from. The speed was tremendous and gave no time for anyone from his allies to react.

“I got you now you old bastard!”

“Huh?”

Zhang Dong called out in surprise as he heard the voice of the Emperor’s son calling out. This wasn’t the only baffling part as the beam that was almost at its target was not aimed for him but at the Emerald Phoenix Emperor instead…

Chapter 617

“What is that thing and why is it coming for the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and not me?”

Zhang Dong was holding a huge sphere of twirling energy above his head that he intended to throw at the man he was fighting. It was a critical moment between the two masters that were charging up some of their strongest attacks. His opponent was on the cusp of charging at him but right as he was about to go a strange black beam of light appeared.

It was traveling fast but it looked too thin to be able to pierce through that mass of emerald flames that were surrounding the old Emperor. He was transforming into a green phoenix of some sort, it wouldn’t be strange if a person had to go through a more complicated process to kill him. A Phoenix was a bird of many legends, they were known to be immortal. It was the same in this world and the technique that Cuilu Fenghuang was using was similar to one that Zhang Dong knew about.

It was different in a few places but in theory, it shouldn’t be different. From the outside, it would look like the person turning into the phoenix could be reborn as long as a tiny fraction of their flames survived. Even if their main body was damaged as long as some of those flames existed then they would be able to come back to life. In reality, it involved soul energy and the practitioners becoming one with the flames on a spiritual level.

Unless a person performed attacks aimed at the soul it would be impossible to defeat such a foe. Against someone like Zhang Dong that was versed in soul arts and their energy it wouldn’t be that difficult. He had expected Cuilu Fenghuang to go with a technique like this and was preparing to deliver a hit to his soul while the flames were in disarray. This would apparently not come to pass as when the black beam connected with the emerald bird, a change started to take place.

“Haha, you old fool, I waited hundreds of years for this moment!”

“Y-you… Kong, what do you think you are doing?”

“Hah, so now you remember my name father? All those years, do you think I wouldn’t take my revenge on you? You have already lived too long, I shall become the new emperor.”

“W-what do you think you are doing… t-the emerald flames, you are corrupting them with demonic magic? Who taught you this technique?”

“You don’t need to know but today the Emerald Phoenix Empire dies and a new one shall be born, one that this Cuilu Kong shall rule as the Obsidian Phoenix Emperor!”

Zhang Dong was momentarily stunned by what was happening. After the ray of black connected with the green flames it was like a virus. It started taking apart the emerald light and corrupting it into a shadowy black. It took him a moment to realize that within the black beam existed a powerful soul, it was probably Cuilu Kong’s very essence.

The son had used some type of demonic technique to strip himself of his own body. His energies were all concentrated into the beam which made it this fast. After colliding with the green flames a battle for supremacy between father and son took place. Fenghuang was already old and in his twilight years, the longer the battle took the quicker were his flames being doused.

By Zhang Dong’s calculations, the old man wouldn’t last more than a few years even less if he was forced to use his spiritual energy. It was the perfect time to make a move by the younger man that still had half a millenia left in the gas tank. The reason for this absorption process was certainly to achieve a power boost. Otherwise, Kong could have just waited the few years and taken the throne afterward. Perhaps the aim was to turn those flames black as the power level had actually spiked and his new opponent was perhaps even stronger than the original Emerald Phoenix Emperor.

‘I need to stop this…’

The attack was already formed above his head so he decided to just throw it at the mass of green and black flames. With his own soul energy in the mix there was still hope of interrupting this procedure. Perhaps if he was lucky then he could deal with both father and son at the same time, if not then he would have a new enemy to contend with.

“No, I am the Emerald Phoenix…”

“I shall take what is rightfully mine you old stupid man, give all of it to me, I deserve it!”

“N–nooo…Arghh…”

Even as he was tossing the ball of condensed spiritual energy at the mass of flames he could only feel saddened. How could a son do such a thing to his own father, instead of killing each other they should have been fighting at each other's side. While the Prince wasn’t as strong as his father, it was possible for him to cause some harm.

Both of them seemed to only garner negative feelings for each other, something he could not understand. How could a parent and his child grow so much apart that one of them wanted to kill them? Could this be something brought on by hundreds of years of living in a parent’s shadow? Could Kong’s state of mind have become eroded by people constantly comparing him to his superior father? The young man was probably one of the most powerful cultivators in their whole empire but this was apparently not enough.

Nevertheless, he could not just stay there and do nothing. His two enemies were battling each other within those soul flames and the black ones were winning. Even though the situation was quite drastic this was a good turn of events. Considering that he could now directly hit his opponent without him not being able to dodge.

The skies were lit up with green, black, and golden light. The people below them backed away to the sides as the spiritual energy produced was not something anyone below a nascent soul level could handle. Even those experts that were of lesser quality started to pass out in the middle of their own fights.

A giant hole in the sky appeared as all the clouds in the vicinity were pushed to the sides. A sunny day greeted the battlefield but right in the middle of that blue sky was a strange or of pitch-black light. The only person that could tell what was happening wasn’t far away from it. To some, it looked like a black hole but to him, it was a swirling mass of black flames with only a few emerald ones still trying to hold on.

“Yes! I did it… I finally did it, I have become the new Emperor!”

Zhang Dong continued to float in his previous spot without approaching the spiral of flames that started to slowly form into the shape of a human. His new opponent looked different than the Green Emperor, he looked like a fusion of a crow and a person with wings made of pitch-black flames. His eyes were all read and he was radiating a massive amount of spiritual energy very similar to the Emerald Phoenix Emperors but at a more stable rate. At least when it came to energy, he would not be able to wear this new enemy down as easily.

“How could you kill your own father for something like power?”

“Huh? What is it to you, your fate is to be a stepping stone for this new Emperor.”

His legs had become a bird and his skin took on the color of obsidian. The current Cuilu Kong looked like some kind of beast that had attempted to become human but failed at it. It was clear that he was stronger but it wasn’t to such a degree that he could ignore Zhang Dong’s own might. Perhaps the son was watching the battle of his father. But his opponent was hiding part of his true power, in this moment of victory, he had misjudged his enemy to be a lot weaker than he actually was.

“Cuilu Kong is no more, now the Obsidian Phoenix… no I must discard that filthy title, I will become the Obsidian Crow that darkens out the lands, all shall know my might!”

His voice echoed through the whole battlefield causing people to bleed out of their eye sockets and also ears. Luckily for everyone, there was a person that could match this spiritual output. An aura of gold erupted from Zhang Dong that shielded his side of the battlefield but left the enemy generals to feel the burn.

“Is that so… are you finished? Old farty pants was already bad but you take the cake…”

“Heh, for someone that is about to die you like to talk, I must commend you for helping me take care of my stupid father, I could not have done it without you, and for this, I will offer you a painless death but if you resist I shall make it as painful as possible.”

“Hmm… that’s a very tempting offer but I think I’ll go with option three so… how about you surrender and call off your army, I’m sure they will listen to their new featherbrained emperor.”

“You dare mock this Emperor? I gave you a chance now you shall become the first one to die by my hands, you should feel honored!”

“I see… you actually haven’t noticed yet huh? Okay, then have at you crow boy let me see what you are made off!”

Zhang Dong smiled at Cuilu Kong in a mocking way. If people from outside compared their energy levels then they would probably give the Obsidian Crow the edge. However, he knew otherwise. There had been something that his opponent didn’t notice as he had been too busy fighting for supremacy with the old emperor. These sorts of demonic techniques always had a chance of failing and even more if they were tempered.

The clash between the two resounded in the air as all the fighting below ground had stopped. It was normal for everyone to be confused after the leader had been exchanged for another one. Everyone was waiting for one of the masters to be victorious as it was clear that the ones without their top fighters would be at a massive disadvantage. Some were already preparing to flee the moment the victor presented themselves.

“What is this? How can you be this fast?”

“Am I fast, or are you just slow?”

“Huh?”

The battle continued for a while but none of the attacks aimed at Zhang Dong’s throat were getting through. It looked like all of his moves were being moved but in reality, Cuilu Kong started noticing that something else was happening.

“H-how could this be… what have you done to me?”

“I see, it took you a while but you finally noticed…”

Chapter 618

“W-what have you done to me? How is this possible…”

“Oh I didn’t do much, it was your fault for attempting that stupid technique next to me. Did you think that you were the only one versed in soul arts?”

“Y-you…”

The angered self-proclaimed Obsidian Emperor mustered all his might to charge at Zhang Dong. To his dismay his movements were quite sluggish, it was as if he was neck-deep in tar. Each time he wanted to land a hit on his enemy there was something stopping him from connecting with the hits. It was as if something that was deeply ingrained into his very being wasn’t allowing him to kill this man.

“I think that’s about it, regretfully even the little trick I did won’t last forever, so this will be it for you…”

After letting his little spell take over his opponent Zhang Dong decided that he needed to finish this. During the fusion of the two flames that had a basis in soul arts, he managed to interfere with the process. It was similar to putting a person under a soul-binding contract where they couldn’t go against the contract holder. This process was forced and done rather hastily so it wouldn't last forever. Cuilu Kong was still at the pinnacle of power and not inferior to Zhang Dong in any way, a forced soul-binding technique wouldn’t last but it would keep him in place long enough for the final finish.

What was supposed to be a fight of a century was ending up being a letdown. People that were down on the ground could only watch with fear in their eyes as Zhang Dong pulled out his golden sword. After going into a stance with the blade above his head he started to charge up.

“Why isn’t the Emperor moving?”

“Is he under some kind of technique?”

“S-shouldn’t we help him? But how are we supposed to get through that thick cloud of spiritual energy?”

The generals from the Emerald Phoenix Empire started murmuring among each other. Even if they wanted to aid their leader there was a mass of metallic puppets blocking their way. They weren’t the only ones as the armies from the Heavenly Crane Sect saw this as a chance to drive them back. Their master was winning and this was the time to strike. Whenever the strongest cultivator from an enemy troop was losing, it was time to shift the tide.

“No, I refuse to die! I can’t die! I won’t die! What are you blubbering idiots doing, protect your Emperor!”

Cuilu Kong was angry, he had plotted for hundreds of years for this very moment. When Zhang Dong appeared and showed his power against his sister his long plan could finally commence. He had retreated and gave his father a good excuse forcing him to arrive in this place. During the clash, he took over all of the emerald flames that were usually passed down as the Emperor was dying. Now that he had forcefully taken them, he was supposed to be the next god among men.

Instead, he found himself at the mercy of the man in white armor and the blade above his head. Normally as someone baptized by the phoenix flames, he would not fear death, as long as some connection to them remained he could be reborn multiple times. This attack that was being built up, wasn’t simple, it contained something that caused his very soul to tremble in fear. He knew that if the sword energies collided with his body, his life would be over.

“Calling for help now? Why would the people that you so tyrannized help you out now? Wouldn’t they be joyful that they don’t have to fear the overbearing Emperor anymore?”

“What are you talking about, they live to serve… they belong to me and the dynasty, it has always been like this!”

“Is that so… how about before you die we ask them?”

“What are you?”

Zhang Dong raised the sword even higher while gathering all of his holy power. His voice was enhanced by all of this spiritual energy and with an addition of his soul power was able to resonate with everyone gathered here.

“People from the Emerald Phoenix Empire, You might have heard my name while coming to those lands, some call me the Golden Dragon and others Long Dong.”

Some people were ready to charge up and even others were still fighting as the inborn fear of the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was still very real. They could not see their Emperor ever losing and if he remembered the faces of the people that didn’t act, all of them would die. Nevertheless, they stopped as the master of the opposing force started talking directly to their souls. For some reason they got the feeling that he was on their side, his presence was just as mighty as that of their late Emperor but much gentler in comparison.

“Hear me out, your Emperor has died and his son will follow suit. You have two options now either you continue with this pointless battle where you will surely lose or… you leave. On my name as the Golden Dragon, I will guarantee your safety and I will make a soul oath that no harm shall befall you.”

“This… how is a soul contract being formed at such a scale…”

The words echoed through their minds as a contract was being established. Something like this was inconceivable but there it was. Though they couldn’t trust in Zhang Dong’s words they could at least trust in the pact that was made. Perhaps it was some type of rouse but it looked believable, if they just retreated they would not be harmed. The only thing that they needed to do was offer up the new Emperor that was shouting at them in a rabid voice.

“What are you idiots doing? You’re not actually considering his proposal? I shall kill all your clans if you betray me! You lowly bugs belong to the Empire and I am that Empire, you serve me!”

“Hah, is this the Emperor you wish to follow? Turn back, your families are waiting for your return, let this madness end with the death of this man.”

“I… My grandchild has just been born, I was not able to see her because of the conscription…”

“My son has recently married, I have not been able to see his face in many years…”

“Me too…”

“I…”

The scary-looking cultivators started slowly inching away to the other side. For some reason the moment the soul contract was being formed they were reminded of their loved ones. A lot of these people were leaders of their own clans, sects, and factions. They had been forced to work under the Emperor and fight in this battle for supremacy. While they also had their own selfish reasons for being here, all of those started going out of the window as they started getting nostalgic.

“What are you doing? You dare retreat? I will have your heads!”

“You can stop, they can’t hear your words anymore.”

“What did you do?”

“Nothing much, I just reminded them of things that matter more than power. I’m sure you think that every person is as selfish as you are but everyone has a small sentiment somewhere deep inside, I just inched it to the forefront.”

Zhang Dong used a combination of techniques to tug on the people's heartstrings. They were more likely to retreat if they remembered their family and friends, or other things that would go away if they continued this fight. Even the stronger masters started getting sentimental which left the lesser ones open to his little suggestions even more. Soon enough they started retreating while their new Emperor was shouting up a storm. To finish this he needed to deliver the killing blow and perhaps all of this would be finally over.

“Farewell, I don’t know what happens to people like you when they die, but I sure hope that if there is an afterlife they won’t make it easy for you.”

“No…NO!”

All the energy that he gathered was pushed into his blade which started shining. The glow was blinding and mostly white as it packed a lot of soul power behind it. The trick to killing a phoenix was in destroying its soul and this was what this attack was aimed at. With a quick downward swing, the blade started cleaving down even though it took only a fraction of a second for an attack to move down, for the Obsidian Emperor it was like a century.

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what was flashing through his enemy's mind before he died. Were there any good memories in this monster's mind? Could his father be the true villain in this instance that had led his son to crave power this much? He didn’t know but too many people had died by this man’s hand for him to feel any amount of pity. To end this war early his head needed to roll and he would be the executioner.

A beam of light flew into the sky and exploded into a radiant shower of light. It looked like a swarm of falling stars dispersing everywhere. Cuilu Kong’s body had been cleaved into two equal halves and the black body that he was so proud of began to crumble. Black flames appeared from within but quickly started turning white as they started to be cleansed from inside of his body.

The soul that kept the technique going was being destroyed and the rebirthing flames could not activate. Without the soul to stabilize the form, Cuilu Kong had died and his body started to vanish. The Obsidian Crow that was destined to black out the sun was now gone, he did not live even for one hour and his legacy would never be remembered.

From within the broken flames, one of them remained intact. It was not part of the man but similar to the triple horn that the Demi-Human Emperor’s body dropped after he was defeated. The item in question looked like a black feather made of flames, what was supposed to be emerald green had become corrupt and it term given him a little bonus. Bob’s robotic voice resounded inside of his head the moment he beckoned the black feather over.

‘The item is compatible with the user’s system, do you wish to absorb it?’

‘Yes go ahead, absorb it.’

The Dao absorption had become, what he thought would be two paths turned into three. His body was washed over by three distinct energies, Fire, Wind, and then Darkness…

Chapter 619

“Darkness is it… well, they say that a balance between light and dark needs to be maintained and only then true power can follow…”

Zhang Dong looked at the prompt on his screen while holding the flaming black feather. After defeating the Emerald Emperor’s Son he gained the prize that he was after. Perhaps after enhancing his cultivation level with these three higher Daos it would be possible to push into the immortal realm? This was an important question as he wasn’t sure if he wanted to make the transition just yet. He had to consider the time and place as the Overseer could become aware of this transformation.

‘But what if someone steals the feather before I can use it, just like that time…’

There had been a chance to absorb Wang Long’s power and he let it slip. What if the same thing happened as last time and he had to actually go through regular cultivation for close to a thousand years? Even though he didn’t really mind retiring for a while after this war was over, a life with some strange powerful being watching over him would be stressful.

Thus a decision was made to just go through with the absorption of the three Daos here. Zhang Dong wondered if this was some kind of hidden scenario that he was given three at once where he expected to get one or two at most. Wind, Fire, and also Darkness. With the last one, he was conflicted a bit but darkness didn’t really have anything to do with demonic cultivators. As long as he was careful he would not be taken over by demonic urges that originated from ingesting demonic Qi.

‘Okay Bob, let’s do it, start the absorption process.’

‘Acknowledged’

The black feather that was in his hand started crumbling into dust and vanished from this plane of existence. The knowledge that he was missing concerning the Dao of fire and wind started filling his very existence. He already had a fairly good grasp of those so the increase wasn’t that great but when it came to the Dao of Darkness it was different. This was something he only grasped a tiny bit of after combating the demonic cultivators in the north.

Just as the knowledge was filling his brain the little seed began opening up even more. His power started growing and the people below that were still unsure of what to do started trembling. He could not stop his aura from seeming out and to the weaker warriors it was a soul-crushing experience. However just as fast as this boost in power came, it vanished quickly after. The seed stopped opening instantly after the process was over and still wanted something more.

‘Hm… it’s still missing something, perhaps the fire and wind Dao’s aren’t special enough to fill out this seed…’

While fire, water, wind, and earth were the basic elemental Daos and were also higher ones, they could be considered the most basic ones. Something like the Dao of Gravity or the one of Darkness that he just took in were a notch above them. This meant that in theory if the Cerulean Empress that was left behind only had the Dao of water to absorb, he wouldn’t be getting much from that confrontation.

‘Hm, I’m sure the hidden boss from the lands Lucius and Argus came from probably had the Dao of Light or Holy which I already have and he won’t probably ever appear now…’

This mission was now over and he would be giving Lucius his reward. With the holy aegis shield relic in their hands, they would perhaps not have any reason to stay here anymore. That is unless a third relic was needed to complete their mission. Nevertheless now with the east and west sides of the empire cleared out, they could just go on their search without anyone getting in their way.

Zhang Dong’s name was already famous enough to open up all doors to people associated with him. The only place they would be barred from would be the Azure palace that even he didn’t have access to. That place was meant to be his last destination after all the Emperors were gone and it looked like that time would come sooner than he had expected.

‘I never thought this would go this smoothly, I over-prepared for the occasion.’

He had prepared a whole army made out of metallic puppets and also taken time to save up on spirit points. He was ready to call forth his close aids which included his wife, Hao Qiang and Zhang Zhi. The three were integrated into his system and possessed a battle power equal to the strongest nascent soul masters in the empire.

His grandfather would also arrive in his golden stronghold that needed a lot of points to be brought over here and then back to the northern battlefield. All of these resources were not used up and everything ended rather quickly. Luckily he could use the automatons somewhere else and perhaps turn them into a task force in the western region.

‘Hm, maybe that is a bad idea. It'll make me look like some power-hungry dictator trying to police everything… but it would probably save some lives, at the cost of some freedoms…’

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure if he wanted to become a benevolent dictator. In theory, this wasn’t a bad idea if the dictator was knowledgeable enough. This however was not something he was confident of nor did he want to stifle the freedom of the people living here. Everyone was free to do what they wanted and he could only present a system that would not allow for too much bloodshed. Considering how quickly people in this world were to seek conflict, he would need to think it through when the time came.

“It’s over, both the son and the father are no more.”

Finally, the time to end this all came. His voice boomed through the entire area and interacted with everyone’s soul. The enemy army was slowly inching back, even though they had the giant fortress floating in the back without their emperor it couldn’t be fully utilized. A design flaw that rigged it to only work with their emperor. This meant that it was now nothing more than a large floating palace with no attacking or defending capabilities.

“Just as I promised, you all may now leave but you’ll have to leave some things behind…”
The enemy Saint Emperors that were previously generals in the Emerald Phoenix Empire army could not say anything against those words. It was already enough that they could just leave. Normally if their side was victorious they would have slaughtered all of the Heavenly Crane Sect cultivators and everyone else that got in their way. The faction leaders from the sect knew and raised their voices in protest.

“Honorable Golden Dragon, why should we show these savages mercy? They had gone through our lands, they pillaged, raped, and killed, they deserve no mercy!”

“You speak the truth, Leader Zhong, they have performed atrocities but they were still only following orders… answer me this, why didn’t you do anything when these acts of violence were being performed on your people?”

“That is…”

He knew that the Heavenly Crane Sect didn’t really care about their people that much. If they did, then they would have pushed back harder. It wasn’t impossible for them to drive the initial forces back if they utilized more of their nascent soul masters. They didn’t though and now that a weakened leaderless opponent stood before them, they just wanted to perform the same acts of slaughter that they did.

“I have given my word, they are free to go. Of course, they will leave their battleships and all the ill-gotten gains that they stripped from your lands will be returned, if they don’t abide by the rules then we will resume our battle.”

“But honorable…”

“I shall not repeat myself, are you trying to go against my decision?”

Zhang Dong needed to put his foot down. He had worked with these people and they had gotten the wrong idea that they were on the same level. They needed to understand that if he wanted, then they would not be able to stop him. This was achieved by his aura spiking to a tremendous degree. His power had actually risen by absorbing the new Daos and this would be felt by the nascent soul masters that could measure it.

“Please appease your anger honorable Golden Dragon, Leader Zhong had spoken out of terms, we shall follow your proposition.”

“Y-yes…”

The man that had usually gone against him quickly went back on his statement after feeling the tremendous power coming from Zhang Dong’s form. He wasn’t the only one here, the army of metallic angles was also turning their heads towards the Heavenly Crane Sect and so was Lucius. They were sending a clear message that if they continued with the prodding that all hell would break loose.

This of course was a surprise to the Emerald Phoenix Empire forces that couldn’t really believe that a powerful master would allow them to just leave. There was no reason not to now, they had already lost and without the large emerald palace behind them, it would be impossible for a counterattack.

“Do you agree? If you promise me to relinquish your weapons and stolen goods, then I will allow you to take a few ships that can contain the remainder of your people and cross the bridge back to your own lands. Of course, you are not allowed to come back and I can not guarantee the safety of anyone that attempts to come back here.”

“C-can we really trust in your word?”

“General Xiang, what are you doing? Are we really going to surrender our weapons to them? What if they attack us right after?”

“Look around you, General Qiuyue, do you think they need us to relinquish our weapons to achieve a victory?”

“That is…”

Zhang Dong waited for the generals to converse with each other. Now that the Emperor was gone a new faction would form. At the moment it would consist of the strongest Saint Emperors and luckily they were starting to agree with each other. It was true that there was not much to gain from letting them go and that his side didn’t really have to. Everyone was already shocked that they had not attacked after the Emperor was dealt with.

He could feel the will to resist fade as he surrounded the area with his aura. Even he had to give them a little nudge to lose all semblance of resistance. Luckily these people were primed to follow strong people and he had proven to be even stronger than the Emperor that terrorized them their whole lives. There was no way that they could hope to go against him and thanks to this some lives would be spared today.

Chapter 620

“Is this really wise? What if they return with a new force? Shouldn’t we snuff out the flame while it is still small then face a blazing inferno later?”

“I’m of the same mind but… how about you tell that to him…”

“...”

The Patriarch from the Heavenly Crane Sect looked along with a few other faction leaders from his sect towards the sky. There a lone man with snow-white hair was gently floating, his hair even though long was not affected by the winds. It was as if he was standing in a vacuum with no air around, with feet planted in something robust.

At the moment the armies from the Heavenly Crane Sect were looking at a handful of ships leaving towards the bridge between worlds. A massive wall of chaotic elements was blocking the pathway from all sides with only a thin passageway going to the other side. On all of those ships, there were soldiers from the enemy side and this would have been the best moment to just blast them to kingdom come.

They were on their way out of this empire and this place would be soon turned into a fortress. Even though these were the Heavenly Crane Sect’s lands it didn’t seem that they had a say in this. To each side of the bridge to another land, two towers were being assembled by the strange flying automation that originated from the United Element’s Sect.

The whole spectacle was quite strange, out of nowhere a group of strange cultivators appeared. They were dressed in white coats with black gloves that looked as if they were made from rubber. Their leader’s hair was all over the place and he was wearing dark goggles to cover his eyes. After shouting out some things the man took control of the flying automatons and together with a few other men started ordering them to build structures. Even though the Emerald Phoenix Empire forces were still in the process of gathering they were already working on setting up the barricade.

“It would be better if we cut our losses here, maybe in the future an opportunity will present itself but for now, we must wait.”

“The Patriarch speaks the truth, we should let the Golden Dragon settle things with the Emperor first before we make a decision.”

“I concur, we still don’t know if they are working together or not… another war might start soon and it will be wise to not get involved with it.”

The Lily faction leaders started nodding at each other. Surprisingly all of them were in agreement, they did not want to get mixed up in the battle for the throne. At first they all were thinking of teaming up with Zhang Dong to force the Azure Dragon to relinquish some resources. They had made a mistake as they had considered their sect to be at least on the same level as the United Element’s Sect.

Now after seeing their leader in action, they knew that they were not in the same league anymore. It wouldn’t be strange if Zhang Dong was able to kick the Azure Emperor off the throne if he wanted. Some were already making up schemes and possible scenarios in their head. Perhaps Zhang Dong was actually the real Azure Emperor and the one sitting on the throne was just a trick to let him go through the lands easily.

“We shall wait and be watchful…”

The old masters nodded at each other while exchanging hidden messages. They would have not dared to utter words out loud out of fear. The way Zhang Dong defeated the monster that was the Emerald Phoenix Emperor was still fresh in their minds. The battle was incomprehensible to them, even though all of them assumed to be great circle nascent soul masters they could not place themselves on equal footing with Zhang Dong.

The gap between them had even become larger as for some reason the man felt even more fearsome than before. It was in their best interest to not anger him as he could very well become the new Emperor of these lands. They couldn’t discount that he already was the hidden leader and was just making things official by coming to the eastern region by himself.

Perhaps all of this was just a ploy to make them realize that they were not part of the big three that they had assumed. Maybe there were never three forces in the whole empire to begin with. After seeing him in action it wasn’t strange to assume that he commanded the strongest force on the entire plane. If not, then sooner or later he would come for the current head which was the Azure Emperor. The Heavenly Crane Sect wanted no part in this war and would be sure to barricade themselves at their home territory until everything was done with…

…

‘Hah, they really are afraid of me now. I wonder what they would do If they knew that I can read their hidden messages on my system screen? Though even there they are referring to me in a cordial manner…’

This was quite normal as they saw something that shouldn’t be possible. The Heavenly Crane Sect had a lot of nascent soul masters but even their Patriarch paled in comparison to the Emerald Phoenix Emperor or his opponent that was the Golden Dragon. It was an entirely new world for them that thought to have reached the zenith of power in this world. It was a gap that they didn’t really know how to cross and the decision to wait wasn’t wrong.

‘But they think I might go against the Emperor huh? That would probably be the path of a regular cultivator…’

There was a saying that there was no room for two Emperors in one empire. It wouldn’t be strange for him or the Azure Emperor to make some kind of move. In the eyes of this Heavenly Crane Sect, a long-lasting war was not off the table. The United Element’s Sect would only have to announce that they are taking over the western side of the empire for themselves and creating a new region with them at the top. This or refusing to pay taxes to the current leaders was also a way out. Then it would be up to the Long Clan to retaliate and if they didn’t then it would send a message to everyone that was living in that region.

‘In the system’s scenario, the Azure Emperor was supposed to be my ally. He might have been destined to fall from the start but could also be there as the strongest opponent…’

After interacting with the Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s son he knew that things could shift at a drop of a hat. If he wasn’t as close as he was to the father and son when the absorption process was taking place then he would be in for the fight of his life. Cuilu Kong was a master that had lived for half a millennium, even though he was around at the same level as Wang Long he was probably a much more advanced combatant with many tricks up his sleeve.

‘I got lucky again… I even have this thing now, it’s quite similar to the Golden Dong Palace, a late-stage weapon’

There was a thing about flying castles and this was one of them. It was of similar size to his golden bastion but at the moment was offline. It was mostly made of some type of green metal that glistened like an emerald when sun rays collided with it. For the time being the whole thing was in some type of hibernation. It was floating around but nothing really worked, Bob was already working on ways of cracking the defenses.

This artifact was meant for the Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s use only and would only react to his bloodline. This would leave Cuilu Yahui as the next in line after both her father and brother had died. He hoped that it wouldn’t get to that but perhaps he would have to use her in conjunction with this emerald palace. Even though the woman was stripped of her cultivation base she was still alive. Her fate would be to live as a mortal while having to bow her head before even the weakest cultivator.

‘But It might be possible to emulate her bloodline to make this thing see me as its master, it’s nothing more than an intricate DNA scanner. Either I’ll have to alter the scanner itself or go with the other option.’

This flying ship was not part of his faction and had no long-range teleportation features. The plan now was to drag it back to his sect where some specialists could look over it. There were probably some hidden treasures on board that needed to be analyzed. With how the weapons of this empire eclipsed theirs, this flying treasure trove of knowledge would probably usher in a new age of weaponry.

“Now that it is over, I would like you to keep your promise.”

“Hm? Oh, Lucius.”

As he was looking at the large palace being attached to ten flying ships they collected from the enemy fleet, Lucius and Argus appeared before him. Now that the battle was over, they had come to claim the prize which was the holy shield. With it in their possession, they might have nothing left to do here and this would be the end of their relationship.

Perhaps others would have decided to hold on to a weapon that they don’t really understand but he was looking at the bigger picture. It was unwise to allow another emperor-level threat to arrive at his doorstep. The Cerulean Empress was the only one that remained but the side Lucius came from wasn’t fully revealed to him. As his people had proven themselves to be capable no further reinforcements were needed.

“Haha, you should stop grimacing so much or your eyebrows will get stuck like that.”

Lucius frowned while Argus that was flying behind him started chuckling. It was quite funny to see him flinch the moment the duke looked back. Zhang Dong pulled out the relic from his replica of the dimensional regalia and threw it toward his allies. The man in golden armor looked quite panicked as he tried catching the item in question.

“C-careful…Argus… is this really it?”

“Hm… yes, it does resonate, it is the sacred shield! With this, it’s almost complete!”

“Huh? Almost complete, is there really more?”

Zhang Dong butted in as for some reason he expected the second relic not to be the last one. After the second one become apparent it wouldn’t be strange that there wouldn’t be more he just never really asked to confirm this claim.

“Ah, yes, if we just need to find the sacred plate and it will be complete.”

“Secret plate? Is it a suit of armor?”

“Yes, do you perhaps know its whereabouts?”

“No… but I’ll be sure to tell you when I find it…”

If a suit of armor was the only thing left this brought some trouble with it. What if it was scattered in multiple places? Perhaps the helmet was at one location but the gauntlets at another instead of it being at one location. However, this also meant that his new friends would be staying and now with the freedom to move around almost the whole empire, they could find it themselves.

Chapter 621

“...”

“Is something wrong?”

“Oh? No, everything is fine…”

“Is that so? You think that I wouldn’t know if my own husband wasn’t worried about something?”

“Ah…It’s just, Everything is going too well.”

“Is that such a problem? Wasn’t this what you were fighting for?”

“Well yes but …”

“Think you might be worrying too much? We still have troubles at the sea and then there is still that brother of yours.”

Zhang Dong nodded at Liena that was standing right next to him. The two were both in their new house where they could see both their children training their martial arts outside. Ever since the war had started the two had been focusing on getting their skills up, it was as if they wanted to help out their father and mother during this conflict that could last for centuries.

A week had passed since the Emerald Phoenix Emperor had died and his main forces were driven out of the east side of the empire. Just like with the demi-humans, a few stragglers remained here and there. They were now getting hunted down by bounty hunters and people trying to go back to their old cities that had been destroyed.

Where the bridge to the Emerald Phoenix Empire existed a large stronghold was being built. It would have giant spirit cannons and protective formations established to not let another group of them inside. The base they had there could be transformed into something like that so the building process would be rather quick. With this there only existed one obvious bridge that hadn’t been closed and that one belonged to Lucius and his forces.

For the time being Zhang Dong decided to let them be. Some people from his side contested this idea as to them it was a bomb that could explode at any moment. He had of course relayed the information he gained from visiting their base and also explained that he believed that their main troops were on standby on the other side. To his people it wasn’t a risk worth taking and forcing Lucius and Argus out to their own kingdom was the best idea. They were no match for the current United Elemental Sect’s forces.

However, he had promised to cooperate with the golden knights and for the time being, they had proven themselves as good allies. During the Demi-human battle, Argus had helped them hold back the animalistic body refiners. Then they also helped him with the Emerald Phoenix Empire. There was no reason to turn their backs on them; it could backfire. What if they had another way of coming to this place even if the bridge was closed?

Their base looked like it had existed on this side for a while; it was possible for them to have some teleportation relics that could do the job. If Zhang Dong started to drive them out it was also possible for the King to show up. While he might have been weaker than Wang Long or the Emerald Phoenix Emperor, it was always a risk. Thus for now they were free to roam the lands in search of their sacred armor. Unless they started performing some heinous acts against the civilians he couldn’t see them becoming a problem in the future.

This only left the Azure Emperor that had somehow vanished and the northern sea that was becoming strangely silent. After the last attack during which he told his army to back off, there was no new news of the Cerulean Empress either. Considering that the clone armies had started to struggle perhaps they finally decided to go with a different approach.

“Yes, the Azure Emperor… he might see this as a challenge to his authority, we can’t exclude that he might be planning to attack our forces when we least expect it.”

“That is true, perhaps it will be wiser to wait now.”

“Wait…”

Liena smiled at him which put his heart at rest for a moment. Yet soon enough he was wondering if waiting would solve anything. What if the Long Clan just used this time to prepare a proper army or if the Cerulean Empress was building up a counter-offensive of immeasurable numbers? Perhaps her tactic didn’t change but the scale did, if her armies were depleted of cloned generals and sea creatures now was the time to strike. If he let this drag on for too long the northern battlefront could suffer greatly.

His main goal was to end this conflict as fast as possible before secluding himself and progressing into the immortal stage. It wouldn’t be wrong to wait but he had been successful enough by being more aggressive. If he didn’t rush to the east side he would not have had such an easy time with the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. None of his own people had to participate which left his army in full power. Without the need to teleport the golden bastion he was now free to invest these points to level it up instead and before going after the sea people, this had to be done.

“I don’t think my husband likes listening to his wife…”

“Ouch…”

While he was spacing out he could feel Liena pinching his arm before standing up and walking away. He could only smile while looking at her pouty face but she was right, he was probably not going to listen to her. The war was not yet over and it was unwise to just sit around twiddling his thumbs. Thanks to the quick resolution in the east, he was ready to continue and he would not even need anyone else than his own armies. Previously it was either Lucius or the Heavenly Crane sect but now, he could do all of this himself.

‘I’ll still have to watch out for the Long Clan, even if Long Qing isn’t planning anything all those people around him probably hate me, then there is his wife that is behind it all…’

What was bothering him the most was the overseer. There was a teleportation spot at the Azure Palace that he could use to get more information. Perhaps after the Cerulean Empress was dealt with it would be time to use it. It was too dangerous, the woman could stop time and it was possible that he would be dealt with if he attempted to get there.

Then there was the second option, that nothing would actually happen. After the war between empires was over there would be nothing standing in his way of ascending. The system wanted him to ascend after fainting some trials and tribulations but it didn’t really seem like it wanted him to die. It was possible for an inept system user to perish but even Wang Long with his disregard for anyone was able to persist. If Zhang Dong wasn’t there, he would have probably conquered the entire empire, eventually.

‘I’ll never know what this is about until I cross over… but if I do, what will happen to all of them?’

Through the window, he could see his wife slowly walking over to his children. After arriving by their side she started scolding his daughter for not being easy on his son. Little Jun was holding in the tears while holding his nose that was punched by his sister. Before Liena arrived Xiu was making fun of him for being so slow. Now she was almost ready to run after seeing the stern face of her mother.

He wanted these days to continue, it wasn’t that long since he had become a father and by losing five years in the other dimension he was even more behind. There was a real chance that if he advanced to the next cultivation level he would be forced to leave this place. It was also possible that where he went to could have another time variation like before or even worse, he could not be able to ever return. This world gave him a long life and at least before making the attempt he wished to see his children grow up and find their own paths just like he did.

‘But it shouldn’t force me out, that guy that came before me was able to postpone leaving until he was more than a thousand years old, I should be able to do the same. After I clear things up in the north and then settle things with my dear ‘brother’ I should be able to relax for a couple of hundred years…’

This was his current plan. First, he wanted to clear up the disturbances in these lands before going into a retirement phase. Perhaps this wasn’t feasible but he wanted to at least enjoy a few years with his family before he tackled the problem with the system. If it was possible he would not interact with the scary overseer and slowly gather more power.

There were still some truths that he might be able to unearth in his predecessor's old home. While most of those tapes there had turned to dust Bob was working on restoring some of the lost materials. However with the main version used for other purposes that part was being stalled.

‘I’ll have to consider that the Azure Dragon and Golden Dragon might not be able to coexist with each other. The story that he told me might have been a lie and the moment the issue with the Cerulean Empress is done, they might strike… though with Lucius around, they might not act…’

He started seeing Lucius and Argus as a possible buffer between him and the end of the scenario. Normally a game would only move to the last stage after all of the main story events were finished. If the golden knights are never defeated and just stay around searching for their holy armor, it could give him time to prepare. It might be even better to hide the armor if he finds it to prolong their stay in this empire.

‘But where could that armor be? It wouldn’t be strange if it was somewhere at sea, I already found the sword at the Golden Dong Palace so there shouldn’t be another one there… unless they hid it away in their treasury or something… It wouldn’t be strange if that Overseer lady placed it there…’

There was a possibility of his enemies playing around with the settings. He did not trouly know what these moderators were tasked with besides hard resting the setting if a strange bug appeared. This happened in the other world that he visited and could happen here if they find that his cultivation was different.

‘I guess I’ll have to take that into consideration, for now It’s time to pay those fish a visit and upgrade the palace, maybe it would be wise to make it waterproof…’

Chapter 622

“This farm really paid off, maybe more than the whole visit to the eastern side of the empire. Now, what should I change this thing into, let’s look over the options.”

Zhang Dong was seated at his chair in the command station of the Golden Dong Palace. The first thought in his head was to change the name that he had given to this thing but going through spirit points for something like this hurt his very soul. Maybe after all the danger was over and the passive spirit point gain was good he would just change it to something more regal. The Golden Dragon Palace had a better ring to it and was also more aligned with his new title.

“Hm… Not that many options, one will add a few defensive features but what I need now is something that can do a few things…”

With the Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s and his son’s passing there was only one main enemy that he stood against. It was the underwater empire that was led by the Cerulean Empress. The usual time for their attack had already passed so now everyone was curious about what was happening. Either they had decided to change their tactics or were just out of disposable soldiers.

Their cloning technology was quite advanced but it required a stable infusion of resources. The cloning mechanisms didn’t just run off spiritual energy they also required some type of strange biomass. His people were able to capture one of those cloning facilities and were somewhat able to deduce the mechanics behind it.

There was one component missing which didn’t allow them to copy the technology but it still allowed them to make some strides in the healing field. It was possible to clone body parts which then could replace lost limbs or organs. Making a full human with a working soul was impossible but creating a body was feasible. They theorized that a person that could move their spirit around freaky could potentially go into a created body like that.

This reminded him of some stories that he heard about or read. There were some powerful individuals that were said to have lived for longer than the millennial limit this world was stuck on. The soul that a person was composed of was much more robust than their body which would start falling apart. Zhang Dong, who had quite a powerful soul could potentially drag his life spawn out by using clones of himself.

However, this wouldn't last forever as the process was a bit unnatural. Each time a body was swapped some of that soul energy would be lost forever. If that core component was affected the cultivator would start getting holes in their memory. With time they could even forget who they were or turn into something different. When used in conjunction with demonic Qi, a person could become violent or a monster.

“Going down into the deep blue sea won’t be easy, even if people are able to survive the crushing pressure and lack of air, they have no training in underwater battles.”

His mind drifted back to the problem at hand. The people from the underwater empire probably had their base deep in the sea. Even he was only able to contend with the monsters because the power differential was really huge and he didn’t really go down as deep.

His spies had done some research about where the enemy monsters were coming from. It was easy to follow the swarm of sea creatures back from where they came from. Everything indicated that they had a base of operations many kilometers under the sea. No light was able to reach that far underground and they had to be ready to fight vast quantities of sea monsters when they got there.

“Going by the report it's possible that this base of theirs isn’t fully submerged in water. They did spot some type of protective barrier that couldn’t be peered through, first we need to destroy that before we can get further. I think this upgrade will allow my troops to move more freely there…”

Zhang Dong looked at the options of the castle and one allowed it to augment its shielding technology. This barrier was also quite special, besides forming one layer on the inside that acted like a semi-transparent wall, there was an outer region that could drive the water back. In this region that could be pushed out to a couple of kilometers around his base, his other ships could maneuver around as if they were up in the air.

“Concentric Barrier Fortress, that’s quite the long name for it…”

Concentric castles were ones with at least two layers of walls surrounding them. In this case, his bastion would gain another layer of regular walls along with separate barriers and generators powering them. Even if one protective wall fell there was another one that his troops could retreat behind. In a way, this was turning into a huge city castle with multiple layers of defenses that could also fly and work underwater.

“It’s going to double in size and even include some residential housing for the soldiers… It can also hold twenty thousand people now, I guess there is no reason not to pick it.”

He was already set on going with the more defensive fortress as that was its main reason for existing. When it came to attacking his sect members and masters would take care of that part. What they needed was a base that people could hide in where they were injured and one that couldn’t be easily breached even from multiple sides. How fast it moved wasn’t really important just how much of a beating it could take.

“Now that I have decided, I should probably post an announcement…”

While he could just spend the points and the transformation would start taking place, he couldn’t just do it while people were outside. The walls would start stretching out and some of the buildings would get shifted around. He wasn’t sure if someone could get crushed or stuck in a wall but it was better to exclude all variables.

“Let’s see…”

After clearing his throat he pressed a button that allowed his voice to go through the whole place. Even though Zhang Jin was here already, he didn’t know what his grandson was planning.

“This is your Patriarch speaking, please move into the inner palace in an orderly fashion. The Golden Dong Palace is going to go through a change so be sure to take all your important belongings with you as they might not be there when you return, that is all.”

The place was mostly populated by military personnel composed of the best experts from his sect. There were no questions asked as they knew that they could trust in the announcement. The only complaints he could see were from Zhang Jin that was interrupted while spending some time with several of his wives.

‘That old fart really changed this into his own harem… that bathing area is bigger than that aqua park I once visited when I was younger…’

“Dong’er, was that you? You could have said something to your dear grandfather!”

“You seemed preoccupied with something else… There is no need for you to do anything, just stay there and wait for everyone else to move into the main palace.”

While the outer areas would be changing, the original palace wouldn’t so it was safe to stay. With his order out he watched people quickly swarming for the main palace gates. They didn’t crowd or push each other and with the help of spatial rings, there wasn’t much luggage that they needed to carry around. Soon after around ten minutes, everyone was safely inside the main hall.

“Let’s get this over with.”

Soon he was pressing the accept button that activated the next step for this Golden Dong Palace. The whole place started rumbling slightly as the change was taking place outside. People that were not stationed inside the flying castle started pointing up at the golden light that was produced. The bright glow masked the transformation slightly but he could clearly see what was happening.

First, the large foundation that looked like a floating island started expanding. The underside was made of something that looked like regular rocks but was just as sturdy as the walls surrounding the whole palace. After this underside was enlarged the walls started popping out from the ground. It was like watching someone assemble something at a hundred times the normal speed. The ground was filled with white tiles that reflected some of the golden structures. This was still the Golden Palace so the motive was kept as it was.

“Everyone is free to go outside, please explore the new palace and make sure that you are familiar with all the new facilities.”

After everything was done he was quick to give the order for everyone to go out. They needed to look through all the new buildings before they descended into the unknown and dark sea. With the expansion of this place, a need for more personnel also arose. Thus the second thing he did was inform Zhang Jin that was meant to lead this place.

“Gramps, I expanded the palace. Be sure to familiarize yourself with the new layout and get new personnel from the main sect. After everything is in order we will be taking this new palace for a spin.”

“Hoh, where are we going with this thing?”

“Where else? Under the sea of course!”

“Under the sea?”

“Yes down where it’s wetter, take it from me…”

“Huh?”

“Ah never mind, just an old song that I remembered. Now, be sure to go through the new floor plans and tell the alchemists and blacksmiths to stock the whole place up, we might be down there for a while and must be ready for any possibility.”

“Don’t worry, I’ll get everything ready.”

“Good.”

After a short conversation with his grandfather he sunk back into his chair. The people outside were already flying all over the place. The moment he gave the order they would normally drop everything that they were doing just to appease him. Luckily this was not out of fear but instead out of reverence.

“I guess it would be bad if I ever disappointed them. Their image of their great patriarch must never be tarnished or the whole place could collapse.”

His image of the glorious leader had to persist. He already saw that his sect was slowly falling apart when he was gone for five years. Now if anything happened to him as long as the basis for his sect was strong, even if he was gone it wouldn’t fall apart like last time.

“Well then, let’s get this show on the road!”

Chapter 623

“Finally it’s time! … But you don’t look too enthusiastic, senior brother, is there something bothering you?”

“Oh it’s nothing, I just don’t like dark places.”

“Ha ha, if you are joking like that then everything must be in order, just call me when I’m needed, I’ll be at the spiritual gym.”

“I’ll be sure to do that.”

Zhang Dong watched Huo Qiang as he left the room he was occupying. In it, he had a nice view of the dark ocean that they were above now. The upgraded flying fortress was in the middle of nowhere. Everything was covered by water and the shoreline was not visible even to someone that could enhance his eyes like him.

After a few weeks of preparation, they had packed up more than half of their army to set out on this attack. His change in mood was noticed by his friend as he did not like the way things were unfolding. The enemies that should be coming in waves weren’t appearing at all. In reality, he predicted them launching an attack in the time they were making their preparations.

‘Could the scenario have changed due to the Emerald Phoenix Emperor’s death? Is it possible that there is some type of hidden difficulty gauge?’

He couldn't discount something like this as he was in the ending phase of driving back the enemy empires. Some games that he played back in his old world had an alternating difficulty where it would change depending on a player's level. Mobs changed to make the game more challenging even when the player gained more and more power.

‘Could she be stronger than the Emerald Phoenix Emperor? It’s a possibility, I should probably be careful and not expect a cakewalk like I previously did.’

From the exchange that his people were having with the fish people, it was clear that they weren’t that strong. When even his regular sect masters could contend with the enemies without his involvement, then it meant that they weren’t the greatest. When he was fighting the demi-humans his forces could only give him some cover fire but would mostly be unable to take care of even the tribe heads. Now, on the other hand, even the named generals of these underwater armies could be soloed by a few of his companions.

‘This might be true but it could also be a cakewalk like with the farty emperor, I just need to watch my back and be ready to teleport everyone out of there when the time comes.’

While he burned through a lot of spirit points to upgrade his flying fortress there were now enough for an emergency retreat. This was one of the reasons he waited close to a month after the defeat of his last foes. Even though he didn’t spend any points on getting his army over to help him, the expenditure for the upgrades to attempt the underwater voyage were just that big.

“Is everyone ready?”

“Aye, they were just waiting for their leader to give them the sign.”

“Well then, without further ado let us depart, make sure the battleships don’t go outside of the outer barrier.”

Zhang Dong contacted Zhang Jin who had become the de facto captain of this palace. He himself was stuck in a more secluded area. Even though he had gotten used to talking to people and commanding them, it didn’t change the fact that he preferred not to do it. Even less when he was already in the company of someone else.

“This is quite the interesting spot you have there.”

“Isn’t it? We can even circle through all the vintage points of this palace.”

His wife Liena was coming for this mission with him. Normally she would be left back home with the kids but with no real threat there it was fine to leave them in the hands of other relatives and his disciples. Through the five-year gap that he was gone some people close to Liena had emerged and they could be trusted with this mission. There were also ways for him or her to go back instantly if any trouble arose.

Thanks to their sect being the governing body of the whole western region the threat was minuscule. Even if someone moved against them, the powerful weapons and protective formations at their base would be able to even stall him for weeks or even months. It was a possibility that the Long Clan could make a move when he was gone yet that would probably not happen.

The main problem with that tactic was his location being shrouded in mystery. He could frequently teleport through various areas thanks to the system and there was no way of telling where he was. His appearance in the eastern region was already a shocker. Before the news was spread he was already back in the main city to make a speech.

Through various teleportation efforts, he was making everyone doubt his true location. They wouldn’t even be sure if the person that traveled to the east was actually him or some other powerful master from his sect. Without proper information, the fable of the Golden Dragon just kept on growing. Bahamut who could move through the whole empire without him was also a force to be reckoned with. Some even believed him to be Long Dong just in his true form.

Thanks to all these diversion tactics he implemented no one could be sure where he was. Without knowing his true position even the Long Clan wouldn’t dare to attack. His system also helped him find all kinds of spies in his main city. To his surprise, there weren’t all that many, and none that actually belonged to the Long Clan.

“It sure is beautiful and terrifying at the same time, some people say that this whole sea could be larger than our entire empire and go down further than the tallest mountain… Hey, are you even listening?”
“Ouch…”

While he was thinking about the strange spy situation and the absence of the Long Clan looking into his sect, a small feminine fist connected with his forehead. Their fortress slowly descended into the dark sea below and Liena was still looking at the sun reflecting in the waves.

She seemed to take it a bit personally that her husband was spacing out on her. During the battle between empires, he had become somewhat distant, always somewhere away and never really interacting with her as much as she wanted to. The last time they had a proper interaction was when he gifted her the new armor and enhanced her power to another level.

“You’re quite daring my dear husband, spacing out when your beautiful wife is right next to you.”

“Ah you know, there were things that I was thinking about.”

“Such as?”

Liena started pushing herself up against him while he was trying to figure out the things to say. While his wife knew some of the facts of his origins he wasn’t sure if she truly believed it all. To begin with, there were many strange powers in this world, so explaining Bob and the system to her was extremely hard.

“That the enemies that we will be facing might be stronger than I expected and that we need to be careful…”

“You worry too much, haven’t you already proven yourself to be the strongest? Can even that little Azure Dragon compare to you at this point.”

“Hey, if they heard you talking like that then …”

“Then what? They would not dare attack us at a time like this, hmph!”

His lovely wife had become quite prideful of her husband that had been missing. It wasn’t strange for people to talk behind her back when he vanished. Some even wanted her to be remarried to another sect master. Luckily he had returned before anything like that could have happened.

“I’m glad that you hold me in such high regard…”

As he attempted to talk her down a bit the whole place began shaking. Their flying ship was hit by some waves as it had become submerged and was now spreading out various barriers to allow the other flying vessels to follow after them. This was the cause for all this shaking and also a little unforeseen mood maker as Liena landed in his arms when trying to hold her balance.

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what to make of this. After taking into consideration that she was a high-level nascent soul master, she would have naturally been able to balance herself out without the need of falling into his arms. The only reason would be that either she was feeling playful or was just that distracted to not do anything about it.

‘Come to think of it… we haven’t really been together that much lately and it will take a lot of time to get to that underwater kingdom…’

His hand moved over to Liena’s thin waist as he tried to hold her closer. After not feeling any resistance he began smiling. No words needed to be said here as he knew his wife well. The place that they were in could only be accessed by a hidden entrance to which only he and now his wife had access.

“I already showed you the console but you haven’t seen the other rooms yet.”

‘Bob, notify me if the Cerulean Empress appears or if there is any trouble that the other sect members can’t happen, if the old fart asks for something, just tell him that I’m busy.’

‘Affirmative.’

Luckily he didn’t have to monitor everything that was happening around this now-submerged fortress. Bob could ring the alarm if something happened and the deed that he would perform here would certainly lower his stress levels. With a little application of his spiritual energy, a previously hidden entrance revealed itself. His hand never left his wife’s waistline as the two headed towards the path that opened. The door then quickly shut behind the pair while no one else was the wiser.

The journey toward the deep unknown had begun and while the grand leader was having some stress relief the people around them were still tense. This was an unprecedented event that had not come to pass at the Empire yet. Many people had attempted to conquer the sea but it always won in the end.

No one knew what to expect to be down there but with this fortress protecting them from all sides, they at least believed that they could make it out in one piece. The teleportation function had been presented to them already and with it as a sort of get away from jail card, they were willing to believe in their safety. Thus they finally departed for possibly their last dangerous mission that was supposed to put an end to this war.

Chapter 624

“Captain’s log, Stardate 800869. After descending into the depths of the sea we have encountered little resistance. The crew had been constantly circulating but was unable to discover any life signs of the enemy fleet. With no fish in sight, we fear for the worst…”

“What are you doing?”

“Huh? I uh… this is…”

Zhang Dong turned off the recording device that he was using to keep himself from being bored. The screen was showing just nothing but darkness in all directions. He wasn’t sure how far down underground they were but it was still going and the bottom of this sea had not presented itself to them.

His troops were able to pick up the path the underwater creatures took back by analyzing their spiritual energy. Everyone usually left behind trace amounts of Qi that could be sensed by some devices but also other cultivators. While masking this signature was possible these fish people certainly didn’t do their due diligence. The path was quite obvious but even after following it for a week, they didn’t find anything.

It was clear that their enemies didn’t expect anyone to dive down so deep and probably without the Golden Dong Palace in its current state it would not have been possible. The sheer amount of water pressure from all sides, coupled with the darkness that could easily disorient anyone made traversing these depths difficult.

“Is it something you picked up from that place you visited?”

“Yes, something like that.”

“Well, I’ll take a stroll around the palace and check up on a few things.”

“Take care.”

After giving his wife a smooch the two parted ways. After a whole week down here some people were getting spooked. They could go outside into the new outer yard of the castle but besides the shining light of the gold palace, everything was covered in darkness. There were no sounds from the outside and a battle could break out at any moment. Without knowing how long this would take, even the veterans were getting affected.

‘The palace isn’t the fastest but we have been going down at around a seventy-degree angle, this depth is quite staggering, how far does this sea even go?’

He could only continue to monitor the surroundings with his own superior senses while waiting for Bob to give him some kind of warning. Luckily with his system ever present he could check up on the state of the empire and confirm that nothing had changed. Now that they were a week into this dive, it would have been the perfect chance to attack their main city.

Nothing had happened, his previous assumption that the Long Clan was planning something was wrong. Now on the other hand he was concerned that they were acting strange. This was the perfect chance to make a move but perhaps his random teleportation escapades kept everything safe.

‘I hope that I’m just overthinking this and it will all be over after I take care of the Cerulean Empress. Though first, I have to actually find here… this trail could be a dead end too.’

At first glance it looked like the Cerulean Empire forces didn’t care about being found as the trail they left was quite obvious. This of course could have been a red herring. He could not discount the possibility of this being a path toward some type of trap or a wild goose chase that would take them nowhere and give his enemies enough time to regain their forces. Though after more than a month's passing since the last attack, he wasn’t sure if they needed more time to create more clones.

‘Maybe they just run out of ingredients for their classes, there don’t seem to be any fish left here, haven’t encountered any of those sea kings either. Could they have just used up all of them for the attacks?’

While pondering he looked at one of the screens and began waiting. There was nothing there and so it remained until they finally arrived at a new location. This location seemed to be at the ocean floor that was finally reached after another week of deep diving. His senses and the palace's detectors also picked up something interesting. The sea here was quite unruly and in the distance, the currents seemed to bend in unnatural ways. This was coupled with a surge of spiritual energy very familiar to him.

“Is this the edge of our empire’s sea?”

He asked himself while trying to compare the underwater current storm to the elemental one that separated the western region and the demi-human empire. It was very similar which made him believe that going any further than this would not be possible. Even the enhanced shielding of his fortress would be minced into pieces if he tried going through it. On the other side was probably where the Cerulean Empress and her forces came from.

“But I don’t see any bridges…”

The map that he copied from the Long Clan wasn’t very detailed when it came to this region. There was a giant red blob in the entire region which made it very hard to pinpoint the bridge from a glance. Now that he was here he finally realized why this bridge was somewhat unique.

While they were down on the ocean floor there was still somewhere that they could go. A huge chasm was down below and that was also where the trail was going towards. When looking even further it became clear that the enemy combatants would probably be somewhere down there,

“So they got in here through that… maybe beyond this blockade there isn’t really anything and this ‘Empire’ was hidden below this chasm but still within the Azure Empire's borders?”

He asked himself these questions while the golden palace was coming to a stop. It was possible to take a bit to come up with a strategy and also shed some light on this entire place. However even though the large lights from all the other ships and even the palace tried to pierce down into the giant hole, no bottom could be spotted. Soon enough he decided to leave this personal cabin and join his wife and all the other high-standing masters from his sect.

“What do you think?”

“I think that we are getting closer, what are we waiting for senior brother? Let us descend and get those damn sea monsters!”

“Why don’t you think for a moment? That chasm is wide but our maneuverability will be severely decreased if we go down there… what if it’s a trap?”

“A trap? This Huo Qiang doesn’t fear any traps, let them try!”

“How this idiot became the head of the Huo Clan and a founding elder at our sect…”

“Hah, if you are scared then you can stay here, me and my senior brother are enough to clear a path.”

“Don’t you even dare to talk about taking my husband along for a silly plan like that.”

“Uh… please you two, calm down… you are kind of making it hard for all the other elders to speak…”

Zhang Liena and Huo Qiang were back to arguing while everyone else could do nothing more than a glance. When the three founding grand elders were talking there was no space for anyone else to raise their voice. Now even less when Zhang Dong was also here, before the Zhang clan and the Huo clan sides would start arguing.

“If it was possible I’d like to send out a scouting vessel first. What if they placed some bombs on the walls to cave them in after we descend inside.”

Zhang Jin commented and the other elders started nodding. It was a reasonable assumption and a very old strategy everyone was familiar with.

“Isn’t this the only way out for them, would they block their only path outside just to get to us?”

This time Huo Qiao, one of the more faithful members and previously personal bodyguard of Huo Qiang, spoke out. In his eyes, the Cerulean Empress would risk losing access to the mainlands that she was trying to conquer if she caved in this place.

“Elders, the preliminary analyzation of the rocky formations has been done, a cave is not a probable event, the walls are just too hard to be broken, it’s like a natural barrier of heavenly might not much different than our own shielding technology.”

Another elder from the science department chimed in informing everyone of their surface-level analysis.

“If what they say is true then we should proceed inside, sending a scout vessel in these conditions will be hard, without the Golden Dong Palace our ships won’t be able to take the pressure of the sea.”

Zhang Dong decided to sit back and let his people decide on the best plan. There was no need for him to get involved in all of the decisions, moderating the conversations was enough. With him here the conversation couldn’t devolve into a shouting match like it did before his return.

The only downside of this method was that if he ever went away then things would probably go back to the old ways. He had not been able to think of a good solution for this problem but at least for the time he was here, he would make sure that things continued in this fashion.

“I think we have come to a decision then? Judging by the fact that it would be suicide for a smaller vessel to travel in so deep we will push forth with the palace.”

Everyone nodded as after an hour of deliberations they had come to a conclusion. While nascent soul masters and maybe some stronger core formation experts were able to resist the pressure, they still needed air to breathe. Some could hold out more than others but they would certainly not be able to sustain themselves on their spiritual energy forever.

Producing air with the Dao of air was possible but also draining without any natural air pockets around. Sooner or later everyone would succumb and suffocate. The gold fortress they arrived in had many plantlife that could produce oxygen and also some other devices to speed up the process.

“Let us depart then, be sure to light the path as the enemies could be coming for us from any direction.”

“As you command Patriarch!”

Thus the descent into the great unknown continued, what was down in the large chasm was unknown to them. They would certainly need to be careful as they were going to fight in the lands that were the home territory of the Cerulean Empire, a place they had never seen before.

Chapter 625

‘I don’t like this…’

Zhang Dong decided to step out of the protective layer of the inner shield. There most of his forces had retreated and the ships that were left outside were keeping a tight formation around the golden fortress. It was possible for some unforeseen attack to come out of any direction while they were descending into the chasm. Yet even after a whole day had passed nothing seemed to be happening.

‘Could they have actually fled back to their own Empire? Following them there would probably not be the smartest move, is there even another empire, or did they come from this side?’

A few theories were floating around in his head. The first theory was about the Cerulean Empire not really existing outside of the Azure Empire. There was a possibility of them just being locked away in a large underground cavern that this massive gush on the sea floor represented. Perhaps if they continued they would arrive at a whole new underground world filled with strange monstrosities they were ill-equipped to handle.

The other possibility was that this was just their temporary headquarters just like it was for all the other Empires. The bridge they arrived through would be somewhere down there. This would make this large chasm they were going through something that had already been here for millenia.

‘It will be better if it’s the second option, I don’t think my people can face an entire Empire filled with enemies. If they were able to make all those clones on this side, I can only imagine what numbers they must have back there.’

Thus he decided to go outside to start his spiritual sense. If something started going wrong he needed to pull his forces back and perhaps think about another solution for the situation. Perhaps defeating the Cerulean Empress was not something possible and their forces would act as constantly increasing waves that he needed to contend with. Now that he found the chasm they were all coming from, perhaps creating an underwater stronghold would be possible.

Yet before he could make his decision they needed to get to the bottom of this place. considering that they were traveling at a slower pace than before it could have taken them a bit longer to get to the bottom of this problem. However, he had a bad premonition that took him outside and this time around he was right.

“Hm?... What is that… I’m sensing something but it’s weird…”

‘Hey Bob, are you picking it up?’

*Trying to identify anomalies… Life signals detected… caution is advised.*

For a while, he wasn’t able to sense anything but in just a second he was getting overwhelmed by the number of beings. It was as if they were waiting for them to get closer. Could have this been a trap or something else?
‘These life signs are strange, it’s as if they are all separate from each other but also part of something bigger… it’s as if…’

Everything was dark in this place and even his spiritual sense was incapable of painting a picture in his mind. Because of all these factors he was unable to make the right decision and blundered. The cavern they were diving into started to open up into a huge chamber filled with even more darkness.

‘What’s that glow…’

Inside this darkness, a glowing circle of light was pulsating as if trying to guide him towards the right path. The whole fortress was traveling the pathway of the leftover spiritual energy and that too was guiding them toward this destination. Perhaps if the light wasn’t so enticing he would have noticed that there was something off about it. While it looked like it was getting larger in actuality there was something else happening.

‘Is it getting closer? Oh, shit… are those… are those supposed to be teeth?’

“Everyone, this is an order from your Patriarch, evacuate from the ships and quickly gather up in the fortress.”

What he spotted was quite gruesome. The light show was just there to lure them into the maw of the beast. What he was looking at was a gigantic angler fish that was many times larger than their whole armada of ships and the golden fortress combined. The teeth were the size of mountains and while the guiding light was dangling before them, those chompers were spreading apart to draw them in.

No one asked questions as they quickly started trying to land with their ships. The fortress was now floating on a large piece of land that left enough outside for them to create a landing strip. After getting there the people could quickly run inside into the more tightly protected inner fortress. This was easier said than done though as the massive beast outside was causing quite a stir.

‘How huge is this thing… I can’t really see where the mouth starts or begins, just teeth…’

The creature was of unprecedented size, Zhang Dong had never seen something like this before. The sheer size was incomprehensible and the amount of spiritual energy this thing possessed was even greater than him. This was something above the level of the nascent soul and perhaps it would be their grave if he didn’t do something about it.

However, even though he ordered a full retreat the golden fortress was unable to pull away. Coupled with the opening mouth a giant suction force was created that was even drawing the city-sized stronghold inside. At this point, the only thing that he could do was to minimize the damage and use his own energy to boost the outer shields that were about to slam into one of those mountainous teeth.

“Senior brother!”

“Husband!”

“Stay back you two, I’ll be fine.”

Both Huo Qiang and Zhang Liena came outside to help him. Yet without his permission, they were not able to get outside of the inner barrier that needed to be kept up. The outside one could break at any moment so he could not risk opening the path outside. The people that had landed on the strip were still able to get inside just not leave.

Suddenly all hell broke loose as the golden fortress tumbled inside the massive mouth of the anglerfish. The beast outside didn’t really react but remained stationary as if waiting for the next prey to arrive. The glowy appendage that it used to lure its prey inside started going out and nothing but silence and darkness remained in this cold place.

…

“ARGH…”

‘I need to hold it, not everyone made it inside…’

Back on the inside, the whole palace was going through a strange torrent of water. They had been swallowed by this giant creature and were now inside its mouth. Normally what Zhang Dong was expecting to do was be sent into the beast's stomach while keeping the barrier up. As long as it didn’t fail them there was a chance of getting out of this whole place alive. However, there was something strange after the beast had swallowed them he noticed something.

‘That was a spatial resonance?’

It was similar to the Dimensional Regalia that he had increased the size to a continent. This place was giving him similar vibes but before he could figure out what was really going on a powerful crushing force attacked them from all slides. The outer barrier began shrinking instantly as it was being pushed back. His main problem was now the people that were evacuated to the inside. He gathered all of his power and everyone that was inside the golden fortress did the same. Even though all of them tried, the bubble burst and the outer barrier collapsed.

“Shittttttttttt……”

Zhang Dong felt a lot of strange pressure being pushed onto his body as the protective layer disappeared. He was tossed all over the place while trying to remain steady. Before he could activate the system's teleportation feature to go into the golden fortress he felt it vanishing from sight. His whole body was then tossed somewhere far, he could feel everyone instantly vanishing to some distant location before everything went dark once more.

…

“Uhg… my head… did I actually pass out for a moment?”
This was not something that happened often but the forces inside of this strange creature had given him a headache. After the barrier collapsed he could feel various things clashing against his body and in his weakened state he had become more susceptible to them. But for some reason, he could feel a warm tingling feeling over his body. He was not trapped in what was supposed to be a monster fish’s belly but instead somewhere comfortable.

“What is this place?”

Zhang Dong was greeted by a vast plain of grass. In the distance, he could see a forest area and even mountains. When looking up, there was even something that looked like a sun. However, his keen senses couldn’t be fooled as he identified the orb to just be an imitation.

‘Bob, It seems that I have found myself in some type of pocket dimension… could it be possible that that creature that had swallowed us wasn’t an actual living being?’

*Calculating… The possibility is at 84.56%*

‘Yeah that’s what I thought, that thing must have been the real entrance to the Cerulean Empire, they must have used it to arrive at this place.’

After putting a few things together he realized that the creature in itself didn’t really possess any life in it. The life signals were coming from within it where all the people from the Cerulean Empire were probably located. The monster anglerfish was something more similar to his own golden fortress or ships, some type of fleshy construct that transported people through its mouth to this location.

It didn’t look like a place that would be populated by undersea creatures. There were a lot of rivers and even lakes all over the place but the air was quite breathable. One part was worrisome as he couldn’t really get a feel for where everyone else was. Also while there were living beings around this place, they were just simple animals without really anything similar to a cultivator nearby.

‘It doesn’t matter, I should be able to teleport back to the palace.’

*Error error.*

‘Or not?’

A problem arose, when trying to access his faction system he was unable to. For some reason, it was being blocked and all the ways of teleporting out were locked. This could only mean that he had come across some type of event that was prepared for a system holder and that it might not be as easy to end this war as he had previously thought.

Chapter 626

“This sure looks like a nice place to retire, but I’m not sure the wifey would want to live inside a giant anglerfish.”

Zhang Dong joked out loud while slowly floating through the place. At first glance, this was quite the paradise, with nice trees, and green grass that a person could just relax and sleep on while the sun’s rays hit their face. Lakes with clear water filled with various fish that would make all sushi chefs dreams come true.

‘Everyone else should have made it to the palace, if I survived then they should be fine too just at a different location. There should not be a reason to rush…’

While going through this place he was trying to calm down his own nerves. This time around a lot more people had come for this supposed last battle. Zhang Liena, his wife was there which caused him to worry even more. In theory, the golden palace wouldn’t be easily breached even by someone like Wang Long. However, with his faction system being blocked by something he could not check nor teleport back to their location.

‘Bob, can you explain why the system isn’t working?’

‘Data inconclusive, a spatial anomaly has been detected and is interfering with the system. The system needs to analyze the data before an assessment can be made.’

‘I figured as much, it’s never easy.’

There was some type of anomaly that had been triggered when he entered this place and it made him worry even more as he was part of something similar in the past. Then one instance of the system becoming bugged had transpired. This was when he was sent off into the other world as just his soul. Back then he could also not reach his old faction as he was in a whole other world.

‘It couldn’t be that I’m in another world again?’

He stopped while trying to use all of his senses. During the previous event of him traversing between worlds, his soul was ripped away from his body. He was only able to survive thanks to his involvement with the system and powerful pure soul. Then when he returned, Bob helped him reform his old body at the cost of most of his cultivation and old resources.

‘This isn’t like it… I am clearly in the same world, the energies here are the same, it must just be some type of pocket dimension that might be above the level of even the Dimensional Regalia.’

After some deliberating, he came to a conclusion. He had been tossed into a pocket dimension that had some similarities to the other worlds but was not quite there. Perhaps there were other ones like it that kept him away from his golden palace where everyone else was. If he was able to find his path there then at least some of the faction system features would open up.

‘That should be the case, but if I’m being blocked from even teleporting back to the sect, then even if I find everyone, we won’t be able to retreat. I guess this has to have been prepared beforehand or…’

In his mind, this place was prepared for some type of event by the powers that made this world. It had been probably designed before he even arrived in this world. The only other reasonable explanation would be that the overseer was responsible and she made a few changes to make things more difficult.

‘Perhaps I was doing too well for my own good? But that shouldn’t be the case, with the old system in place taking care of the Emerald Phoenix Emperor shouldn’t have been that hard either.’

He could only speculate while moving through these locations. His first attempt at getting out of this place was to fly straight up into the air. From the ground, it looked like this place had a normal blue sky along with a star shining over it. Yet after he got up to around twenty kilometers he hit an invisible wall.

Before giving it a good old punch he decided to let Bob run a few tests. It was not a formation barrier but something else. It felt like the end of the world imposed by whoever made this spatial space. One thing was clear, even without giving it a thwack he knew that he would not be able to force his way through. This thing was something on the immortal level and would not be damaged by someone that was still at the nascent soul realm.

‘I guess I’ll have to find a pathway instead…’

When glancing up he could see the glowing orb that represented the sun. It was further behind the invisible wall in an unreachable location to him. This somewhat reminded him about the trial area he had died before and was freed from his system. It could be the case that it was similar to that.

‘If this place was made by the same person that made this world, then one of those cubes should be here to power it all. Maybe if I can find it and remove it, then it will collapse on itself…’

If he managed to grab the power source he would attain a large number of spirit points. However, there was a danger of removing something that was creating a pocket dimension. Without enough energy to sustain it, there was a possibility of it shrinking on itself and even imploding.

Perhaps he had enough power to shield himself from harm and leave through the thinned-out walls but what about the people that he came here with? If they were wandering outside just like he was now, then their lives were at risk. Staying in the golden palace and waiting for his return would be the best option for survival but he could not count on his people being passive. Liena along with Qiang were probably already out and searching for him. They could also be in trouble, this was in fact the place where the Cerulean Empress resided.

*WARNING, WARNING*

“Huh?”

While floating up in the air and touching the invisible wall, a strange shift in the environment occurred. First, he noticed that the wind had picked up and it wasn’t just a little summer breeze, this wind was sharp as a razor blade. Thanks to his recent gains of new Dao’s he was barely able to dodge the mass of wind blades that appeared out of nowhere.

‘These attacks are coming from behind the invisible wall? Did I trigger some type of defensive measure by coming so close to it?’

He wasn’t sure but the more he stayed up there the more turbulence he spotted. It was as if this place didn’t want him here, considering he reached the end of the map by going straight up this made sense. If this was some type of trial that had to be done, getting out through another location had to be forbidden.

Soon the temperature up in the air started to drop below zero and the fake star that was in the sky vanished. Something was triggered and he wasn’t sure if the process could be reversed as when it started to descend down, a blizzard had formed. All the nice green trees and nice lakes were instantly frozen over and when he was back down everything looked much different.

‘It’s like an apocalyptic wasteland now… wait, I sense something…’

After surrounding himself with a barrier of holy energy to keep the cold winds away, he noticed a new event. From the frozen lakes that had a few minutes ago been filled with various fish, a monster emerged. It looked similar to the humanoid fish people that were part of the Cerulean Empire army.

‘No it’s similar but quite more powerful than the drones my people encountered…’

The creature was much bigger than the counterpart that was encountered above ground. The scaly skin looked like it was made from dragon scales and its power was above that of core formation. When this monster fish noticed the golden glow it instantly was tossed into a maddened rage. Without giving Zhang Dong a moment to relax it charged forward.

It had powerful arms and webbed hands which ended with claw-like nails. Before it even got close it discharged a stream of yellow-green liquid from its mouth. Without even blinking he dodged to the side, the discharge hit the iced-over ground behind him and quickly dug into it.

‘Is that acid?’

Normally he would have stayed in place and just let the attack bounce off his holy shield but for some reason, it gave him a bad premonition. To test this theory he sends a secondary barrier in the path of the follow-up attack. The radiant glow was intensified after the corrosive substance collided with it. He expected it to evaporate or at least be bounced back onto the ground but instead, it persisted on his shield. The fluid started slowly dissolving the barrier he created, a feat that shouldn’t be possible.

‘This creature isn’t that strong, how can it disperse my Qi this easily?’

While the attack was able to get through his defenses, the creature was not up to par with his skills. A few dodges later he decided to create a sword of light to remove the fish's ugly head. Without it, the monster fell to the ground and quickly started turning into the same yellow-green substance. It was quite dead but the hole it left behind was becoming deeper as the ground wasn’t even able to contend with this strange liquid.

‘It must have some Qi dispersing properties along with eroding attributes, as long as I keep recreating the shield it won’t get through but I’m not sure if I’d be able to survive for long in a pool of that substance.’

The first enemy that appeared was dead but it wasn’t the only one. He wasn’t sure if this was due to him trying to escape through underhanded means or if it was a trap created from the start. Nevertheless, now he was feeling multiple creatures like the one that just attacked him appearing all over the place. They were all jumping out of the now frozen-over rivers and lakes to attack him.

‘I can’t let them surround me…’

While he was closer to the ground and the blizzard made it hard to move, he needed to get out of here. It would be over for him if he just remained in one place where the monsters could surround him. Thus after choosing a path he took for the skies. The monsters down on the ground in unison started spitting the strange goop toward him. Even with the winds raging they were capable of using their attacks like high-speed projectiles.

‘I think I saw something this way… I hope they don’t encounter these creatures…’

With a heavy heart he pushed onwards, what he needed to do now was find his people that were perhaps ill-equipped to fight these creatures for a prolonged time. Even the shield of his improved fortress might not be able to contend with these acidic attacks.

Chapter 627

A giant white claw descended from up top. Its swipe caused a massive blizzard and sharp ice fragments to fly in all directions. The aim of this massive sharp appendage was a sphere of golden light in front of it. Yet when it collided with this radiant orb of golden energy instead of cutting through it the claws broke into many smaller pieces.

The creature that the large claw belonged to revealed itself to be an ice dragon. While the pain from losing its claws was excruciating it didn’t stop with its attack. Its large toothy mouth opened up wide to produce a dragon breath attack which these types of creatures were known for. It flew forward and produced even more cold energy that this place was already filled with.

Yet the man inside the ball of golden light didn’t move an inch. Instead of evading he propelled himself toward the attack. The protective barrier he was surrounding himself with pushed all the frozen flames to the sides. His entire form propelled itself into the monster’s mouth before it could even close it. Then within a matter of moments, the dragon began to inflate like a giant balloon. Soon the golden light the man was clad in burst from within and signaled the death of this creature.

“Can you just leave me alone, this is getting annoying…”

Zhang Dong looked at the pink chunks of flesh that were bursting around him turn to icicles the moment the dragon was dead. He was still stuck in the area he arrived in and ever since he attempted to check the sky of this pocket dimension the monsters were after him. Usually, these types of traps had some type of end but there was no end to it.

‘They aren’t strong but there are a lot of them… Will my spiritual energy hold up without me being able to recover? I need to find some kind of safe haven where I can rest.’

Even though he was a master that reached a realm that was slightly above the nascent soul, he was not invincible. His spiritual energy reserves were finite and sooner or later he would also run out of pills to recover. Already half a week had passed since he arrived in this place and the beasts just continued to come at him.

First, it was the frozen versions of the undersea soldiers that he was more familiar with but then more varied ones appeared. Ice Dragons, Ice Tigers, and Ice Serpents were only some of the creatures he had to contend with. Some were weak, others were strong and even close to his level. Coupled with the harsh weather that would freeze him to the bone if he decided to drop his protective barrier, it was a troublesome trial of attrition.

He could not sleep as the monsters were somehow able to always pinpoint his location. Even when he used his new Dao of darkness to hide himself, they always found him. There was probably something guiding them to his location as he did not belong to this place. Even with the best hiding skills he was unable to keep even the smaller beasts from finding him. Thus he was forced to travel through these strange lands in hopes of finding an exit.

‘Luckily the mapping feature is still working, at least I won’t get lost like this.’

The visibility of this place was also abysmal. Even when straining his eyes he could not see more than around a hundred meters in all directions. If he was at the core formation stage he would probably not be able to see anything above ten. The blizzard was constantly blowing crystal shards in his face and the temperature was at around minus hundred degrees celsius.

‘If this is another immortal treasure, then the space inside could be huge, we never managed to fully repair the Dimensional Regalia, could this place be a finished product or maybe even multiple treasures in one?’

Considering that he could not feel any presence of his sect members even before the whole place turned into a giant ice cage, it could be possible that these pocket dimensions were separated from each other. He could be going through several Dimensional Regalia-type pocket dimensions with each being the size of the old planet he came from. Luckily he was capable of flight at high speeds.

‘Hm? What’s that?’

Only thanks to the mapping feature of his system was he able to fly in one direction. Without it around he feared that he would go around in circles until all of his Qi reserves ran out. This was probably the way this place intended to bury him by disorientation and continuous waves of beasts.

‘It looked like a tower… Can’t even see the end of it…’

Finally, he arrived at something that looked like a structure. It was a massive tower that stretched into the sky. Due to all the ice and blizzard, it looked like a giant tower made of blue crystal but when he squinted he could see the rocky outlines inside.

‘This could be the way out…’

When looking behind he saw some more strange creatures charging at his location. The tower made of ice crystals looked to be quite thick, at least a kilometer in diameter. This was the only reason that he could see it with the blizzard storm still raging around him. Without thinking too much he decided to investigate further as it was the first actual building he managed to come across.

‘I hope it won’t be a dead end like some of those caves…’

Previously he discovered a couple of large caves yet besides a mass of angry monsters inside he didn’t find anything substantial. A large structure like this had to be placed for some type of reason. It could be his way out of this frozen hell hole. Thus he sped towards it with utmost care. From his experience, he knew that a potential trap or encounter with a powerful beast was probable.

“Hm? Are you not going to follow after me?”

To his surprise it was the reverse, the moment he arrived at the bottom of the giant icicle, the monsters that were behind him started chasing him. It was as if they were being kept away by another invisible barrier that surrounded the whole palace. This was mostly confirmed by the perfect circle they made around this place without any of them being able to take even one step inside.

‘I could probably kill them all now, they are sitting ducks just standing like that… but it might not be wise to waste my energy on trash mobs like these.’

This would have been a nice place to farm for spirit points if he ever had his old system. Without it, killing the monsters was somewhat meaningless. He also considered that more and more were appearing before him. Taking the cloning technology that the Cerulean Empire was known for, there would be another swarm waiting to replace these if he killed them.

‘There is an entrance…’

Instead, he turned around to face the crystal-like ice, with a swipe of his finger he was able to cut a rectangular opening to get to the entrance gate. There was no writing to indicate that this was some type of test.

‘Hm, usually these types of places have some warning or a tip about what is inside… perhaps the person who made this didn’t expect any visitors?’

Before going in he took one last look at the monsters behind him. They were just staring at him with those lifeless eyes of theirs. Thanks to his knowledge of the soul arts he knew that these beings were nothing more than hollow husks. There was nothing in them and they were purely moving on instinct. Only a tiny fraction of what used to be a soul remained inside and it was probably left there by whoever created them.

“Sad creatures…”

For some reason, he didn’t feel any fear when looking at these beats, only sorrow and sadness. This could be his future if he ever stopped fighting and also when he decided to reach the next stage. He was still convinced that the being that set this whole thing out couldn’t be doing it out of the goodness of their hearts.

His idea of the reason didn’t surface yet but he had a few theories. The one that was winning was due to the concept of boredom. Perhaps this entity was just entertaining itself due to its immortality. An immortal lifespan might have seemed in theory but then what would happen after a million years? Everything that could have been done on this plane of existence could have been achieved. There would be nothing more than performing the same mundane tasks with no goal.

For the time being he had things that he wanted to do. But after everything was secured his long lifespan might become problematic. Even though this empire was huge, what would he do for a thousand years? Then potentially after he ascended he might become an actual immortal. Would he go crazy or would his mind be somewhat able to cope with all the time he had on his hands?

‘Why do I always ponder these existential questions when I’m out in places like this, I need to focus on the current problems, living for too long will probably be the least of my problems.’

After getting all the ice from the entrance gate he gave it a push. The thing started buckling under the pressure but needed a few well-placed kicks to actually open up. If someone of his stature had trouble opening this thing up then anyone that wasn’t a nascent soul master at the later stages would be out of luck.

The stony gate slammed open while he prepared to take on any potential hidden attacks. Yet instead of any attacks, only darkness greeted him. Thanks to his newly gained Dao he knew that he didn’t have anything to fear. No monsters of the night that would be able to previously sneak up on him could remain undetected.

‘This is not a tower of any kind… this energy… It’s a gate?’

When he began approaching the entrance he could feel something tugging at his body. At first, he planted his feet firmly in the frozen ground but soon after he began to move inside. This place would not give him any trials, it was just a passageway through which he would reach another destination. Thus he accepted the pull and quickly vanished into the darkness.

‘I hope all the others are on the other end…’

He could feel getting dragged through some kind of passageway. It was somewhat similar to going through a teleportation gate but not quite. His body was actually flying through a weird dark corridor that sometimes produced a purple haze. Without his Qi shield raised, he would have already been torn to shreds. He could only hope that this led somewhere, otherwise getting stuck in an endless tunnel might be the end of his journey.

Chapter 628

“Woahhhhhh…”

Zhang Dong could feel his body being tossed around through this space like a pinball. He could not imagine anyone else surviving this treatment or at least not anyone that wasn’t prepared for it. Perhaps there was a way of traveling in a normal fashion but after he triggered the blizzard it might have become inaccessible to him.

‘Bob, are you sure this is safe?’

‘Affirmative, we will be reaching the exit in 3… 2… 1…’

His Ai partner informed him about the safety of this dimensional tunnel so he decided to take the plunge. After the countdown was finally over he could see something at the end of this strange tunnel. Soon he was able to stop holding his breath as his body appeared outside, in an area with increased temperature.

“Where did I end up now? Bob, be sure to inform me if there are any more beasts nearby.”

Zhang Dong popped out in the middle of the ground and had to stop himself from being thrown up into the air. The first thing he noticed was the heat, it was a stark contrast to the desolate lands filled with snow that he came from.

“About thirty degrees I would say? A good temperature to take a dip… and it seems that someone has already decided to do so…”

To his surprise, he could quickly feel the presence of living beings. There was no way of seeing these beings with his own eyes but they were certainly not human. Previously he had analyzed the underwater creatures that plagued their lands and these were similar in nature. Their Qi was a lot purer than what he was used to, even the generals that were at the pinnacle of power didn’t have this pure.

‘Considering that all of that army was made out of clones, could these be the original denizens from the Cerulean Empire?’

This was one of the theories floating around his head yet for a place that should belong to the royal family, it wasn’t very well protected. The spiritual energy coming from these creatures was quite low, they were around the level of core formation experts at the early stage. Even his old self that just arrived into this world would be able to handle them in combat.

‘Their strength won’t be a problem, but those two energies with them…’

To his surprise, the creatures that were there weren’t alone. He could feel a familiar presence. It was only two people but they were of the nascent soul variety. For some reason, they were surrounded by the being there. It didn’t seem that they were injured or anything but it was very suspicious that they would just be sitting there with the enemy.

‘Could they be under some type of spell? or could these people be non-violent or something?’

Zhang Dong really hoped that his somewhat calm way of approaching things rubbed of on his sect members. Yet this scene that was unfolding before him was kind of strange. Considering that the last place he came from turned into a death trap of ice, it could be possible that his companions were being duped. Perhaps this time around he would be able to use his Dao of darkness to erase his presence.

Thanks to it he could sink into all the shadows that the strange trees here were producing. It was a strange movement technique that allowed him to approach without making a sound. Thus he quickly departed towards the area that had his sect members and potential brain-sucking monsters. Perhaps the nascent soul masters that were there would be under their control, so he had to prepare for a fight with them. Subduing them could be tricky as one of the people there was quite strong.

“...”

‘What the hell are those two doing there?’

Finally, he was there, hiding in the shadows as an inconspicuous blur. What he saw when he arrived at the spot was truly baffling. The two energy signatures that he recognized belonged to Zhang Jin and Huo Qiang. The latter posed an actual threat if he engaged in a proper battle so he wanted to make sure that there wasn’t any trickery here. Yet, instead of someone being controlled by some demonic spells, the two seemed to be having a swell old time.

“No~”

“Come here, he he he, I’m going to get ya~”

“Pervert!~”

“Yes, guilty as charged!”

On one side he could see his grandfather slowly chasing after one of the beings that he previously felt. This person looked like a beautiful woman from the waist up but had a large fishtail instead of legs. It was a beautiful mermaid, like in the stories that he read. She even had a bra made out of seashells like that famous one with red hair he still remembered. At this time, she was being very playful with his grandfather who had a very perverted look on his face.

When he glanced to the other side he saw Huo Qiang partially submerged in water as well. He was resting his hands on the edge with one mermaid on each side resting on them. There was a certain grin covering his face as he was trying to take a peek at the large peaks that these two fishy women had. It seemed that these two were enamored with these lovely ladies, considering that these two were horn balls by default he was not sure if they were actually under any mind-affecting technique.
‘I can’t throw out that possibility yet…’

Zhang Dong knew that he couldn’t be hasty. Even though he wanted to just jump in there and give the two idiots a good smack on the head, he couldn’t. It was possible that something down in that environment was making them act like this. It could be the mermaids themselves but could also be the food they were eating or even the water they were in.

All of them were gathered in what looked to be a lake. The water was really clear and some other mermaids were seen in the deeper parts just having some fun with the other fish. It was some kind of tropical setting, the trees were somewhat similar to palm trees. It had some strange pink-looking fruits on them that Huo Qiang seemed to be munching on.

It was quite bright outside and the light source over them looked quite real. He remembered the moment that he flew up to the other one in the other pocket dimension. There was a possibility that he would trigger another ice age if he flew up there again or that it could be triggered by his interaction with the natives.

First of all he needed to identify the fruits. After sinking back into the shadows he arrived at one of these trees with the fruit already on the ground. Thanks to it being surrounded by shade it was easy enough for him to pull it right in. Bob was initiated to give it an assessment and just as he thought there was something in this food.

‘So, it’s something like an aphrodisiac?’

‘Affirmative.’

‘How did those goofballs end up eating these…’

By the look of it, the fruit was a potent drug even nascent soul masters weren’t safe from it. Yet the preliminary analysis told him that it shouldn’t be enough to make them lose their mind and just take a dip with the enemy troops. Next he approached one of the mermaids that had decided to sunbathe a bit. With a little poke to her forehead he sent her into a deep slumber and quickly made the second test.

‘So… their vocal cords have some type of hallucinogenic effect that could work in conjunction with that aphrodisiac?’

‘Affirmative.’

Bob answered him again while he moved away from the sleeping mermaid. After analyzing some other things, like the water in the lake he came to one conclusion. All of the things here were tailor made to take out these two idiots. They would only work on people that couldn’t keep it inside of their pants for too long. The small amount of substances here should normally not be able to force a nascent soul master to act this way. There was only one reason that it actually was, the two must have wanted it to happen.

This didn’t make any sense otherwise, why would they have fallen into such an obvious trap. Even though some of the mermaids were producing a very sensual tune it wasn’t hard to block out. It was as if the two arrived in this place and allowed themselves to be enticed by these beauties just so that they could have some fun with them. Perhaps if it was any other person he wouldn’t believe it but considering that these two had harems of women everywhere, this was quite plausible.

‘The possibility of a hidden expert doing this to them isn’t very high…’

Bob confirmed all of his claims as the two weren’t showing the telltale signs of being coerced. Normally their eyes would be a lot more droopy and the way they moved would be impaired by something. On the other hand, the two looked quite chipper; they were probably just trying to get something out of these encounters. It was probably them that were trying to coerce these mermaids into some naughty acts and not the other way around.

‘Uh… are they playing stupid and hoping that they would commit to something more?’

Zhang Dong frowned while stepping out of the shadows. He was standing directly over Huo Qiang who was trying to peel off one of the mermaid's shells from her chest. Before anything could happen his large fist connected with the man’s head. The force from the impact plunged him directly into the ground while causing water to splash everywhere.

“What the hell are you two idiots even doing? Get ahold of yourself!”

“D-Dong’er is that you?”

“Don’t you Dong’er me you old fart, stop chasing that mermaid already!”

He started shaking his Qi-covered fist at his grandfather that was close to two hundred years older than he was. The moment he appeared on the scene the mermaids that were gathered here started scattering to the sides out of fright. They quickly dove into the lake and headed to some underwater tunnels that it was connected to. It seemed that there was a large web of those underground.

These Zhang Dong had somewhat investigated with his spiritual sense and there was a possibility of them leading to their next destination. However, before he attempted to get through this pocket dimension he needed to get some information out of these two bozos. They were clearly inside the golden palace before they were swallowed by the large anglerfish, he needed to know how they ended up here.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 629

“Senior brother, can we at least get off the ground?”

“No, you can’t and if you ask me again, I’m going to deck you in the nose.”

Zhang Dong shook his fist at Huo Qiang who was forced to kneel down on the ground before him. To the left of the muscular man was an older gentleman that was doing the same. His face already had a fist imprint on it that he was rubbing.

“How could you hit your dear and only grandfather?”

“Keep talking like that and I won’t have any grandfathers left.”

“So cruel…”

Zhang Jin moved his face to the side to face Huo Qiang. He covered his mouth to send a message to his partner in crime that Zhang Dong was able to quickly intercept.

‘I think Dong’er is a little mad, let’s give him some time to relax, just follow my lead.’

‘I’ll leave it to you elder.’

“Dong’er it’s…ack.”

“I heard all of that, you two idiots. Instead of trying to fool me, how about you explain how you ended up here? Where are the others? Where are the Golden Palace and the other sect members?”

His fists rained down on their heads before they could try to bullshit their way through all of it. He continued to berate the two until they gave in, their heads began to spin around from the impacts. Zhang Dong's fists were quite heavy, even when he was pulling his punches they went through even the best defenses.

“We… we don’t really know…”

“You don’t know?”

“Yes, we just ended up here and decided to take a little break in our journey.”

“A little break? Wait, how about you go back… what journey?”

Zhang Jin gave out a sigh before finally deciding to give his grandson the whole timetable of what had happened.

“At first the whole palace and all of us together were swallowed by that strange monster fish. We could see you being swallowed by the darkness while the others made it back inside.”

He nodded while listening, this was the start of his own trek through the frozen wasteland. Zhang Jin on the other hand and the others were all transported to another location. It was a stark contrast to the one that he ended up as it was even hotter there than in this tropical environment.

“We ended up in a place mostly filled with lava, only thanks to the Golden Palace’s flight capability were we able to remain unharmed. Liena wanted to form a group to search for you but we couldn’t allow this.”

“Ah yes, if I’m gone the palace will switch to the next in the command line.”

“Yes, and she also is aware of some secrets that I’m not aware of because of a certain Patriarch never disclosing them…”

Zhang Dong could see his grandfather squinting in his direction. This was true as he had shown Liena all the secret rooms and granted access to the hidden command station only he had access to. Zhang Jin would be able to command the ship but some functions would be unavailable to him. Liena would actually be able to activate the teleportation feature back outside, that is if something here wasn’t blocking it.

It was possible that it was due to them being inside of a living being and not at a location. It was constantly moving throughout the highly pressured waters. It was also filled with pocket dimensions, maybe even the system had trouble locking onto the coordinates in a situation like this.

“Maybe if a certain old man could be trusted to not engage in lewd acts with the enemy, then he would have told him everything… but that’s not important now, what happened next? So you arrived at a lava location and then?”

Zhang Jin put his head down in shame after hearing Zhang Dong’s rebuttal. He at least was sure that his wife wouldn’t have fallen into a strange trap like this. Perhaps they were sure that the aphrodisiacs wouldn’t affect them but the danger wasn’t zero. If his grandfather was given all the secrets and then controlled then it would be quite a problem for everyone. Without him around his Golden Palace could have been turned into a grand weapon against his own people.

“Yes, the golden palace should still be at that location at least it still was when we activated the trap…”

“A trap?”

“We decided to form a search party to look for you Dong’er, Huo Qiang here who is well versed in the Dao of fire was the perfect choice for it.”

“Yeah, but why did they let you go outside too?”

It made sense for Huo Qiang to go outside, his Ifrit Soul Beast was capable of controlling flames and so was its master. Moving through a lava-filled environment with people from the Huo clan side of the sect was a good idea.

“We couldn’t let the Huo clan go alone, we needed to send a force capable of contending with many other issues.”

“That makes sense… so why did they let you come with them?”

“What is that supposed to mean? I am one of the most experienced experts in the entire sect!”

“I guess you are…I keep forgetting each time you pull a stunt like this…”

Perhaps Zhang Dong was a little biased against his grandfather who seemed to only think with his lower half. He was still a nascent soul master with over two hundred years of experience. There were a lot of things that he knew and was a capable general of his own accord. Having him along in the search party wasn’t a bad choice.

He was the Patriarch that towered over everyone from his own sect. His perception of them was a bit more realistic so he forgot that others were considered masters. In the eyes of his sect members, a person like Zhang Jin was not a useless pervert but a legendary figure. Huo Qiang wasn’t a brainless musclebound idiot but an honorable warrior at the forefront of the empire. Some even considered him to be in the top ten of the strongest people in the whole empire.

There was a moment when he started feeling that he was perhaps too harsh on the two yet after seeing Huo Qiang dozing off during Zhang Jin’s tale, he went back to his old preconceived notions of these two. Finally, he started getting to the important part where they were transported to this place.

“So you were fighting some volcanic creatures and activated some type of teleportation formation which split you all up into smaller groups?”

“That’s correct, it hasn’t been that long since we arrived here so we decided to take a little break before moving along…”

“By little break you mean?”

“Yes…”

“Hm…”

The story was over and he could kind of fill in the blanks by himself. After getting here and encountering the natives they forgot about their mission. It was more likely that all of the two were actually affected by the alluring forms of the mermaids to some extent. Perhaps if there was someone like Zhang Zhi with them the story would have ended up differently.

“But you’re fine so now we just need to find the way back to the palace! Or perhaps you could create a teleportation formation to send us back!”

“I can’t do that, these pocket dimensions are strange, I can’t pinpoint the location of the Golden Palace but we could try finding some of the people that came together with your group but remember not to fly too high up…”

“We shouldn’t fly?”

Zhang Dong nodded and after giving a smack to the back of Qiang’s head he explained everything that happened to him. Soon the group of three nascent soul masters was going through the deserted encampment that looked like a resort. Without the mermaids being here to look over their shoulders they were free to investigate the place in peace.

“So it’s possible for those lovely creatures to turn into ugly monstrosities?”

“Yes, there might be some type of trigger that changes the environment and it would be better if we first found the others, have you been able to detect them?’

“No… I wasn’t able to sense any of the juniors that came with us, nor the other masters, perhaps they have been transported to another of these ‘pocket dimensions’ you speak of Dong’er.”

“That could be the case but I hope it’s not.”

It took him multiple days to just get past the first frozen area. If there were multiple pocket dimensions inside this anglerfish then it would be a difficult task to go through them. Even for masters like them, it was disorienting. Normally they had Zhang Dong and his system to ask for help but it was being blocked.

The current function that was somewhat helpful was that he could still map out the entire place and this included the underground tunnels that these mermaids went through. However, this wasn’t all. After getting back with this two some of the old faction-based perks were back to working but to a limited degree.

“I and the elder have been here for two days but we were unable to discover any of our brothers even after arriving at this place.”

Huo Qiang was finally allowed to get up as the three needed to think about a new plan. The quickest but the most dangerous way of escaping would be to split up. Thankfully, his system was now picking up these two back on his faction screen. It seemed that if they were this close that it could recalibrate their positions again.

‘Bob, does this mean that there are no other of my faction members here or that I need to get closer to them for them to be registered in the faction window?’

‘There are several unknown errors plaguing the system, an answer can not be given.’

‘I see…’

It was possible that he only needed to be in the same pocket dimension as his faction members for it to work. Yet considering that he wasn’t able to see Huo Qiang and Zhang Jin there before he got closer then it was possible that more people were somewhere here. Normally he would be against splitting up but this was not a good time to take things slowly. They needed to get back to their main force and either escape the belly of this beast or find a way to conquer it.

“Fine then, I’ll head into those tunnels and you two examine the surroundings from outside, we will meet back at this location in two days…”

The three masters nodded at each other and now that they could communicate via Zhang Dong’s system the danger was lowered. All of them jumped in different directions and resumed their search for their lost sect brothers and sisters.

Chapter 630

‘Going through the surface is much faster than these narrow tunnels, good that I’m not claustrophobic…’

Zhang Dong was squeezing his body through the narrow passages that the mermaids escaped to. He had even noticed some of them watching him as he was passing without giving him a greeting. It was clear that these creatures were scared of him but this didn’t mean that they were docile. They were still trying to entice his horny grandfather for some reason. If it was just out of fright then it would be fine but perhaps they had something else in store for the two idiots that he ‘rescued.’

‘Should I just drill through the ground… but these rocks are quite thick and sturdy, I’ll be out of qi in no time…’

For a moment he decided to stop and look at his mapping device. The whole place was like a maze. There were hundreds of these narrow tunnels everywhere and only thanks to the map was he able to navigate through them. When looking out the window there was a red line formed behind him to indicate where he had already been. He had already managed to follow one of the tunnels to one that he already took and thanks to the map he was able to quickly adjust to a new pathway.

All of them looked the same and were quite disorienting. It also didn’t help that there was seaweed everywhere. It was quite thick and even able to block off some of the paths that he had already been on. It blended with the narrow walls and would probably cause people to miss some of the old pathways they had taken.

‘It’s good that I can track the paths they took with the little Qi those mermaids use for swimming but where will it lead me to?’

He had already spent several hours down here. Due to the narrow pathways and the seaweed everywhere, it was pitch dark down here. Normally he would be glowing like a lightbulb but thanks to his newest Dao of Darkness he could comfortably move through this place like it was nothing.

His eyes couldn’t see anything but he could still tell what was happening around him. It was a different type of vision that didn’t require any light to be present and allowed him to be a bit more sneaky. If he tried to produce light then he would open himself up to a potential trap. Like this, even if the mermaids were trying to lead him toward doom, he would have the upper hand.

The journey continued for a couple of more hours until he managed to sense something. Even with the thickness of the walls in place, he managed to pick up something nearby. There was a larger concentration of living beings in the area that was before him. Thanks to his shadowy sneaking skills he was able to approach the area without needing to slow down that much. After squeezing through one last hole he was greeted with quite a large cavern with a huge castle in the middle.

‘Is this their lair? Looks like it’s in a large air bubble…’

He was now inside a huge cave. There were many small tunnels that popped out of the ceiling and some mermaids could be seen going through them. Instantly he could see that there was something fishy about those mermaids. Two of them were swimming with something that looked like a big soap bubble. When straining his senses a bit he managed to notice that there was someone inside that bubble.

They were all going towards the giant dome in the middle of this cavern. At first, it looked like it was just a massive pocket of air but when taking another look he noticed that it was actually a large barrier. It allowed the mermaids to easily move inside but quickly cleared behind them. Inside this barrier, there were several large structures. Some type of palace was there which could mean that he had found what he was looking for.

‘It’s probably not where the Cerulean Empress lives, a bit too small to be a castle the Emperor would live in…’

With the help of his system map and his own senses, he tried peeking into the inside of this bubble. Now that he was free of the strange rocks he was actually able to peer through the veil. On the inside, there were many nascent soul-equivalent beings and also more of the mermaids. This wasn’t the part he was interested in though as besides those creatures his people were present.

‘That person in the bubble was probably someone from the search party… I shouldn’t assume the worst but this doesn’t look good… Now how do I get inside without alerting them of my presence?’

After finding that his people were being dragged into the palace he needed to do something. It was probably possible for him to force his way in by sheer brute power. Yet this would alert everyone in this underwater city to his presence. Even he wouldn’t be able to contend with swarms of nascent soul-equivalent monsters. Considering that this place could also turn into a deathtrap like the frozen wasteland he left behind, it would be better to try the hidden approach first.

‘It might not affect me but not many people would survive those temperatures…’

Considering that his people were being brought here he could not risk another disastrous change occurring. He assumed that he would be fine even in extreme temperatures but this wasn’t the same for the people from the search party. Some of them could be out cold, others were just core formation experts. They would surely perish if the same monsters that he left behind in the desolate frozen wastes appeared before them.

‘Is there a way to sneak in…’

When thinking about the way to go his eyes landed on two mermaids but mostly on the big bubble, they were dragging through a hole. Inside was a man at the core formation level that was probably going to get transported on the inside. This was his ticket into this area, he just needed to cloak himself in darkness. Even though the palace behind the barrier was filled with light, the rest of the underwater areas were flooded with darkness. He just needed to take up a shadowy form and keep to the backs of the mermaids which wouldn’t be clad in light.

This new Dao had improved his hiding technique to the next level. Even while moving no one that was close to his level was able to detect him. The only weakness of this new technique was light. However, there weren’t that many places in the world that light reached everywhere. Even now, he was sticking to the mermaid's back that was shrouded in some shade while she approached the protective bubble. Soon she was swimming inside without anyone being able to pick him up.

It was actually like passing through a soap bubble and on the inside there was a mix of water elements with breathable water. Yes, it was a strange phenomenon where the surroundings were composed of water with infused air. It was a strange phenomenon where two existed at once which allowed people with regular lungs to breathe. Before coming here he was sustaining himself with the other Dao that he had gained, the one of wind. Without defeating the Emerald Phoenix Emperor, investigating a place like this would have been quite troublesome but if he could produce his own air then there was no problem.

‘Where are they taking him…’

Even though the little bit of shade behind the mermaid allowed him to sneak in, if she turned around to face a light source his location would be exposed. Thus when inside he quickly jolted to a safe location before anyone discovered his presence. There was a whole city around him that offered a lot of shaded spots that he could now move undetected through.

His gaze landed on the bubble of water that began to open up after the mermaids made it in. He was prepared to instantly jump into action if he felt any killing intent from the denizens here. The main reason that he decided to come here is to find the people that were searching for him. Perhaps it was unwise to cause a scene but he wouldn’t just let one of his sect members be killed right in front of his nose.

Luckily the man didn’t look to be injured and his face had a rather odd expression. There was a certain grin there similar to the one that his grandfather and Huo Qiang had when they were interacting with these mermaids. Considering that he was only a core formation expert the mermaid’s aphrodisiacs and enticing melodies probably had a larger effect.

‘Was he just drugged and brought here? Or perhaps he tired himself by having fun with these mermaids?’

While the women were quite beautiful and exotic from the waist up he had a hard time believing that anyone would go through with the deed. They still had long fishtails with no legs to be seen anywhere. He wasn’t really sure about the logistics here but perhaps it ended before anything could have been explored further.

‘They are on the move, I need to follow them.’

After the man was freed from the bubble the mermaids continued to drag him towards a large palace-like structure in the back. It looked like it was made out of hollowed-out coral with uneven towers and seashells everywhere. Fish were swimming in this strange environment which if not for this situation would have been quite captivating.

‘The people are starting to show up on my faction window, there must be something about this environment that is blocking my system.’

It was quite interesting to see that his system wasn’t perfect. Only after getting inside of this bubble and the member of his sect getting out of the smaller one, was he registered back in his faction window. It seemed it were the bubbles and perhaps this protective formation that was doing this.

Before leaving this palace he made a mental note to investigate. If there was something able to block out his system, it could perhaps be used against his true foe. Perhaps this would give him a tip on how he should counter the time-stop effect that the Overseer was producing but first he needed to get his people out of this place.

While using the shadows to keep a low profile he entered the strange palace. There he found guards that looked like the clone generals. They were wearing bulky armor and holding tridents in their hands while not moving. Some lesser commanders were even patrolling the corridors through which he was sneaking.

All of the people that he was picking up on his faction window were getting moved to one location, there he would find his answer to what these mermaids were attempting to achieve with the kidnapping.

Chapter 631

“Quickly, we must prepare for the feast!”

“Yes, bring them in, they need to be prepared before we can have the feast!”

“Yes, yes!”

‘The hell are they doing…’

Zhang Dong had managed to sneak in through the chamber door while it was being opened. His form was that of a very thin shade so it was quite easy to make his way in. He had followed after the two mermaids that had captured one of his sect members. The room that all of them were being brought in had more than just this person, there were multiple of his sect personnel here.

To his surprise, they were all dumped in one spot on top of each other by these unseaming mermaids. The beautiful women were floating around and dancing as if they were at some kind of dancing event. It was actually somewhat strange and creepy when he took note of those big grins. They were certainly preparing something insidious and now that he came here he could confirm it.

This looked to be some type of kitchen, a strange large pot was right in the middle of it. What made the thing weird was that the water inside of this cauldron was starting to boil. Everything was already covered in water so this had to be some type of special cooking utensil that only affected the water inside of it while not allowing the heat to seep out.

There was one larger mermaid in the middle, her skin was gray and her teeth were a lot sharper than the rest. She was wearing a cap that he would only see on modern-day chefs back in his old world. This was probably the main cook that was starting to insert some herbs and vegetables into the now boiling pot. It was clear what was going on here, these fish people wanted to eat his sect members. The cook was already picking out a good knife to chop them up into something smaller.

‘Do they like to eat humans or something? Could this be what this is all about?’

The Demi-humans were here for the great hunt, the Emerald Phoenix Empire to gain power and resources. His friends from the magical kingdom were searching for their secret relics, all had some type of grand reason to be here. Could these undersea creatures just be there because they saw the cultivators as food?

‘There are techniques that change people into pills used by demonic cultivators… could they seek to enhance their bodies by eating us or something?’

He wasn’t sure what was going on and what the true aim of these people here was. It was possible that they were just part of this pocket dimension and were actually not related to the Cerulean Empress. It could have been some type of strange side quest that the mysterious being that created this world created for him. If it was anything like the previous location he was in, then perhaps he needed to prepare for the worst.

‘I should probably call gramps and Qiang before I go through with this.’

While the situation looked dire the people that were here weren’t getting cut up just yet. Before turning this kitchen into a battlefield he needed to give his allies a heads-up. Thus he brought up his system window and now clicked the working faction window where he could actually contact the two.

‘Gramps, have you found anyone?’

‘Dong’er? Yes, I’ve managed to find six members.’

‘Qiang, what about you?’

‘Senior Brother, I have seven people with me!’

‘Where were they when you found them?’

‘Oh? They were at a similar resort as we were but the lovely ladies fled the moment they saw us coming.’

‘So they were gathering our people at similar locations… together with the ones that are here, that makes it twenty-four, you really didn’t take that many people with you.’

‘Twenty-four? Then you found the rest of our group?’

‘Yes, I’ll attempt to free them but you should watch out for the world around you, it could go through a change. You two need to rendezvous back at that resort.’

‘A change? Is it some type of trap?’

‘Something like that. I’ve managed to sneak into their hidden lair, if this place is anything like the other one I visited, there could be trouble. It would be better if you rendezvous together and set up a few protective formations before I join you.’

‘You can count on me, senior brother!’

‘Is it that dire? Very well, we will wait for you Dong’er be careful.’

‘I’ll try to keep a low profile but I can’t guarantee anything, talk to you later.’

It seemed that all of the people were accounted for. The group that went to search for him was composed of mostly elite members. There was one nascent soul master here that had gone along and the rest were core formation experts at the great circle stage. While they wouldn’t offer much help to the stronger masters, they could act as eyes and spread out for the search. It was a lot easier for these small groups to function versus a huge army that needed to be micromanaged.

He ended the call between them and glanced over at one of the mermaids. She was in the process of carrying one of the passed-out cultivators toward a large wooden board. There were cuts and nicks on this board. It didn’t take a genius to figure out that his sect members would be cut up on it and then their parts were thrown into the large pot. Perhaps others would be turned to sushi before his eyes if he didn’t do anything about it.

‘I should try using these new skills, maybe I can do this quietly…’

While it wouldn’t be hard just to blast his way through these mermaids, he feared that some type of trap would be triggered. There were a lot of those general clones around this place that were at the nascent soul level. If he attacked without thinking they would probably swarm this location in a matter of seconds. Only if he could keep it quiet then would he be able to sneak out of this place.

Thus he initiated his new Dao of darkness. The shadow that he was sticking to started expanding. It traveled all over the walls to block all the light out from this large kitchen chamber. The mermaids only noticed that something was wrong only after the darkness fell all over the place. With his shadow covering the entire location no sound could escape outside and he was free to come out of his hiding spot.

“What is happening, how did it get so dark?”

“Is the Mistress angry? But it’s not dinner time yet, we should have more time!”

He wasn’t sure what these mermaids were talking about but he used this chance to quickly knock them all out. The normal ones were at the level of core formation experts with the cook being a tiny bit stronger. It didn’t take much besides his Qi to seep into their forms to stun them. Soon all of them were down on the ground and as he had managed to silently take care of this situation.

‘This went better than expected…’

Zhang Dong was standing in the middle of the room as the shades seeped back into his body through his feet. Usually, he took the radiant approach but thanks to this Dao other forms of combat were now possible. It was suited for assassination and trick attacks. He could see himself hiding attacks in shadows while fighting his enemies. If the environment was suited for it, then perhaps it would be possible to even sneak up on a master to take them out in one hit.

‘I’ll better put them into the medallion for now…’

After the enemy cooks were taken out he started gathering out the people that were brought here. Luckily he had arrived as the last person was brought over. Probably if Zhang Jin and Huo Qiang didn’t find the other locations the sect members were being picked up, more of them would have wound up here. It was clear that the resorts were a honeypot trap.

The enticing mermaids would serenade the victims into a comatose state before bringing them here. Now that he got his hands on some of his sect members he was sure about it. They were all slumbering with stupid grins on their faces. They were all under a strong illusion technique which made them dream of nice things and events. They were probably still thinking that they were up in one of those resorts having some fun with these half-women half-fish.

‘It seems to affect not only the men but the women cultivators too…’

The group of people that were formed to search for him wasn’t composed of men only, there were several women in the pile that he rescued. The enticing melody could even affect people of the same gender it seemed. If it was this strong then perhaps he needed to watch his back. Perhaps the Cerulean Empress was capable of performing similar techniques that would probably be even further enhanced.

‘They shouldn’t affect me but it wouldn’t be the same for the others…’

He could already imagine Huo Qiang and Zhang Jin charging at him just to serve their new Empress. Perhaps bringing over his entire army into this Angler fish was the wrong strategy. Now that he looked at this mess it was possible for it to go south. It would have been a lot simpler if he just set out on this journey himself.

‘Was this supposed to be a solo quest or something? Great…’

After shaking his head a few times he started packing up. There was no reason for him to stay here and the safety of his people was a priority. His teleportation feature was still not working so he couldn’t really set up a teleportation spot here. Thus instead he sank back into the shadows to quickly crawl through the way that he entered.

The words of the mermaids bothered them, they seemed to be making this human pot for someone. Probably if it wasn’t made that person would be mad and come to check. This was probably the leader of this palace and perhaps a side boss that he would need to handle. However, his main objective was still to just wrap things up here and return to the golden palace where his people were. There was no time to battle beasts and monsters without identifying who the Cerulean Empress was.

‘I’ll just grab a few things along with these mermaids, they should give me the info that I need!’

Thus he sank back into the shadows and made his way back to Zhang Jin and Huo Qiang that were waiting above ground. If everything went well, they would soon depart back to the palace and the volcanic area where everyone else was.

Chapter 632

‘Just a little bit more and I’m out…’

Zhang Dong was able to make his way out of the hidden headquarters. His Dao of Darkness which allowed him to blend with any shadow and even create some of his own, was too strong. Everything went well as no one was able to discover his presence and now he was in one of the tunnels heading above ground.

‘Usually, something goes wrong when I do these stealth missions, I guess it will be possible for me to switch to a stealth build now, should I start learning some of those techniques?’

The dark arts he was using were working so well that he was actually thinking about learning them to a higher degree. Inside his system’s library, there were a few good techniques that could be combined with others to create something better. At the moment he was just using the Darkness Dao without any main technique but he could see it expanding into something better.

It was a very nice art for sneaking around and solo missions as he would have probably been able to reach the hidden boss in that underwater palace before anyone spotted him there. However, with many of his sect members in danger he needed to look at the bigger picture. Now that they were all out, it was time to find a way toward the volcanic region.

“We greet the Patriarch.”

“Senior Brother, we came as you wanted.”

“Good.”

Finally, after following a path given to him by his mapping function he was back in the initial resort where Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang were having their fun. Both of them had arrived a few minutes before him and were now giving him a little salute. After nodding at the sect members that he wasn’t familiar with he gave a little nod to both Zhang Jin and Huo Qiang.

“Elder Qiang and Jin will join me for a talk, the rest of you stay here and keep watch.”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

The small group of cultivators stood up at attention and quickly bowed. He could see the reverence in their eyes, they really thought that he was something special. That look of blind faith and loyalty didn’t go unnoticed. It was something that still continued to add to the stress of living in this world. Everyone trusted in his judgment and decisions, and for the time being, he was able to somehow plow through all of the problems that lay before him. Contrary to their belief he was not so sure if he was making all the right choices.

Even now perhaps it was better to have blasted the underwater palace with one of his greater attacks. At that time they had no idea that he was there but by now the kitchen area might have been looked over. It could be the case that someone would go after them but it could also be the reverse.

“How can we help?”

“First, do you recall the place where you first appeared? I need the exact place.”

“The exact place? Hm… it shouldn’t be a problem, it wasn't that far from this place.”

“Good job Elder, I didn’t really pay attention that much… I do remember a large rock near that place though, but I’m not sure…”

Zhang Jin answered while Huo Qiang nodded. The two arrived together with the other core formation experts being spread around the whole pocket dimension. Luckily Zhang Jin took note of where they were before the mermaids appeared to entice them away. Huo Qiang on the other hand wasn’t that sure. He started listing a few rocks and trees that he noticed but there was nothing clear to go off.

“It’s fine Young Qiang, I left a little of my spiritual imprint at the location, it won’t be hard to find it.”

“Well, at least there is one of you that doesn’t only think with your other head.”

“Haha, it’s just the basics of surviving, this old man didn’t survive for this long without learning a thing or two!”

Zhang Jin started laughing at Huo Qiang that was frowning. Luckily for them, the old man knew how to survive in a world filled with treacherous cultivators and powerful beasts. It was an old tactic to mark the initial point after initializing a teleportation trap. Usually, a person would lose their bearings and get lost, this was a good way to realize if a person was going in circles or not.

“But why do you want to go there, Senior Brother?”

“The area that you arrived at could have a clue, a trace of spiritual energy that we could perhaps follow to the exit. If not, then perhaps I could pinpoint where you came from and assemble a teleportation array to the spot the original trap triggered.”

“Are you capable of doing that?”

“Perhaps…”

“That’s why you’re my Senior Brother!”

“Don’t get your hopes up, I won’t know what I can do until we get there.”

After coming back to the area where the core formation experts were hanging out all of them departed. Time was of the essence so instead of letting them use their flying swords Zhang Dong decided to surround the group with his golden aura. All of them looked quite happy to be taxied around by their Patriarch, perhaps when they got back to the palace they would see it as a badge of honor and tell their friends.
“It’s around here, yes we appeared between those two large rocks…”

“I knew that I remembered that rock!”

Huo Qiang pointed to a large boulder in the distance but Zhang Jin just shook his head around.

“It wasn’t that one, the two on the other side.”

“Oh…”

Everyone laughed a bit, even the core formation experts were having a good time. It was a stark contrast to the way some sects operated. It was rare to have the core formation experts act this nonchalantly when around nascent soul masters. Yet this sect was built up like this, it was meant to have a more familiar feeling where people actually worked together with each other. In other factions, it was usually a rat race to the top.

Limited resources, masters that wanted the best potential disciples, and everything needed to be fought for. In the United Element’s sect on the other hand, with the merit system around even the worst cultivator had ways of getting stronger. There was an environment of camaraderie instead of the usual competitiveness that could be found in other sects. Thanks to this, they weren’t as afraid to speak up when next to nascent soul masters. The way to this level wasn’t that outlandish and even some people they knew had made it there through some help from their Patriarch. Nevertheless, they would still act accordingly to their standing and in a formal way as the old ways would take some more time to be eroded.

“So this is it?”

‘Bob, start scanning, there should be some type of residue from the teleportation trap, if we can pinpoint the coordinates then it should be possible to get out of here.’

‘Scanning… found teleportation signature… analyzing… unable to complete the quarry, need more data.’

“Damn…”

“What is it, Dong’er?”

“It’s not enough, the residual energy has faded away, I need more of it to complete the formation.”

“Hm, that’s a shame… how about we ask the juniors? They had been scattered through the entire place just like us, maybe if we find enough of those locations, it might be enough?”

“That’s not a bad idea.”

There were almost thirty people that were stuck in this place. Some of them appeared in pairs while others were alone. This meant that there were other locations just like this one, if they were fast enough then it was possible for Bob to complete the data analysis. The ones that he saved from the underwater palace had started to wake up as well, it was time to let them out and make them be of use.

“The area that I arrived in shouldn’t be that far…”

“I’m sorry Patriarch, I don’t recall…”

“I left a slither of my Qi in the location, let me guide you there, Patriarch, it will be an honor!”

While some of the core formation experts had no idea where they arrived, some others were more useful. A few were smart enough to leave a trace amount of their Qi behind just like Zhang Jin and those places they would go to first.

“Good, Gramps. Give the ones that left their Qi behind some merit points when we get back, they did a fine job.”

“You hear that? Some of you will get rewarded!”

The ones that would get rewards for their smart thinking rejoiced while the others that didn’t think looked ashamed. This was a big chance to show their skills to their Patriarch and they blew it. He could see the horror in their eyes and only hoped that they wouldn’t take it too harshly. Yet he couldn’t let anyone be rewarded, the ones that didn’t use their head needed to be reprimanded as it could help them not do the same mistake again.

So the search for the trace amounts of teleportation energy started. Some had more than others and Bob was quick to analyze them. Luck was on their side as after the fifth location they had enough data to triangulate the location. Now, what was left for him to do was to build a teleportation array and send everyone back to the volcanic area they came from.

“The Patriarch is really amazing, he can do everything.”

“That is true, we were the ones supposed to rescue him but instead he was the one that saved us.”

People started murmuring while he was working. While he didn’t want to eavesdrop on the hidden messages about him, curiosity got the better of him. Even though she should be above things like praise, being someone that people relied on wasn’t all that bad. At least he was shown respect and given praise for his achievements and it gave him the needed motivation to move on. But then there were some parts of the conversations that he wished he never heard either.

“The Patriarch is so dreamy, think he would take me in as a mistress?”

“Do you wish to die? Elder Liena would not let it be, your whole family would be in danger.”

“You really think so? The Elder Jin has many wives, I’m sure the Patriarch has similar tendencies.”
‘Do I really look like that pervert?’

Some of the women from the group started gossiping while trying not to make it too obvious. He could feel their eyes focusing on his back while he was trying to assemble the teleportation array that would take them to the rest of the sect.

‘Let’s do this before something else goes wrong, it shouldn’t take more than an hour, I have all the materials that I need…’

Chapter 633

“There, it’s done, now we just need to get enough energy for it to work.”

“I see that there is nothing that my grandson can’t do. He must have gotten it from this old man!”

“Sure I did…”

Zhang Jin’s palm landed on Zhang Dong’s shoulder as he was praised for assembling a complex teleportation formation. The other sect members with them could not believe what had transpired. His movements were so fast that they were afraid to blink. None of them understood the techniques that were used but they already knew that it would help them further pursue the formation craft. Normally to see an expert like him at work they would need to either be his disciples or part of the inner sect. Even then no one was really granted any teachings besides the two main disciples Zhang Xue and Liu.

“You lot, stop staring and line up. We will be returning to the volcanic region you came from, I need you to focus on the mission.”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

Everyone jumped up in fright after he shouted at them for spacing out. While he appreciated that they were interested in his work, they were supposed to keep watch over the whole area. While he had the system it wasn’t perfect, when he was focusing on making the array his spiritual sense couldn’t be utilized to monitor the area. There was no way to track the enemies like in the azure empire through the map either.

“Huh?”

“What was that?”

Suddenly, before he could start the activation procedure, the ground started to shake. At first, it seemed to just be a little quake, maybe even some distant creature making a ruckus. However, after focusing on the area where the tremors were coming from, it became clear that there was something off.”

“It’s coming from that area…”

“Yes, where I met you two…”

Zhang Jin nodded at his comment as it was becoming clear that they perhaps didn’t have that much time. Quickly they turned around towards the teleportation array that still needed some time to be charged. This was a process that couldn’t be rushed as doing it too quickly would destroy the fine traces it was composed of.

“They had to chose the worst possible moment to come after us.”

“Gramps.”

“Leave the array to me and Elder Wuyan.”

This was the third nascent soul elder that came for this rescue mission. He was not as strong as Huo Qiang and more on the level of his grandfather. His expertise in the arts was true and he had lived around the same amount of time as his grandfather. Together the two would probably be able to handle the teleportation formation.

“I’ll leave it to you. Qiang, come with me.”

“Finally something to do!”

The big brute’s fists collided with each other as he pumped himself up. There was nothing more that a battle maniac like him liked more than a good challange. Judging by the spiritual energy traces, the enemy that they were facing was at the apex of the nascent soul. This would normally not be an issue but there were multiple enemies at a similar level.

“It’s probably the Cloned Generals, there were a bunch of them down in that palace.”

“The more the better!”

“Don’t let your guard down, there is something else there… something much stronger…”

The first to appear were the generals with the tridents. They seemed to be the same soldiers that used to plague the seas close to the coastline. Previously his armies used them to farm a lot of spirit points which made this expedition possible. Huo Qiang had already faced them in battle so there was no fear of letting him handle most of them.

What he was more on guard against was the being that was following behind them. Even after the generals appeared on the surface the rumbling didn’t stop. Something huge was approaching and it was making this whole miniaturized world shake. It was hard to focus on the group of nascent soul masters with raised weapons when a giant torrent of earth was shooting up into the sky from right behind them.

It blocked out all the view and even covered some of them in mud. Zhang Dong could see some of the generals fleeing to the sides or surrounding themselves with water energy to not get swept by this avalanche. Soon enough he could see something appear there and it was thrashing around in all sorts of directions.

“Is that a giant tentacle?”

At first, he thought that it was another version of his old foe that forced him to take a five-year-old break from his family. The energy signatures that were coming from this thing were different though. It lacked the evil demonic aura and was more attuned to the water Dao that permeated through this pocket dimension.

“Wait… could it be something like a Kraken?”

An ugly head with huge tentacles at the sides appeared out of the ground. The creature somewhat resembled the Cthulhu monsters that he used to fight but it lacked the humanoid shape. Instead, it was composed mostly of a mass of tentacles and strange tendrils with other appendages at the end. Then there was one other difference, this beast could actually speak.

“My feast, they stole it! Bring them to me!!!”

To his surprise, the monster could articulate quite well. If he didn’t see the mass of tentacles and the ugly mouth filled with teeth then the voice could be mistaken for a woman’s. Considering that this was probably the leader of the mermaids it made some sense. This was probably their mistress and perhaps someone that created the fishy ladies that could serenade everyone to sleep.

“Qiang, don’t let them approach the array, we must not let them get to the other sect members.”

“Leave it to me, Senior Brother!”

Huo Qiang was ecstatic when he saw the massive creature. Its body was as huge as a mountain and it was also apparently capable of floating above the ground. It was as if the creature was swimming through the sky while giving out orders to the many trident-holding generals below.

“Capture them! I want to feast on their sweet flesh!”

“Yes, Mistress!”

The clash between the two strongest elders from the United Element sect and the forces from the Cerulean Empire started. Considering that this thing had a female voice the thought of it being the Cerulean Empress crossed Zhang Dong’s mind. Yet the generals weren’t referring to her by this title which more than likely meant that this wasn’t the case.

“Are you the one that stole my feast? You will pay and join them inside of my stomach, I hunger for human flesh!”

“Sorry, but I’m not into those sorts of things, and your breath kind of stinks…”

The moment the monster octopus appeared it instantly picked him out as her target. Huo Qiang attempted to intercept her through a punch from his soul beast but was stopped by the generals that were acting like minions. They were in for a blazing inferno that was slightly diminished due to the nature of this place.

Even though his junior brother wasn’t showing it, his Dao of Fire was somewhat suppressed by the prevalence of water, even more after the squid monster appeared. Zhang Dong could tell so he decided to lure the monster away to the side to let Qiang have some breathing room while fighting.

The peaceful landscape filled with coconut trees and a relaxing atmosphere turned into a battleground. Trees were unearthed and burned by the giant fire monster and the man that was controlling it. All of the buildings that made up the previous resort were destroyed in the process of the squabble. Energy blasts made out of water energy, fire, and electricity were flying everywhere.

“Elders, shouldn’t we help the Patriarch?”

“Concentrate on the array and stop looking away, they are only distracting the enemy from us, remember our mission is not to defeat these beasts but to return to the rest of the sect.”

“My apologies elder.”

Zhang Jin paced around the array that some of the other core formation elders were reinforcing with their Qi. If it was up to him then he would just throw himself into battle along with Qiang and his grandson. Yet he also needed to keep the troops alive that were given to him, the easiest way out of here was through this teleportation device and it wouldn’t take much more for them to finish it.

The only problem was the berserker creature up in the sky. The tentacles it was swinging around were so long and thick that they looked like giant towers. Each of these appendages also had smaller ones attached to them. Every time Zhang Dong dodged one that was approaching a swarm of smaller tendrils with spikes at the end shot out.

These squiggly fleshy whips were breaking the barrier of sound with each attack. There were so many of them that even Zhang Dong was having trouble keeping up and had to rely on his holy barrier to deflect the ones that he couldn’t shake off. Then if this wasn’t bad enough, even though he was constantly slicing through those tentacles they just kept growing back. No amount of holy energy that usually worked on demonic beasts could halt the regeneration that this beast was equipped with either.

“Dong’er, we are finished!”

Luckily he wasn’t alone here and beating this monster was not the main plan. Zhang Jin called out to Zhang Dong who could tell that the teleportation array was activated. Some of the core formation experts were already going through to pave a path for their experts.

“Qiang, we need to retreat!”

“I’m not sure it will be that easy…”

The number of the generals wasn’t low and even Huo Qiang who went through an upgrade was having trouble contending with them. Even though some of them were down on the ground with their faces melted off, some were able to deliver some flesh wounds to the muscular man and draw blood.

‘I’ll open up the path for you, close your eyes and follow behind me.’

A hidden message was sent and right on cue a massive flash of light escaped from Zhang Dong’s body. It covered the entire area in bright white light that disoriented the enemy attackers and even caused the squiggly beast to wiggle in pain.

“S-stop them, you shall not escape!”

Huo Qiang closed his eyes right in time as the flash took place. Soon after he combined his body with his soul beast and turned into a flaming comet. Both he and Zhang Dong were now in full escape mode yet the massive monster wouldn’t just let them escape. Without any thought for her own men, she started elongating those appendages to cover everything in them. Qiang who was trailing behind a bit was the one to get smacked and even the coating of fire didn’t protect him from the thick beast whip.

Even though he wasn’t stopped, now a meteorite of fiery energy was heading straight for the teleportation array. Zhang Jin instantly jumped through while ordering everyone to do the same, it was clear to them that whenever that bundle of fire energy collided with the teleporter then it would become unusable…

A note from Kuropon

Going to take a 2 day break for easter, next chapter will be delayed.

Chapter 634

“Haha, I knew that we would have made it, we are back, Senior Brother! … Senior Brother?”

“Huo Qiang, where is Dong’er, wasn’t he in front of you?”

“Well…He turned around to diffuse some of the fire energy and tossed me into the teleportation array, then I think he was grabbed by some of those squiggly things…”

A confused Huo Qiang was rubbing his head while looking at the group of cultivators in the volcanic region. The spot they arrived at was actually the exact same one they entered the trap. It wouldn’t be strange for their allies to appear somewhere now but without the man that they were supposed to rescue here, they couldn’t really return.

“We must go back, what if he can’t find his way back here without us?”

Huo Qiang shouted out while turning towards the spot he arrived from. However even if he attempted to bulldoze his way back to the location he came from, there was no way of going back.

“Qiang, that’s not how teleportation arrays work, you can’t just go back. It was a one-way tunnel and the trap that sent us there is already out of energy.”

Zhang Jin was a bit calmer than the hot-headed Huo Qiang that was punching at the air. No one from this group actually knew how their Patriarch was able to create the array. In theory, they should be able to reverse engineer his method and use the ambient energy from the previous zone to create a similar array. This was easier said than done as they had no way of knowing how he was able to analyze the faint traces of Qi tied to the other location.

“Does this mean that he is trapped there?”

“Perhaps, Liena won’t like this…”

Just as all seemed to be lost, both nascent soul elders felt something. There was a ripple in the space and it started expanding.

“Wait, something is happening, prepare yourselves!”

Everyone pulled out their weapons and fists to stare at the spot in front of them. Suddenly a torrent of black goop shot out from thin air to coat everyone in a strange-smelling substance. This wasn’t all as screams of their favorite Patriarch followed soon after.”

“AAaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa”

His form which was usually white as a snow flower tumbled through while being black as obsidian. He was spinning around like a helicopter propeller and collided with the first person that was standing there, Huo Qiang. The collision caused the volcanic rock under them to shatter and sent many jagged rocks flying everywhere. Everyone was quick to disperse to get away from the liquid and mass of tentacles along with it.

…

“Uh… I made it?”

Zhang Dong gathered himself to his feet as he arrived at the other side of the teleportation array. He had been forced to save his junior brother from tumbling to the wrong side of their escape route. If he didn’t act then he would have been stuck there with the flying tentacle monster and its goons. Yet after shifting his position a bit he had been caught by a vast quantity of tendrils. They were quite slimy and not something that he liked touching his body.

A struggle with the Queen Octopus thing quickly ensued as his escape route was closing up. It wouldn’t last more than a few seconds but now that all of the people from his faction were on the other side, he just needed to join them. His Qi skyrocketed to the zenith as he incinerated the mass of tendrils that were constantly increasing. The regenerative capabilities of this monster were truly tremendous.

However, it was still a beast that had to abide by the rules of this world and setting. Like any other beast in this world, it had a core that was supporting all of its cultivation. It was the size of a golf ball and squiggled around through the water-based monster like an eel. Perhaps if he wasn’t working against time, there would be a better way to go around this but instead of a pinpoint precision attack he just decided to make everything explode. With everyone safely going through the teleportation array he didn’t need to worry about any collateral damage.

Soon a massive amount of swirling energy was gathering on his fingertips and expanding into a sphere of energy. It was time to make everything explode with this tiny star attack of his. The monster squid wasn’t having any of it as it attempted to engulf his entire form with the energy ball forming. For a moment everything went silent and it actually looked as if he had gotten devoured. Yet suddenly, the monster’s body started glowing like a Christmas tree. The light was shooting through those suction cups and various pores in its ugly body.

*BLAM*

Everything was covered in a black ink-like substance, Zhang Dong included. He didn’t even remember how he got out of there but without getting this liquid off he bolted for the teleportation array exit. The rest was history, in the nick of time he made it through and collided with Huo Qiang on the other hand.

“Senior Brother, what’s that smell?”

“It’s the Smell of victory…”

He wanted to give Qiang a smack on the head for making him go through this experience. Being surrounded by that squid's body was truly traumatizing. Even though he was able to encase himself in a shield made of Qi, he could see all of those ugly tentacles trying to get him. It was like he had been put into a horror movie with fleshy monster walls closing down on him. Then there was all this smell that had seeped right into his clothes.

“Why would victory stink like that…”
“Come over here and I’ll give you some of that victory.”

“I think I’ll pass, Senior Brother.”

Zhang Dong shook his fist at Huo Qiang while looking around. Finally, he realized that they were around a pool of lava that was constantly popping bubbles. It didn’t seem that there was any nearby water supply where he could clean all this gunk out. During the explosion, he needed to push through all of the monster’s guts to get to the teleportation array. Even for someone of his power, this wasn’t that easy and in a moment of weakness, he was drenched in all the stuff.

“Hoho, I’m glad that you made it out Dong’er, now my life is safe!”

“What are you babbling about?”

Zhang Jin laughed at the state that his grandson was in before moving over. Now that the Patriarch was here, the Matriarch wouldn’t be mad. When he was leaving for the mission she made it clear that if he didn’t return with Zhang Dong, then something would happen to his nether region.

“The fire elements are strong here but it shouldn’t be that hard.”

Zhang Dong on the other hand needed to get cleaned out. Luckily he knew some water techniques and conjuring up some of it even in this volcanic environment was still possible. It was something that he used to do when short on time. Developing a quick cleaning technique that left him clean and dry wasn’t that hard. The other sect members also loved it as it allowed them to train more and not worry about their smelly clothes.

Soon he was surrounded by a sphere of water through which no one could see his body. Within it, his clothes, body, and hair were being cleaned out of the strange black liquid. Luckily it didn’t seem that the monster was alive as it wasn’t reforming from some of the tentacles here. He was not sure if he had managed to get the beast’s core but as long as it wasn’t on this side, the monster couldn’t retake its previous shape.

“Senior Brother, could you…”

“Yeah sure…”

He was now clean but Huo Qiang had been covered in the sticky stuff as well. The cleaning technique allowed the clothes to be cleaned as well. Within a few minutes, the two best combatants were back to their old looks and the black sludge was evaporating due to the heat.

“Now that we are back here, we should find the Golden Palace and rendezvous with the others, lead the way, gramps.”

“Sure thing, just follow this old man.”

The description of this place that he was given didn’t give it justice. The place was just a wasteland composed of lava and volcanoes. All the air here was filled with strange vapors that were of various colors, most of them black or filled with yellow sulfur. This was not a place a regular human would be able to survive, without the enhanced cultivator bodies that everyone here had it would be impossible to breathe.

“Be careful Senior Brother, the volcanic beasts here are quite ferocious.”

“Are they?”

It was surprising to hear this quote from the battle maniac that was his junior brother. Normally he would be ecstatic to engage in battle with new creatures. If they were giving Huo Qiang trouble then even he needed to watch his back. After scanning the area with his spiritual sense he sensed some of these monsters nearby.

‘Hm, are they body refiners? Don’t feel that much Qi coming from them.’

When glancing toward one of the pools he felt a living organism. It wasn’t alone nor was it moving, like a predator waiting for a victim to get closer. When performing a more thorough search he could detect many similar lifeforms everywhere. It was like they were also underwater creatures like all the others, just instead of water they were using lava.

“Wait…”

“What is it Dong’er? If we hurry up we should be able to arrive at the palace within a day’s time.”

“We might have to move a bit faster then…”

“How so?”

Zhang Jin’s cultivation wasn’t as advanced so he couldn’t feel it. The environment was also working against them as the monsters that were gathered here blended in with the lava and Dao of Fire quite well. There weren’t just a few beasts looking at them, it was closer to hundreds or perhaps thousands.

“I think that our arrival here had woken up the natives.”

“Are we being watched?”

Everyone started looking around as they couldn’t see anyone within the flaming environment. Their leader knew though that perhaps the teleportation array or his cleaning method had roused some of the beasts here from their slumber.

“Yes and I’m not sure if they will let us just pass without a fight, get ready.”

Chapter 635

“These guys are tough, what is their skin made of? Can this even be called skin, it looks more like some type of organic rock, could it be this that allows them to stay down in the lava without dying?”

Zhang Dong looked at the various claws trying to slice him apart. The creatures that were previously hidden deep in the lava pools and lakes had decided to engage them in battle. Their forms were humanoid as a base but their arms were a lot longer and ended up with hands that looked more like claws. Then there were their bodies, it looked like they were golems with lizard faces and massive amounts of teeth.

“Some type of dragon offshoot? They do look like overgrown lizards to a point.”

After seeing the cloning technology that this Empire was equipped with, it wouldn’t be strange if they could splice things together. When examining the creatures further he spotted a monster core that was fueling their bodies. It felt slightly off, similar to the one the squid creature possessed. It wouldn’t be strange if this feeling was due to it having been altered as the spirit energy pattern felt off.

“Get in formation!”

“There are just too many of them elder, what should we do!”

“Just follow the Patriarch’s orders!”

Behind him, the group of twenty cultivators had retreated into a battle formation. It took the form of a serpent composed of spiritual energy with a fire aspect. There seemed to be a lot of people from the Huo Clan in this rescue party. While they were good at contending with the flames and the environment, this could not be said for their attacking power. Creatures that could live in lava could not be easily defeated by flame attacks. Even Huo Qiang and his ifrit which could generate even more heat, weren’t doing much to blast through those thick rock-like muscles.

‘Leave it to the Patriarch, huh?’

“Fire attacks won’t do you much good, you must counter the flames with their counter element.”

Zhang Dong proclaimed while pointing out toward one of the lizard-like monsters that lunged itself in his direction. Before it could get to him though he decided to increase the gravity around it which made the beast fall back down. Even though it was slammed into the hard jagged rocks, the thick hide made of organic rock didn’t take much damage. It was clear that these creatures were used to being in extreme conditions. Physical attacks were almost useless, even their organs and the inside of their mouths seemed reinforced for combat.

It was like fighting beings made from metal that didn’t seem to have a weakness. However, there were a few tactics that would work. The easiest one would be to produce some ice, these creatures more than likely needed the hot temperatures to survive. Just like most reptiles, they were probably cold-blooded. There was no need to regulate the temperature inside of their bodies if the environment was this hot. This meant that they would probably not survive extreme cold regions.

‘There are too many natural flame elements around here, with my incomplete knowledge of the Water Dao I won’t be able to perform this task too well…’

He knew a lot of techniques, some were based on the Dao of Water. While he could use them to a degree, his fortitude was lightning and holy attacks. Electrifying these walking monstrosities would probably be slightly better than using flames but it would also be inefficient. It seemed that even their insides had been enhanced to take a lot of damage, perhaps swallowing lava had something to do with it.

While he could brute force the issue against these monsters, this wasn’t the problem. There were many people relying on him here and without the flaming serpent they were forming, they would stand no chance of surviving in this environment. What he needed to do was try to find a way of getting through those reinforced shells without using too much of his power. These monsters were probably just the tip of it so he could not waste all of his power on them.

“Get behind me, we can’t waste time here, if this many creatures appeared here then perhaps the Golden Palace and everyone there could be at risk.”

“Dong’er, do you have a plan?”

“Lowering the temperature would probably work but that won’t be possible with all these active volcanoes around. However, there is a way to disable them for the time being.”

“There is?”

“Yes, just follow my lead, we are going to break through.”

Zhang Jin nodded while turning toward Huo Qiang and the rest of the sect members that were with them.

“You heard that, get ready we are going to go straight to the palace, follow the Patriarch!”

While there weren’t any external techniques that he could use to stop these monsters, there was an internal one. His Dao of the Souls would be the best way to go against strong-body refiners. While their bodies were reinforced to an extreme degree, it wasn’t the same for their souls. Even though they might have been beasts made through cloning and selective breeding, they still possessed this core to hold themselves together.

‘Their soul energy is quite weak, It’s like a child driving a tank’

There were several ways of utilizing his Soul Dao but he chose to go with the most lenient one. In truth, he wasn’t sure how he felt about attempting to use this technique. Previously he only used the Dao of Souls against evil spirits that attacked him. Tearing souls from bodies was not something he was inclined to; it was also not as easy as it sounded.

The connection between a body and its soul wasn’t that easily broken. Yet it also wasn’t that hard to affect this strange energy that resided on another plane of existence. It was something that kept everything together. All living creatures in this world had souls, even the ones created through nefarious methods. A corrupted demonic soul was still a soul and could be affected by his Dao.

“Protect me for a second, I need to concentrate.”

Thus when everything was ready he clapped his hands together and began to concentrate. A pale almost transparent aura washed over his body as he gathered his energies. There were a lot of these volcanic beasts everywhere so it would take some force to knock them out at the same time. Even more, if he actually intended to rip away the connection their bodies had with their souls.

The art that he was preparing needed to be on a certain frequency. Luckily these creatures were quite similar to each other which probably had something to do with how they came to be. Suddenly as they approached the group of cultivators and their white-haired leader a colorless burst of energy flew in all directions. It was hard to see and wasn’t even followed by a gust of wind but the moment it enveloped the bodies of the approaching beasts, they crumbled down to the ground.

“Now!”

After giving the signal the group of cultivators turned into a flaming meteor. They flew up into the sky while the monsters that were keeping them in check started to pass out. The group could barely believe it, how could the bloodthirsty swarm of volcanic creatures just drop down?

“Are they all dead?”

“No, I just damaged the connection their souls have to their bodies, it will naturally mend itself in time but for now, they will be passed out for a while.”

Tearing this connection to shreds was also possible but after battling with the squid monster and assembling the teleportation array, Zhang Dong needed some rest. His Qi reserves had been drained by even this wide area stunning technique. There were just too many enemies here, it was better to retreat to the golden palace where everyone else was. With their help, he intended to finally start the counter-offensive and perhaps even take over this pocket dimension.

“Connection to their soul, that’s fascinating.”

“Is it?”

“Yes, soul arts aren’t easily attained, you should teach me some of them if you have the time.”

“What, do you want to inhabit a new body after the old one is unable to have its fun?”

“What? That’s not it!”

Zhang Jin shouted out in protest while trying to concentrate. All of them were using their spiritual energy to produce a shield around themselves. Even the core formation experts were adding with their battle formation that allowed them to fly at an increased pace. With the initial ambush resolved the lava pits and pools remained calm. Without them keeping to the ground they didn’t trigger any new encounters.

“That should do it, relax and gather your energies.”

Soon he gave the order to lower the pace. If they continued for too long they would just burn through all of their Qi and render themselves useless for any further battles that were waiting for them. Returning to the Golden Palace was important but considering that it was a flying fortress, they didn’t really need to worry about the safety of the people there as much.

At a slower pace and with everyone alive they flew forward. Now with some time to organize his thoughts, Zhang Dong could look this place over. The volcanic region was quite a desolate desert of flames. Similar creatures that they just got away from roamed the lands and there were even some capable of flight. Luckily even at the reduced pace they were just too fast.

The flier types looked to have a similar lizardly origin point like the volcanic creatures below. They didn’t seem to be bothered by the toxic fumes escaping from the volcanoes. Their similarity to flying dinosaurs was uncanny but luckily they weren’t quite nimble enough to pose a threat.

‘What do these creatures even eat here? Do they just hunt each other? Doesn’t seem like there is anything that is weak for them to eat…’

There were no volcanic fish that could be eaten, just the unending flames and fumes that shouldn’t be able to support any life. It was as if these monsters were just dumped here to act as a source of spirit points for whenever a person with the system arrived.

‘I still can’t seem to connect with the faction system.’

Soon his attention went away from the mobs living around this place. His system window wasn’t showing his wife or the Golden Palace that she was supposed to be in. It didn’t seem that he would be able to teleport to their location. He could only hope that nothing bad happened before he arrived.

“Gramps, I think everyone rested enough, we need to pick up the pace, I have a bad feeling about this…”

He called out to his grandfather, there was no time to waste, they needed to rendezvous with the others before something like that tentacle monster appeared again. Even if the Golden Palace was resistant it would not survive forever in this type of environment that would eat away at its energy and shields. Sooner or later it would fall and be opened up to a full push by these ferocious beasts.

Chapter 636

“Matriarch, the protective barrier won’t last for much longer, shouldn’t we move to another location?”

“If we move now, it will be hard for Elder Qiang and Jin to find us.”

“But if we remain here, we might not be able to leave, these beasts are relentless, there is no end to them, we need to…”

“Your input is appreciated, Elders but we will hold out for now, that will be all.”

“Matriarch… if that is your wish.”

Five nascent soul elders clasped their hands at Zhang Liena. The group soon left after discussing some issues involving their stay here. Already close to a week had passed in this volcanic area where they had appeared. All search parties that went off too far had not returned to give a report, instead, they were in a constant state of being besieged.

“Was that the right decision…”

“The Patriarch will find his way back to us, he always does.”

“Elder Zhi, you might have more trust in my husband than me but it’s true, he hasn’t let us down before…”

Zhang Zhi was the last one to leave and after the comment, she felt somewhat reassured. Yet, she could not help but worry about Zhang Dong. While others thought of him as some kind of deity, to her he was only a man. His facade of the perfect Patriarch was something that he always did put on but that was the problem, it was partially a facade. His power was tremendous, but he made mistakes and sometimes others needed to pick up the slack.

“I’ll have to move the fortress if this takes too long, the other elders are right, if we run out of power, then it's all over.

The problem was due to their main generator, it was slowly getting drained. Normally the fortress should be able to replenish the energy reserves with time, that was if it wasn’t burning through energy constantly. The protective barrier needed to be in place to shield them from the toxic fumes and hot environment. Not everyone would be able to survive outside if it wasn’t in place.

Then there was the second problem with them wasting energy, constant attacks from the residents. The strange lizard-like creatures with almost impenetrable scales were the problem. They could be defeated by continued spirit cannon barrages but all of this took their precious resources and fuel. The beasts just continued to come at them, even the nascent elders needed to get themselves involved to allow the barrier to function normally.

Even as she was thinking about the correct move forward, the lights turned red as the alarm went off. She hadn’t gotten used to this yet, the red flashing lights and the loud sound was something her husband came up with. Something about it showing the gravity of the situation better than just having an announcement done by an elder.

“What is it now?”

Zhang Liena was the temporary owner of the Golden Palace. She could easily teleport herself to the command room in which she could observe the outside of the palace. The alarm had a tint to it and by the look of it, the situation was dire outside. Normally it started out with a yellow, then moved on to orange, and ended up on red when the situation was critical.

“What is that thing, it's as big as the whole palace… not it’s even bigger…”

She soon realized what the problem was, outside there was a towering being made of molten rock. Its size was gigantic and constantly increasing as it was trying to rise itself out of the lava lake it came from. It had a humanoid shape that lacked any legs, and its underside looked like it was stuck to the ground but perhaps it was only hidden there.

The massive arms were made of black obsidian rock that was on fire. Cracks filled with lava constantly spit out a fiery concoction along with black smoke. Without the need to analyze this thing, it was clear to her that this was a problem. The creature was slow but its size was a problem. With the Golden Dong Palace stationed in place, it would be an easy target for this monstrous being.

There were a few options she could go with, the easiest one would cause more energy to be spent. This volcanic monster that looked like a flaming stone golem was still an easy target. The large number of spirit cannons that were placed on the floating bastion would eventually kill it. How much of the barrier would be damaged in the process was a problem and she also didn’t know if more of these creatures could appear. If they started getting pounded from all sides, sooner or later all of their reserves would run out.

“I haven’t really had an opportunity to test that new gift he made, this might be a good opportunity for it.”

Liena looked at the lumbering giant slowly approaching the golden palace that was conserving its power. Soon she found herself outside where she could see masses of spirit bullets flying from the defensive towers. The shield was designed to allow the cannon fire to pass from the inside but would not allow anything to enter from the other side. The same was true for anyone that wanted to go outside. They would be free to leave but entering back in wouldn’t be as easy. Only someone like Liena had all the privileges could move back and forth at her own pace.

“Matriarch?”

“Stop the cannons, I’ll take care of this creature myself, aim them back at the smaller beasts instead.”

“As you command!”
Her voice echoed through the entire palace and no one dared to say anything against it. The only person that didn’t like this plan was Zhang Zhi who decided to hang out in the back. At the moment he didn’t raise his complaints but Liena knew that he would prefer to perform this task instead.

He was a loyal soldier to her husband and would probably give his life to protect his dear Patriarch’s wife. She wasn’t that fond of this treatment as the man trying to protect her was actually weaker, proving to him that he didn’t need to baby her around was also part of this encounter. Sometimes the people forgot but she was one of the great three founders of this sect and just as strong as any of them.

Soon her form started exuding copious amounts of emerald light. She shot out like an arrow from a bow to cross to the other side clad in a veil of wind energy. The rays of emerald light that were surrounding her body slowly intensified as she went through a change. Everyone could feel it, a great Dao of the Wind taking form and a marvelous power that she wielded with it.

The ugly lava golem that was trying to emerge from the huge lake could see the bolt of green light getting closer. As a reaction to the attack, it started opening its large mouth which was filled with volcanic ash and magma. Soon a torrent of red flames emerged from within with the target being the green energy.

The emerald light looked so tiny in comparison to the huge torrent of lava coming it's way. No one would expect Liena to be able to handle this amount of molten rock. The sect members expected her to just gracefully dodge to the side before launching a counterattack but instead, they saw the lights of their Matriarch being engulfed by the burning earth instead.

Some gasped, others were stunned and even Zhang Zhi reacted in shock. However, before acting, he realized that the power Liena was exuding was still there. Suddenly a massive burst of green took shape, the torrent of lava was forced to the sides and submerged the lizard beasts.

“A mindless beast like you is not a worthy opponent of this Zhang Liena!”

Her form became noticeable to everyone and it had changed. Instead of the flowy dress robe that everyone was used to, a suit of armor could be seen instead. It fully covered her body from head to toe and glistened like an emerald. To her back something that looked like four wings were fluttering yet when taking a closer look, they were metallic in form. Instead of being actual wings made of feathers, they were composed of many flying swords.

These swords were soon utilized as weapons, she just needed to point in a direction with her right hand and the whole wing on the same side started disassembling itself. Multiple green blades emerged and flew right toward the massive beast made from lava. Even though its body was composed of hard rock the swords made it through.

The creature was attempting to smack the glowing green fly away with its massive hand. Yet just as it was taking a swing the shining swords started cutting into it. Their speed was astonishing and each and everyone could produce a green beam of light that cut through the hardened rock. In a matter of moments the monster’s whole arm was shredded into pieces and fell to the ground.

Yet this monster defied the natural laws, even though the chunks of its arm were landing on the ground a new one was forming back in place. A surge of lava escaped from the stump that was left behind. It soon took the same shape as the old limb. The molten rock soon hardened and Liena had to continue with a few more tests to realise that this approach wouldn’t be enough.

“It’s regenerating its body through the connection to the ground.”

She could feel the fire and earth elements being sucked up from underneath to replace any missing body parts. This beast was quite large and when trying to feel for the core that should be the weak point, it wawa hard to pinpoint. There was a vast quantity of fake cores inside the monster. It was one of the ways these creatures became almost impossible to beat as a fake core could become a true core if that one was destroyed.

“If I destroy all the cores at once, it won’t be able to transfer its consciousness into a new one.”

She waved her left hand to activate the flying swords from the left wing. This time instead of using them for more slicing she called back all the blades. They all swirled around in front of her to create something that looked like a sexagram. From the center a massive amount of Qi energy was then quickly gathered as she prepared for a technique that this armor came equipped for. She wasn’t quite sure about the technology her husband invented but the destructive power it had, was quite real.

A massive burst of energy flew forward and collided with the volcanic monster that was still busy reforming its body. The emerald light shredded into the volcanic body tearing it apart into tiny pieces. It was as if the monster was getting cut apart by millions of tiny wind blades, even the swarm of fake cores could not shield it from its demise.

“Hoh… I see you didn’t really need my help…”

The beam flew up into the air to push the clouds to the side and revealed a glowing orb of golden energy hidden within. Inside of it, there were a few familiar faces but only one, in particular, brought a smile to her face.

Chapter 637

“Took you long enough.”

“Sorry for making you worry.”

“Hmph.”

Zhang Dong flew over to his wife that at the moment was clad in the emerald armor that was created for her. During the trip here he was able to pinpoint their location after she activated her prestige unit skill to make her more powerful. With it, she was able to easily destroy the being made from lava and all the fake cores along with it.

“Isn’t that cure, little Liena is blushing.”

“Shut your mouth if you don’t want me to make you into a woman old man!”

One of the blades that were flying in the sky aimed itself at Zhang Jin’s crotch after he made the comment. Then it actually flew toward the old man’s crotch and would have connected with his tool if he didn’t dodge to the side. Zhang Dong started scratching his head while watching his wife chasing after his grandfather. It was quite surprising to see Zhang Jin dodge those high-speed attacks without getting scratched.

“D-dong’er please help me! She has gone crazy!”

“... Should I? Hm…”

“What if she damages it? How could you be so cruel to your grandfather!”

“Ugh, fine…”

Even though it was fun to see his perverted grandfather being chased around by his angry wife, this was not the time to waste their energy. While the huge mountain-sized lava creature had been defeated, it was not the only one out here. When he was flying towards this place where the Golden Palace was parked he saw another of its kind moving to this area. They were probably attracted to either the sounds of battle or the massive amounts of Qi being wasted during it.

“Liena, think that’s enough, the other sect members are looking at you… Do you want to be known as the mad Matriarch in the future?”

He played it off as a joke and it worked like a charm. The people in this world like to keep an image and his wife wasn’t different. The moment she saw some of the juniors and elders glancing her way with confused expressions she managed to return to her old self. The armor that she was wearing vanished into green particles of light and her lovely figure along with her flowy robe was revealed underneath.

“No one saw anything, understood?”

She covered half of her face with one of her battle fans while glaring at the people down below. With haste, all of the sect members started bowing with approval while shouting.

“Yes, Matriarch!”

“Good…”

It was hard for Zhang Dong not to smile in this situation. All the stress and fear of having his sect members along with his wife slaughtered was gone. The palace was there and along with it everyone that had gone out for this trip. While he wasn’t sure if there were no casualties, the palace was in good shape which probably meant that they were all fine.

“I think she grazed it a bit… is it still there?”

Zhang Jin on the other hand started looking down at his robe which had been slightly nicked in a few places. Luckily he discovered that his little gentleman down below had not been damaged. This allowed him to release a sigh of relief while also fleeing from the sky to not get poked at again.

“We should return inside.”

“Yes we should and don’t forget to tell me where you vanished to, I thought that teleportation technique was supposed to be perfect?”

“About that…”

Now that he was flying down to the golden palace along with his wife he had some explaining to do. Previously she was assured by him that nothing could go wrong. Even if they were lost somewhere with the help of his system there would be no way of him finding everyone back.

“It seems that my technique doesn’t work that well if I get stuck in a pocket dimension.”

This was the crux of the problem, these miniaturized worlds that were inside of this fish. For one reason or another, his system was bugging out and Bob couldn’t do anything about it. He wasn’t sure if it was due to the separate dimensions as he would be able to teleport himself into the Dimensional Regalia with the help of his faction system. But this could be due to it being a treasure that he was the master of. Perhaps other similar ones would be able to block out his system which now he needed to account for.

“Does this mean that we won’t be able to escape from here?”

“I don’t think so, if I can’t use my technique then I probably won’t be able to use it on the whole palace like I intended to.”

“Then are we stuck in this place?”

“No, there are ways of getting out of these pocket dimensions, we just need to find the correct area.”

The two continued their conversation while returning to the hidden control room in the golden palace. Zhang Dong could use the system’s or the palace’s teleportation feature to get them out of there but this wasn’t the end of it. He had already managed to assemble a teleportation array to transfer himself and the group of cultivators to the lava dimension. This meant that it was possible to use the old method of traversing through these pocket dimensions and to do that he just needed to pinpoint the correct one.

“So, we need to find the right place?”

“Yes, I don’t think this fish that swallowed us is a sentient being, it’s more like a gateway to other smaller dimensions, like a very complex treasure.”

“Then if it’s a treasure, then it has to have a master!”

“Yes, if we find whoever is controlling this thing, then we’ll be able to leave.”

“Could it be the Cerulean Empress?”

“It might be but I’m not sure how this place works yet, the dimensions are thin in a few places and they also connect to one another.”

“But how will we find such a place? These lands are filled with those creatures, I don’t think they will make it easy for us to pass.”

“The longer it takes us to find the exit the least amount of power will the palace have…”

Zhang Dong knew that there was a way out of this place. In the cold region he was able to find a gate that would allow him to travel to a different area. There he found his grandfather and the other cultivators. He knew that a place like that should be here as well.

‘Bob, if I find another gate like the previous one, could you figure out how this place works?’

‘More data is required for travel, more sources of input are required to calculate the quarry, the possibility is at 24,56%.’

‘I see, so if I give you more time then it could work.’

The previous time he encountered a gate to another pocket dimension he had Bob store the data from it. If he was able to find a secondary gate like the last one, the data that his Ai received could be enough to triangulate other locations. What he was looking were not the ones that brought them to dangerous zones like this one but to the one that the leader of the underwater people resided in.

“It could work.”

“Have you figured out something, husband?”

“Yes, we need to find a certain location first and I think it won’t even be that hard.”

Liena smiled at Zhang Dong who started to go to work. The golden palace needed to take off and head to the next location. The spot that they were occupying was already known by the enemies. They couldn’t just blindly fly through the volcanic area, sooner or later their engines would lose power and he would need to turn himself into a battery to keep everything running.

‘Bob, find the wavelength similar to the gate that I traveled through, there is probably at least one exit like that which connects to another pocket dimension, use the golden palace as a magnifier for the signal if you have to.’

‘Affirmative…’

‘Calculating…’

‘Signal found, 94,23% match, sending over coordinates…’

It took a few minutes but Bob was able to find a spot with a strong enough signature. Soon enough the Golden Palace was starting to take off and flying in that direction. On the many screens that were in the control room, he could see the volcanic creatures following after them. They were all over the place, it didn’t seem that this volcanic area had any safe locations devoid of conflict.

Without the giant base that could hold so many people, it would have probably not been possible to minimize the casualties this much. It was the correct choice to wait for enough system points for the upgrade. If he took the previous version of the Golden Dong Palace into these depths, then it would not have been such a smooth ride.

Even with him knowing the way the road was a bumpy one. The monsters were on to them and continued to chase them throughout the entire journey. Getting their shields pelted with lava-filled rocks was an hourly occurrence. Their ship wasn’t the fastest one and as they were trying to conserve power, they couldn’t move at full capacity.

It took a few days but they made it to the location that Bob pinpointed. It was another giant structure but this time instead of a tower it looked like a mountain stretching above the heavens.

‘This one clearly connects somewhere as well but I’m not sure if we should just cross through it. Then there is the problem of taking the palace with us…’

It didn’t seem that it would be possible for the whole golden palace would fit through the dimensional door that was hidden within this mountain. At the bottom was a similar-sized gate that could probably only fit people through it. Leaving the flying fortress that was their main weapon wasn’t really an option so another way needed to be found to get through here.
‘Bob begin the analysis.’

‘Affirmative.’

Zhang Dong gave the order as his intention was to figure out the pattern between these connectors. If he could map them out then it would be possible to just teleport to the source without the need of jumping through hoops. Yet to his surprise, this wouldn’t be as easy as he hoped for.

‘Warning…warning… threat detected.’

‘Huh? What is it now?’

The moment Bob began analyzing the pathway forward some type of defensive system was triggered. It was similar to the time he attempted to bust his way through the sky and with it triggered more of the lava monsters would be coming to this location.

Chapter 638

“That’s a lot of them…”

“Where did all of these monsters come from?”

“This didn’t happen in the previous zone, it must be some inbuilt defensive mechanism against analyzing the gates.”

“Defensive mechanism?”

Zhang Dong nodded to Liena who could also see a scene playing out on the outside. The whole place became shrouded in black smoke. Previously they could at least see something but now it was as if a demonic miasma was being conjured by an evil cultivator. From within this dark mist, more of those strange creatures started arising. Their intent was obvious as they all charged at the golden palace that was hovering slightly above the ground.

‘When I was in the ice zone they stopped attacking me when I arrived at the teleportation spot. They have some type of ingrained command that will force them to back off or attack depending on a situation, this is clear.’

It was like fighting an army made out of automatons. The creatures didn’t seem to have a mind of their own and reacted to something their creator ingrained into their brains. It was clear that his hacking attempt was the trigger for this situation to arise. The person that created this pocket dimension maze didn’t want anyone to shorten the trip. Perhaps the path was linear but it was possible that more of these teleportation spots existed.

‘This would have been fine if I came alone but there is no way I’m getting out of here without the palace.’

While Bob was busy analyzing the teleportation patterns he got up from his chair. Along with Liena, they needed to head outside to stall the monsters. There was one unconfirmed theory, that this place was meant for a solo adventure and could only be finished by a system holder. It was possible that if he tried to go through the gate alone that it would be shut off.

His people would then be stuck in this lava region facing countless waves of volcanic monsters. There was no way of knowing that even if he reached the end if they would be set free. This whole place was somewhat above his knowledge as he had no idea how pocket dimensions were formed. All that he could do was analyze the portals between them.

Luckily he wasn’t alone, even without giving out the commands the people in the palace quickly picked up the pace. The cannons started reigning down doom on the approaching beasts and the nascent soul masters used their own attacks to support everyone. They were like a well-oiled machine that knew how to handle things.

This force was mostly composed of the cultivators that were fighting out on the sea. They knew how to circle out and keep everyone fresh. There was a system in place allowing only the well-rested warriors that be directly involved on the battlefield. The ones that were tired would quickly retreat and get treated for the loss of stamina and spiritual energy. After they were back at full it was time to go back.

“I guess they don’t really need me…”

“Stay here and leave everything to us, the Patriarch needs to be ready for the worst case scenario.”

”I guess you are right, be careful out there.”

Liena along with Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang were all out there doing their thing. Zhang Dong on the other hand remained in the control chamber while the analysis took place. If he didn’t use up his own Qi then it would actually go a little bit faster. As the strongest person in the sect he needed to conserve his battle power. If a being of unfathomable power arrived he needed to be ready to battle it when at full power. If he used up too much energy on minions and side bosses, everything could turn sour fast.

It wasn’t the easiest thing for him to do. Just sitting here while doing nothing wasn’t really his style. Ever since he arrived in this world he was kind of forced to act by himself while the people he led only had a small role to fill. Now that they had been trained up to a force that could rival the old big three, it was time to let them handle things. Zhang Dong needed to stop treating his people like little children that needed him for every small thing.

This wasn’t the easiest thing for him to swallow. He knew that if he didn’t get involved that people would get hurt and perhaps even make bad decisions. Yet just as a parent sending off their child into the world he needed to do the same for his people. They needed to be able to handle themselves, otherwise if something happened to him, they would be defenseless. Finally, they were able to defend themselves, all that hard work, sweat, and tears was all for a day like this to arrive.

‘80%...85%...89%...92%...99%... calculations finished, transferring data to the user.’

The analysis of the signal had been done and now it was just a matter of time for him to input it into the golden palace. First off he needed to see where they were and how many of the pocket dimensions other than this were accessible.

‘Bob, give me a visual representation of the situation.’

‘Affirmative.’

While the rumbling noises continued outside he looked at one of the screens that was being filled out by some spheres. They looked like marbles with different colors, the red one in the middle was a representation of the lava pocket dimension he found himself. Other ones had their own main theme that gave him an idea about the most prevalent Dao in them.

‘So this is where I am and that one looks like the one gramps and Qiang were sent to… everything is connected…’

There was not much variation in the structure of these pocket dimensions. They were created in a straight line that wrapped around like a serpent. The ice biome that he arrived in had two locations it connected to, one of them was the previous world he found his grandfather in. There were always two pathways that could be taken but everything was connected into one singular pathway.

‘So, if we just keep going through the gates we will arrive at the ice zone I first appeared in? This can’t be right, there must be something else…’

‘Bob, is there a hidden area somewhere? This can’t just be a loop of pocket dimensions, there must be some type of way out of here… Try to analyze the data again.’

‘...Hidden world found… attempting to find a pathway…’

Just as he had concluded there was an area that connected to the middle. There seemed to be one main world right in the middle of the serpent. All of the side dimensions connected to it but it required more time to analyze. This of course put more time constraints on the whole situation which was quickly turning ugly.

Many large-scale volcanic monsters like the one Liena destroyed had managed to arrive. They were showering the protective barrier with their volcanic fists and attacks. Eleven when they were pelted by multiple attacks they were hard to eradicate. The false cores were almost impossible to destroy at once without using up one of the special transformations.

This power had a cooldown period and wasting it on a wave of monsters before going into the belly of the beast wouldn’t be the best idea. There was a secondary option though, instead of teleporting to the main pocket dimension they could make their way into one of the smaller ones. They would be used as a soft reset as the monsters there should not be aware of their whereabouts.

The only problem was just like before, the Golden Palace. Considering that he needed to get it over to the other side in its entirety, it would cost a lot of energy. After one jump they would burn through half of it. They would be unable to make repeatable jumps and could even find themselves estranged in the new area. It would be much better to have a fully functioning fortress when they arrived at the enemy's doorstep.

‘Bob, keep at it.’

After giving his Ai the order he looked at the screens to see a small problem. The long battle outside had attracted something even worse than the titanic lava golems. It was something that reminded him of his familiar that was left in the main sect as its main protector. It was a massive dragon that was as big as four of those lava creatures put together. It didn’t seem to possess any wings capable of flight but its massive size that towered over everything was real.

This was not an opponent that the golden palace and his sect could handle alone. The fire coming out of this dragon’s mouth would not be stopped by the barriers for too long. Even as he was glancing at the monitors he could already see the energy dropping down rapidly. This time around he would need to go outside to get his own hands dirty. At least that was his intention yet before he could step take a step out of the hidden control room, he received a private message.

“Senior Brother, let me handle this.”

“Qiang? Are you sure? That thing might be too much for even you.”

“Haha, this is what I live for!”

Huo Qiang was willing to endanger himself to fight this massive monster instead of him. Zhang Dong wasn’t so sure about this but if he went outside now then this whole thing would take even longer. Bob needed to use his spiritual energy for processing power. It was like trying to run a game while many files were being copied at the same time in the background. It was certainly not an optimal process and not like there was an end to these monsters here.

“Very well, just be careful, that thing is probably resistant to flame attacks.”

“Haha, it might be but so am I!”

Just like Liena his wife Huo Qiang was in possession of a separate mode. His armor was soon taking form as he finally activated his battle mode. The frame wasn’t too bulky but the sun designs became apparent. He was someone that could wield the Dao of the Flame almost to perfection and along with it came the energy that stars were made from.

The battle between the two fire-wielding monsters soon started. The environment that was composed of hard obsidian rocks started melting as the dragon opened its huge mouth to intercept the incoming fire cultivator. A battle of immense proportions was taking place and for once Zhang Dong would watch it from the sidelines.

Chapter 639

“Take this, Solar BUSTERRRRRR!

“...”

“Tremble before the might of Huo Qiang, the sun god!”

“...”

“Haven’t had enough?”

‘Does he have to shout out his attacks every time, I know that that dragon is slow… but everyone from the sect can hear him.’

Zhang Dong had trouble concentrating on helping Bob crack the code to the main pocket dimension where their true enemy was probably hiding. When the massive dragon monster appeared before them he was going to defeat it but instead Huo Qiang wanted to have a go at it. It seemed that he was actually winning but the performance was rather loud and unnecessarily long.

Huo Qiang quickly shifted into his enhanced form that placed him inside of a large glowing armor. He did look like a sun deity by tossing large plasma-filled solar bombs at the fire dragon. Even this creature made of molten rock started to melt into liquid as the fight continued. It seemed that after a while he shifted from taking it seriously to showboating. The sect members that cheered him on from afar only fueled this whole situation.

‘Maybe I shouldn’t have recreated those comics and mangas when I was bored.’

A while back he implemented a new technique that he became aware of. Thanks to his brain being enhanced as a cultivator he could recall all the pieces of fiction he once read or saw back in his previous world. It was quite easy to infuse those old works into books inside his system library. Then copying it into the real world wasn’t hard anymore and some of those works contained manga. These usually had the heroes call out their special attacks before attacking and after reading a few Qiang seemed to develop this quirk.

‘Well… he probably won’t go overboard with it, at least he is luring the other monsters away from the palace with all of that shouting.’

With the flamboyant performance, it was hard for the creatures to concentrate on one target. It was actually a good tactic to lure them toward Huo Qiang and that huge dragon boss. The beast was so huge that it could destroy even the lava golems. Even now one was crumbling after getting hit by a tail swipe. The monster was clearly enraged as the fight wasn’t going its way.

‘Bob, speed it up.’

Soon he just decided to sit down and concentrate. By relegating some of his own spiritual energy into Bob the process could be hastened. Only now that he knew that there was no reason to save up power did he push himself to the limit.
‘Calculations complete, sending trajectory data to the user.’

‘Finally!’

The triangulations were complete and the visual representation of the map showed him a world filled with green and blue energy. This indicated that the element of wood along with water were probably the most prevalent there. Perhaps this was a clue to what he would be getting if he managed to defeat the master of that place. Yet he couldn’t know if that was the finish line for this military expedition.

‘Hm… this is going to take out a lot of energy… luckily these monsters let me farm more spirit points.’

While he couldn’t farm spirit points by killing monsters it was possible to use it in tandem with his faction system. The monster waves that were being cleared out by anyone above a certain favorability ranking was giving him some points. This together with the constant passive gains from his enlarged territory would be enough for a two-way trip.

“Qiang, stop playing around and come back, I’ll be teleporting us and the Golden Palace away from this place and you better be in range before that happens.”

“Already Senior Brother? Fine, I shall end the life of this overgrown lizard!”

After it was possible everyone was given the order to return to the inner parts of the palace. They all needed to be inside during the teleportation procedure or otherwise, they would be lost in this place forever. Soon the only person that didn’t retreat was Huo Qiang that instead was gathering a large attack over his head.

It was somewhat similar to Zhang Dong’s finishing move which created a miniaturized star. Qiang on the other hand made his from plasma energy which made it look like a smaller sun. It was then promptly tossed at the already injured volcanic dragon that could only activate its fire breath to go against it. The two forces clashed with each other to generate a massive explosion. Even the creatures that lived in this volcanic region weren’t able to sustain themselves in all this heat. Their scales and hides started turning to black charcoal or just melting.

Soon the golden palace started glowing brightly and together with the flame technique, everything in the vicinity went white. Where once stood the massive golden palace nothing more remained and near it a giant hole that spawned a few kilometers with a headless dragon remained.

“Did you see that!”

“Yes, I saw a lot of stupidity, there was no reason to cut it so close you idiot, when my husband gives you an order you better comply immediately!”

“You’re just jealous that I took out their boss!”

“Why you!”

“Calm down you two, this is not the time for petty squabbles, we could be in for a lot of resistance on the other side so conserve your strength.”

Zhang Dong’s voice could be heard through the speakers. He was still sitting in the command room and adding power to the teleportation procedure that was taking place. The golden palace was shaking quite a bit and the shields outside were having some trouble holding together. The passage through dimensions wasn’t that easy and he still didn’t fully understand it.

He could only let the system along with Bob guide him through it while hoping for the best. This was not something he wanted to keep relying on. The system that he was given was created by a strange unknown force. The reason for its existence was unknown to him but it didn’t seem to be anything too good. If it was created by a benevolent god then monsters like Wang Long would not have been created from it. The Overseer that was there didn’t even react to the wanton destruction that he created.

The only time it showed itself was when he was about to go through a transformation into something new and greater. It was as if these beings were only here to keep the system holders from discovering the full truth of the matter. Perhaps if his strange cultivation variation was found he would be in for a world of pain. Before that could happen he needed to get stronger and clearing out this last area could bring him over the edge.

‘We are here…’

The Golden Palace stopped shaking as it finally appeared in the hidden region. All the other ones were connected to form a loop. Perhaps there was a secret pathway that would be created after he visited all of those pocket dimensions but through this way, he was free to end it faster.

‘Looks quite peaceful… similar to the area I arrived in first but there is a lot more of this strange water here…’

At first glance, there was no reason to be alarmed. The creatures of this new zone didn’t seem too violent or too powerful. It was a quiet place filled out with breathable water like in the underwater base of that squid monstrosity. This water was very clear and didn’t really impede the view as much as regular seawater did.

To check some more he gave Bob the order to scan for everything he could find. All the information was transferred to the golden palace’s main computer which could then forward the information to his army. They were quickly getting a visual representation of the region's geographical structure.

“Is everyone alright? If you feel teleportation sickness please rest for a bit in the medical chamber.”

“P-patriarch, you are here.”

Zhang Dong removed himself from his hidden command room and appeared in the official one where all the elders from his sect gathered. Zhang Zhi and Liena were here along with Zhang Jin. Huo Qiang had barely made it in so his location was outside the inner walls of the golden palace. His condition wasn’t all too great, the amount of spiritual energy he went through to defeat the large dragon was staggering. At the time being, he was passed out on the ground in a starfish position.

“Can someone peel Qiang off the ground? The barrier is still in place but the water should be breathable even if that doesn’t make sense. “

“Patriarch, should we be cautious of it?

“It should be fine but considering the enemy, we are facing is proficient in water techniques, it would perhaps be better to minimize the contact.”

The elders in the room nodded at each other. Even though the water allowed them to function without using air this didn’t mean it was safe. What if the strange liquid entered their bodies and was then used against them by whoever was living in this place. Taking in a foreign substance always carried a risk so it was better to remain vigilant and evade any contact as if it was composed of poison mist.

“Dong’er I’ll be the first to ask, where are we now?”

“Let me explain the structure of these strange zones to you first before we continue.”

Zhang Dong presented his theory to the elders gathered in the room. The circular structure and that they found themselves in a hidden area that they should not be in. Immediately everyone was stunned by the scale as they could see the mockup map that Bob had created for Zhang Dong before. There were twenty-one other pocket dimensions in this anglerfish that they found themselves in. Each and every one of them was the size of the current dimensional regalia.

“Fascinating, what is this creature, and who would be capable of creating such a being… is it even alive, or is it some type of automaton with no soul?”

Some of the elders brought their speculations to the forefront. Zhang Dong himself was inclined to believe that the fish was not a real living being. If it actually had a proper soul then it would have been large enough for him to notice it. Instead, the monster fish was already chomping down on the golden palace before anyone knew what was going on.

“That’s a good theory but we must stay focused, I expect heavy resistance after whoever owns this place realizes that we are here.”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

While it would have been nice to have the drop on their enemies, they were in a strange place that worked on peculiar rules. There was no way of knowing what would happen to them after their protective barrier stopped working and before that could happen they needed to get this mission over with.

Chapter 640

“This looks like it’s going to take a while.”

“They aren’t budging an inch, this barrier is one strong barrier…”

Zhang Dong, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Liena were looking at the screen. There they could see a bunch of spirit blasts colliding with what looked to be a giant soap bubble. Inside this bubble, there was a massive structure that was covered in a strange haze. More than likely this was the last place in this journey but they were having trouble in getting through it.

“Patriarch!”

“Speak, how much longer will it take?”

“The elders believe that it will take more than two months.”

“Two months? That is a lot of time…”

“That it is…”

Replied Huo Qiang while yawning. Ever since they arrived at this new location not much had happened. It had become a snooze fest for everyone yet they were unable to relax. The longer they stayed in this strange pocket dimension the worse everyone’s mental state became. Some like Qiang were holding it in but he knew that others would not.

“Hm…”

“This sounds troubling. If we waste two months in here we put ourselves in danger. We also might not have enough energy left for the main battle with their leader, what should we do? ”

Zhang Liena commented while the three main elders deliberated. In reality, it was mostly just him thinking of a way to get there. Huo Qiang was just a muscle brain that was only good when a fight broke out. Liena on the other hand was a lot more helpful but would also not push the matter too much, instead she would give him a few choices on which he needed to decide by himself.

“There is probably a way to shut that thing off from the inside…”

“There is Senior Brother?”

“Are you an idiot? Why wouldn’t there be?”

“It could be one of those barriers, you know the ones that become stronger if they just focus on defense!”

Huo Qiang laughed at Zhang Liena that furrowed her eyebrows. Luckily he was here to stare the two down before they could get into another fight. For once Qiang was actually right, some barriers were only in a single direction which enhanced their defensive capabilities. Even with their massive cannons and the golden palace along with a few leftover flying ships, they weren’t even putting a small opening in the thing.

“Perhaps their leader never intended to leave their headquarters? This could be why we only saw waves of cloned troops instead.”

He murmured while taking into account that this whole place was probably set up to be a solo mission for a system holder. If he went at it from that angle then another option of getting in there should be somewhere. This also meant that bringing his forces here had been a mistake on his part which actually made this whole mission a lot more difficult. Now he needed to watch for his troops' safety as they were unable to teleport out of the large fish that swallowed them all.

This complicated things as he couldn’t just leave them all here. What would happen to them if even after taking care of the enemy Emperor there was no way of getting out? Would the Golden Palace be able to handle a collapsing pocket dimension or another trip through them?

At the moment it was possible for him to squeeze through the pathways between these dimensions but the path outside was being blocked by something. Perhaps all the answers that he was looking for were inside this soap bubble but if he entered it then he was risking the lives of his people.

‘What’s the alternative here… waiting for two months or more? There might be another barrier if we try forcing it inside, what if something happens to the kids while we are in here?’

He could not trust his so-called older brother. The Azure Emperor was a big unknown to him which made him a potential threat. Perhaps the Heavenly Crane Sect was afraid of him now but this wasn’t the same for the Long Clan. Without him in Spirit Spring City, spies would be able to sneak in.

What if they send word that he was missing and someone decided to attack? The Azure Emperor was probably on the same level as the other Emperors. He would be able to make it in as the strongest three elders were all out on this mission. Then there was also that overseer that he didn’t know much about. The longer they stayed in this place, the more dangerous it got for the people outside.

“What are you thinking about?”

“... I might have to do something that you probably won't be too happy about, my lovely wife.”

“Oh do tell?”

“Well…”

While he was thinking about the next step, Bob was busy analyzing everything in their vicinity. If he was not meant to go through the direct route then there had to be another one. Just like in the other pocket dimension he had discovered small underground tunnels that spawned through everything like an anthill. This was probably his way in and he needed to do it alone.

“You want to crawl through those tunnels alone? I’m not sure if that’s such a good idea.”

“Yes, senior brother, how about I go instead?”

“Your Dao of Flames is ill-suited for traversing those dark underwater caves. Sending a larger force won’t work either, they are very narrow and surrounded by strangely resistant rocks, even I wouldn’t be able to force my way through without using a large amount of my own spiritual energy…”

Everything kind of confirmed his previous theory of this being a test for a system holder. Bob was able to analyze the underground pathways to an extent. After around two hundred meters all of the bedrock became incredibly hard. It was possible that it was made from similar rocks that surrounded those nuclei with massive amounts of spiritual energy in them. This place had clearly been tailor-made for him to go through it alone and everyone else would just be a burden if they followed after him.

“It’s ill-suited? Maybe junior Zhi should go instead then?”

“Oh? You can actually say smart things from time to time?”

“Well, of course!... Hey, what’s that supposed to mean!”

His wife was not willing to let him go that easily. Zhang Zhi, who was a master in the Dao of Water would probably be able to survive the trip, at least to a point. He didn’t have an Ai companion like Bob that could show him the way. Even if he made it inside the soap bubble he would probably not be able to find a way to shut it off. It was possible for him to handle a general-class enemy but if that Empress appeared then he would probably be a goner.

“I don’t think Zhang Zhi will be up to the task, this is something that only I can probably do. Don’t worry, I’m just going to find a way to disable this barrier, you then need to be ready to come to my aid.”

“It sounds like you have already made the decision to leave.”

“I’m sorry but we won’t be able to progress any other way. Let me explain, this is more similar to an immortal abode.”

To get his wife on his side he had Bob show her the layout of the underground tunnels on the large screen. It was a large maze of thousands of narrow corridors without any way of knowing where to really go. Only with the help of the system’s mapping function and his knowledge about illusory formations would he be able to get through this maze. Any other person would be trapped there and perhaps never be able to come out.

“The rocks are too sturdy, even Zhi wouldn’t be able to dig himself out of there if he got lost and I don’t think maneuvering through underground tunnels is one of his specialties.”

“You do have more experience in infiltration… a bit too much if you ask me.”

Liena narrowed her eyes while frowning. To her, it was suspicious that he always went away on these strange missions. It was as if he liked to put himself in danger or didn’t trust anyone else to do a better job. Yet she also couldn’t think about anyone from their sect that would be able to outdo her husband in this field. Even less after he showcased his brand new Darkness Dao. It was impossible for even her to tell if he was inside of the room if he decided to hide inside of a shadow.

“Fine but you better inform me about your whereabouts whenever you can, I’ll be waiting!”

“No problem, that should be possible for now… at least until I go inside that barrier.”

At this point in time, his faction system was back to working in a diminished fashion. He was not able to reach anyone outside but at least everyone that was here in this pocket dimension was identified by it. Thanks to this even teleporting back into the golden palace should be possible and communicating with Liena and the others was also possible.

Thus after he had the talk with his wife and Qiang he made his preparations. To not make it look like they were plotting anything the golden palace would continue with the attack. It would act as a distraction while he went through the mass of tunnels down below them. Luckily this place also had a day and night cycle which made it easy for him to go unnoticed.

While sinking into the shadows he made his way down onto the land. The strange feeling of having this breathable water did not go away and it was even stranger after he had to sink into an actual lake to get to one of the entrances. It was a very similar experience as in the other pocket dimension.

Thus he continued while shrouded in full darkness. With Bob’s help, he could map out each tunnel that he went through. Perhaps the other dimension was supposed to be a practice run for this first maze as it was very similar yet slightly more intricate in its design. Thanks to that previous experience he was inclined to believe that this would be another cakewalk.

Perhaps it wouldn’t even take an hour to get through all of this and turn off the barrier above him, yet he couldn’t be more mistaken in his assumption as this new maze was not as easy to traverse as the other ones…

Chapter 641

“This is starting to get annoying, how would a normal person get through this, even I can barely figure things out…”

Zhang Dong looked at his mapping device which was all covered in red lines. After descending into this maze of tunnels he didn’t expect to almost get lost. There were many more corridors than in the other dimension and even if he had the mapping function with himself it was becoming hard to read.

Previously he assumed it to just be the usual same-looking tunnels with similar distraction tactics. Most of the time there was an easy pattern to them along with a few formations that kept the right paths from being noticed. He had already traversed many mazes like that and with the help of his system, he was able to traverse through them at a rapid pace. This one was a bit different though as there was a whole spatial element included.

Normally, illusory formations were used to confuse anyone that was going through the tunnels. Here on the other hand he was getting teleported to other locations after going through specific paths in the tunnels. To make all of this even worse these teleportation spots liked to shift around and put him in different places. The patterns were non-existent and some of the tunnels were actually moving and changing as he was passing through.

Due to this, it was almost useless to look at the map and the redline that represented the paths that he took. After a few minutes the pathways would shift into different locations and where he previously went through would have changed into a wall.

‘This isn’t going to work… no one without a system would be able to get through this place, this is true but there has to be a way to find the exit. Bob, have you managed to analyze the spatial pattern?’

‘Calculations 96% complete…’

‘Good.’

After taking a little break to wait for Bob to finish the calculations he removed the red chicken scratch from the map. It would be of no help to look at the old paths that he took if the maze was constantly shifting around. His attempts to drill through the walls were also ineffective. Even he with his current power could barely scratch the walls here. Only if there was a thin layer of rocks between other paths would it actually be possible.

‘Calculation complete. Sending the spatial readings to the user.’

‘There we go… So that’s how it works…’

Only thanks to Bob was he able to make out what was actually happening. It seemed that this whole place was riddled with hidden portals and spatial traps. Sometimes he would be teleported to another location while other times he sunk through a side dimension into this one. There were multiple ways of getting lost here and without Bob he would have probably needed the system to teleport himself out to the start of the dungeon.

Now after the code had been cracked he could try searching for the correct patterns or go through a different approach. If he could change the coordinates of the traps like he did before then it should be possible to arrive at an area that lacked these time wasters. There was also a third approach he could take by disabling the traps he already went through. This would not do anything about the shifting tunnels but would still allow him to see the paths that he had not yet been in.

‘Let’s go Bob, this isn’t over yet.’

Thus he started trying to pinpoint the issue and reverse engineering the spatial passageways. After going through a few more of them Bob had enough data to block out the traps from ever activating. Now he could map out the area again which started looking a lot more uniform.

Whenever a shift in the maze occurred he just needed to either backtrack to a location that had not been traversed yet or just force himself through a thinner wall. Without the teleportation traps being able to halt his advance he was soon able to get through this first stop-gap and only had to waste a few hours of his time on the whole thing.

‘A regular cultivator would probably be stuck there forever…’

It wouldn’t be strange for anyone else to just starve to death inside this spatial maze. He wasn’t even sure how a regular system holder with the cash shop would get over this thing. Perhaps there would have been some treasures that they could buy for a huge amount of spirit points for this part. This would explain all of the cloned troops that could be farmed for points beforehand.

Nevertheless, after passing through this last tunnel he would be out of this dreaded maze. Going through the narrow tunnels in darkness was not for the faint of heart. Luckily this was only a test of pathfinding, there were no monsters lurking in the shadows to push in the course. Perhaps if he spent more time then he would start seeing things, there were some illusory formations here and there that were dormant.

‘It’s bright.’

His eyes were hit by a radiant glow of light after he pushed through the last spatial tunnel. He was finally out but this place didn’t look like the inside of the soap bubble that he was working to turn off. For the whole trip through the maze, it felt that he was going in all sorts of directions but mostly down.

‘So is this now a monster level? Kill all the monsters and arrive at the end where the big bad boss is or something?’

He gave out a sigh as he could instantly feel the presence of living beings around him. They looked like some kind of mix between the fish people that attacked his lands and spirit or demonic beasts. This area was crawling with them and only thanks to his deceptive techniques was he able to keep them from becoming aware of his presence.

‘It was the right choice to keep myself hidden, these things seem to have been placed here for an ambush. Some are even hiding within the ground ready to pounce…’

The area was a mix of rocks and forests which made it easy to use the previously gained shadow-hiding technique. Within a few moments, he was out of the introductory space right outside the maze and up a large tree. The plants here were gigantic and the trees reached up to half a kilometer. This was the same for the monsters hidden everywhere, the whole place was swarming with them.

‘This would have really been troublesome if I took more people with me. It looks like another smaller pocket dimension again, the person that made this place was really good at making those.’

The area he was in wasn’t as large as the pocket worlds he previously visited. It was hard to make out as there was something like a giant fog blocking his senses from spreading further than a few kilometers. There didn’t seem to be a fake sun to keep everything illuminated, instead, he could see many smaller glowing squares stuck to the rocky ceiling above.

‘Are those giant centipedes in there?’

When glancing up he could see holes in the rocks that were occupied by giant insects. There were thousands of them up there and their size was above that of an average human. It wouldn’t be strange if they pounced at him if he attempted flying through the air.

‘Do they want a person to go through the forest instead? There are also flying beasts everywhere…’

Another area to keep him away looked to have been prepared for someone with a system. Zhang Dong could see a system holder training here for weeks and taking out the nascent soul and core formation level beasts until moving on. Perhaps this area was here to make up for the loss of spirit points that were needed to traverse the earlier maze.

‘Well… I don’t really need to do this.’

He couldn't get any points from slaying these monsters so there was no reason for him to stay here. With the use of the shadows, he just continued to traverse through the forest while examining the beasts stationed. They seemed to be aligned with the water and wood elements the most. A lot of insectoid variants were fused with fishy monsters. At his current power level, it didn’t take him long to get through this place as he didn’t lose any time hunting the creatures.

‘Is this supposed to be the way forward? I never liked spiders…’

The entire forest area was encased in a massive barrier of rocks and there was only one place to go through. A chasm covered in webbing was before him and inside he could see many tiny eyes that belonged to the spider monsters inside. With his mastery of the Darkness, he could clearly see the hidden monstrosities inside.

‘There are so many of them, big and small…’

Luckily for him, in his shadowy form, he was unable to get stuck in the net. The monsters that made this their home weren’t much different than any other demonic spider species. They usually reacted to sound or body heat. Whenever someone arrived in their territory the sound waves of their footsteps would travel through the net to inform the arachnids of their prey.

In a matter of minutes, he was already traversing through the nets. They had some poisonous attributes along with a paralyzing effect. However, while in this strange shadowy form, he was fully immune to it all. Without much trouble, he arrived at the last chamber with what looked to be a sleeping spider queen.

‘Hm… looks like a black widow Arachne…’

The monster had a part that was humanoid in nature. It was actually quite beautiful and very similar to the human part of the mermaids he encountered. It was just stuck to a massive spider with many more tiny ones crawling all over its body. This monstrosity was probably supposed to be his last enemy as it was slumbering right above a large gate.

‘ So, normally if I stepped forward it would jump down on me along with the smaller spiders to act as a distraction… Whoever made this thing will probably be mad…’

Zhang Dong slithered away towards the gate and squeezed himself through a tiny gap in his shadowy form. The last spider boss would not be able to fulfill her duty as he was already on the other side. Two obstacles were gone but how many more troublesome areas awaited him was unknown. He could only hope that whoever created all of this wouldn’t be mad after seeing that he just ignored most of their hard work.

Chapter 642

‘I guess this one can’t be cheesed as easily…but that doesn’t mean that it isn’t possible.’

Zhang Dong sat in the shadows while looking at a large monster on a huge circular platform. After passing through the level with large numbers of monsters he arrived at this location. This one seemed to be similar to the second stopgap but not quite. Instead of a large open area, it was a smaller closed one with an enemy waiting for him. This enemy was just waiting for him while nothing was happening.

‘Scan complete.’

‘There we go, let me see…’

He did not try to attack the monster just yet. This would obviously set something in motion that perhaps he could not stop later. It was better to sit back in shadow form while letting Bob analyze the situation. To no surprise, this location turned out to be something like a boss gauntlet.

This was the first floor of a tower-like structure. It was around a hundred meters in diameter with thick walls that could not be easily destroyed. What Bob counted were fifty floors with a new enemy waiting for him. The one that was standing here was relatively weak but this didn’t mean that the other ones would be the same.

‘So, I reckon that after I kill this one, I’ll be forced to the higher floor, rinse and repeat.’

After looking at the data before him it was easy to come to a conclusion about this place. It was more a test of stamina than actual power. He would need to face beasts that probably became stronger with each level. The breaks between the fights would probably be quite short and he had no place to run.

‘Are there any cracks to slip through or will I need to just do this the traditional way.’

Conserving his energy was an important tactic. If he continued to fight these beasts then he would not be at his best when facing off against the main enemy. He needed to plan for the future and not be stuck here fighting the lackeys one by one. Luckily he was not the average system holder and there were ways to hack into these trials with the help of his Ai. The predecessor that lent it out to him was truly a lifesaver.

‘So there is something like this here…’

The walls were made from a similar material to the one where he found those strange cubes. It lacked the ability to block out his map but was similarly resistant to any impacts and spirit energy. With some help, he spotted a side entrance that would normally not be accessible to anyone. Perhaps the person that made this thing used it to travel through the levels. Only by waiting here and letting Bob analyze everything was he even able to discover it.

‘Hack it Bob.’

After spotting the area in the wall he waited another fifteen minutes for his Ai to open the path forward. After triggering the mechanism the black rocky walls opened up to reveal something that looked like a modern-day elevator. When looking inside he could see the same number of levels represented as buttons on the side. They went all the way from one to fifty with one level being even above this.

‘This should take me all the way to the next spot.’

This was a strange side entrance so he still needed to remain vigilant. When inside of it he gave Bob the order to look for anything detrimental to his health.

‘No protective systems spotted.’

‘Hm? I guess this makes some sense. Whoever made this probably didn’t expect anyone to find this elevator. No reason to bother with defensive measures.’

People with immense power tended to undervalue anyone that was below them. The immortal that created this tower with many nascent-level monsters in it probably didn’t expect anyone to be able to get in here. There wasn’t even a system to scan for a spirit signature of the owner, they clearly didn’t expect Zhang Dong to have something like an Ai to open it and guide him in.

Thus after stepping in he pressed the last button that would take him to the fifty-first level. With some more luck, it would take him to another area through which he could easily travel through. Usually after finding one of these secret areas, traversing through the others was easier.

‘This place looks similar, could that guy have been here too?’

After traveling through all of the fifty levels he arrived at the top one. After the doors opened up he was ready to defend himself against some ancient golems that were left behind as a defensive mechanism. Instead, he found a room with many monitors, it looked like something a person could find in a casino just without anyone actually working there.

‘This design looks like something from earth… Could someone from there be the one behind all of this or…’

When moving forward into this strange monitoring room he began thinking. Usually, there were no coincidences in this world. This place looked similar to the one back where it all started. These monitors were very similar to the ones that his predecessor used along with the machines here. There was a difference though, they weren’t as destroyed by time.

‘Could he have found one of these locations and based his technology on them? That wouldn’t be strange, that’s probably how he was able to figure things out and was able to crack my system…’

This theory had some merit to it, or at least that’s what Zhang Dong was thinking. If this location existed then perhaps other ones were out there as well. He usually didn’t sit tight foir half an hour while letting Bob scan everything. It was normal that he didn’t locate any other of these locations.

‘This is good… Bob, take as much data as you can from here.’

‘Affirmative.’

If he could have his Ai get the pattern down of these spots it would help him against the overseer. Ways of combating those beings could very well be at one of these locations. This one didn’t seem to have much to it as it was just something used for monitoring and getting around the locations. He could even see all the fifty levels and beasts waiting for him there.

‘There is some sort of time lock on these levels… that’s how these creatures have managed to survive for this long…’

This reminded him of his encounter with the Azure Empress. For a moment she managed to halt time and grab the item that was left behind by Wang Long. This was also a type of Dao that allowed people to affect time. It seemed that whoever was behind this all had some type of understanding in it and perhaps this sample here could help him find a countermeasure in the future.

‘This will probably take a while…’

Normally he would have to give Bob some time to analyze the strange frozen zone. At the moment he didn’t really have any time for that. His people were waiting outside for him to get through these blockades. Instead, it would have been better to get something that he could analyze later.

‘Luckily whoever made this place, liked gaming rigs…’

Everything that was here looked like a replica gaming PC from his time. It had purple lights going through the water-cooled fluid part. Even now as the whole thing was working the PC case underneath was glowing through the transparent screen. No dust seemed to have built up either so he could see everything vividly.

‘I don’t recall the GPU model, it looks quite large…’

Zhang Dong could recall the two main GPU companies from his old world but none of them seemed to have a model like this one. From the outside, it looked very similar but wasn’t quite there. Perhaps whoever made this place decided to customize it to their own liking or they came from a different earth than he did.

‘For all I know, the earth I came from could be a recreation too…’

He didn’t really want to think about the godly being working in the background but the closer he got to defeating all Emperors the closer he felt the last confrontation was approaching. His current white seed was slowly opening up and he could feel himself growing stronger by the day. After absorbing the Dao of the Cerulean Empress he could see himself progressing even further and perhaps breaking through to the next level.

‘Bob, what will happen if I take this with me…’

‘Unable to come to a conclusion, need more data.’

‘So you fail me now…Hm…’

He stared at the RGB lights that started turning on and illuminating this dark room. On one end was the entrance he came through and on the other another door through which he would arrive in the next area. If he took this PC there would possibly be an adverse reaction.

‘I’ll just take the whole room with me…’

After nodding at himself he moved over to the exit door. After opening it he could see the next area through it. The door was seemingly hovering in the air above a large castle-like structure. There was also the inside of the bubbly barrier that he could see from here. If he jumped through the door it would probably close behind him along with this room and the PC in it. Thus he needed to grab everything he needed while the door was still open.

Soon he pulled the replica of the medallion out while quickly working on the walls of the room. Forcing everything out and placing it into the medallion wasn’t easy and he needed to do it in one fell swoop. As he was working the whole tower part of the trial area began to collapse and along with it came all the monsters that were trapped inside.

‘Well, sorry about that guys…’

All of the room along with all the constructs in it made their way into his medallion. Just as he expected the moment they were in there the door started to vanish. Luckily he was already prepared to step through it with most of the room making its way into his possession.

At almost the same time he started hearing a strange rumbling. In the distance, a large sinkhole had formed and started to collapse. From within he could hear the roars of strange beasts that were quickly drowned out by the sounds of destruction. The whole thing was collapsing onto itself, it was as if a black hole had formed inside to swallow all of it in one quick gulp.

‘I really hope no one heard that…’

He was floating right up in the air with light shining from all sides. There were no shadowy spots that he could disappear to. His position had become exposed and he was not alone here, from the distance he could feel something coming and it was not a weak opponent.

Chapter 643

‘At least I tried…’

Zhang Dong looked down at a large army of flying fishmen coming his way. After he took out a large portion of a hidden room and appeared here his location became known. His Dao of Darkness couldn’t help him this time around as there were no shadows to sink into. He had appeared up in the sky and right in front of the enemy base. Instantly when he came out the people living here became aware of his existence and were coming his way.

‘There are a lot of them, I need to find a way to open up this damn bubble, I can’t even teleport out back to the golden palace…’

The person that made this place really didn’t like the teleportation function. Now that it was gone Zhang Dong realized how much he was reliant on this feature. There was a possibility of getting out through similar means but he would first need to create the correct gate through which he could leave or a formation. Without it, there was no way of getting back to his people or the area he previously was in. After ripping out the secret room the entire section he was in vanished from his map. It was as if the whole place didn’t exist in the first place.

It was more of the clones coming his way. There were quite a few at the general level. With this many around, even Zhang Dong didn’t feel confident in his victory. Together with the men holding tridents also came a swarm of fish monsters. There were many nascent soul-level beings here that numbered in the thousands. They continued to pour out of the castle and it didn’t seem like there was an end to them.

‘I don’t see any way of opening this bubble from this side, the mechanism must be inside of their main base…’

To his dismay, there was no way for him to avoid this battle or get back to his people. He was in for the fight of his life and the Empress he was supposed to face off against didn’t even show herself yet. He was hoping to save his battle armor for the last battle but as it stood now he needed all the help he could get against the swarm of lackeys.

“You guys probably don’t want to talk this over, right?”

He called out to the underwater people that came to greet him. In his mind, there was no way for them to communicate after all of the events that transpired before. His armies had killed massive numbers of the cloned soldiers and they had been battling against each other for months now. However, for some reason when the large group arrived something happened. Before he could take a fighting stance and start blasting, they called out to him.

“The Empress is expecting you, please come with us.”

“She is expecting me? The Empress?”

“Yes!”

Instead of attacking him, they moved to the sides. A tunnel surrounded by various creatures was formed from up in the air and stretched all the way out to the faraway palace. Apparently, their leader knew that he was already coming their way. Perhaps she had a way of observing his movements as he was trying to come in through the back door.

‘Could it be possible for there to be peace between our two factions?’

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what was going on but he couldn’t know if this was just a trap. He had already met one of the Empire sides that weren’t totally his enemies like Argus and his people. Perhaps it was possible for this Cerulean Empress of theirs to be the same. Perhaps some kind of treaty could be reached.

‘Maybe if I just offer them the sea they will leave us be?’

These people were beings that needed some water to survive. The cultivators above ground didn’t really need the great sea for anything much. They could survive without really fishing outside and there were also many sea-sized lakes on the main ground that could be used instead. An agreement could be reached for the hundred or so years this empire was there. They would keep away from the water and the Cerulean Empress would not push into the land.

‘That is if it's not a trap, it could be possible that she just wants to lure me into some type of trapping formation but, I might have a chance to disable the bubble if I get inside the palace.’

The whole thing looked fishy but not like he could decline. They were opening up the gates before him and he felt confident in his own abilities. Thankfully most people in this world tended to underestimate his abilities. As long as he was careful he didn’t see himself getting defeated.

‘Just to be safe I’ll leave an escape route ready…’

While he didn’t want to depend on his teleportation feature too much, it was still working when inside this large bubble. Even if he couldn’t get outside of it to his people he could still set up a place to escape if something inside of that palace happened to him. After putting the save spot into his faction window he nodded at the person that came to pick him up.

“Fine then, I’ll meet your Empress then.”

“Please come this way, the Empress wishes to see you now and she doesn’t like to be kept waiting.”

Soon he was flying through the tunnel of monsters. A thin layer of golden energy was surrounding his body and ready to explode. It wouldn’t be strange if these monsters decided to just push themselves onto his body. They were acting strange though, just standing there without even blinking. At least for the ones that had eyes, some of them were just fish with no eyelids.

‘These beings… they aren’t quite there…’
Zhang Dong realized something, there was something off about these beings. There was something affecting their movements, something was jolting their souls into acting a certain way. Previously the army of clones didn’t seem to have this attribute to them but the creatures here did. Something strong was pulling at their strings and the closer to the palace that he got, the more this feeling he received.

‘I guess it must be their Empress.’

There was nothing really known about this Cerulean Empress to him. The cloned soldiers weren’t good at describing their leader as they had never actually seen her before. There was also no mention of the huge angler fish that had swallowed them whole.

‘If it was just soul arts then I might be able to break her hold on them but there seems to be something more there…’

His expertise in souls was one of the greatest in this world. Normally if someone was controlled by some demonic art it would be possible to affect the person in some type of fashion. If the armies here were getting controlled through some corup technique then breaking it would have been his priority. Even though he could feel a connection through the soul there was something else binding this control.

‘Could it be… bloodline arts? Could these people really have all come from her?’

After arriving at the palace gates he somewhat grasped the situation. There were connections through blood that existed in this world. Ancestors of immense power could sometimes affect their descendants through their bloodline. Usually, this type of control died after the ancient being of power died out but what if such an ancestor managed to survive? In theory, the control would never be removed and the descendants would be forced to comply.

‘But this many? Or could this be why they are cloned… If they remade members from the first or second generation it’s feasible to retain the bloodline purity and keep control.’

With each generation, some of the bloodlines were always muddled. With time only a few individuals would retain those ancient abilities that made their ancestors famous and powerful. By cloning people with high amounts of purity in their blood the ancestor in question could retain absolute control through generations. The question was if this was the case here or if there was something more to it.

This was not good news for him. Perhaps he would be able to break control over these clones if they were bound to the Empress’ soul. It would be impossible for him to go around the bloodline ability which he could not affect with any Dao. The only way to counter this ability would be through an individual of the same line that was at a similar level to the ancestor.

After that, there was a third way if a person had a similar bloodline to the ancestors. It was sometimes possible to draw in people from another bloodline if they accepted the new one as their own. However, in this case, this wouldn’t be possible. He was a human cultivator and these were some types of underwater beings. There were no close relations with their bloodlines and this would be impossible.

‘So this is the place? I don’t see anything that could turn off the bubble yet but there must be something inside, the connection is there.’

While he could not see anything that was powering the defensive formation there was a way for him to sense where the power source was coming from. Large defensive shields like the one this place had needed a lot of power. Even if he couldn’t break the array or treasure that was generating it as long as he found the power source, it would be enough. Going by the spirit energy of this place, it was somewhere in here and these clone soldiers were actually guiding him to that spot.

‘There are a lot of mermaids in here… not many men though.’

One thing that he spotted was the lack of any male mermaids in this place. The soldiers that were guiding him looked more like regular human men or were like a mix between a fish and a person. All of the females of this species seemed to only consist of one type, the mermaids that were peeking out from the corners and looking at him.

‘Wang Long would have probably liked this place a lot… that is if the Empress looks anywhere as beautiful as these mermaids.’

Finally, he came up to a huge gate made out of sea coral. It started to slowly open and he was welcomed with a nice fragrance along with the music.

“So you are the one that harmed my children…”

From within a voice that belonged to a beauty was heard. His eyes quickly darted toward the location it was coming from. There he finally saw his new enemy that finally revealed himself to him, the Cerulean Empress.

Chapter 644

‘So that’s the Empress? She does look Empress-like but… something feels strange about her…’

Zhang Dong arrived at the throne room. It was a luxurious-looking place with many many smaller mermaids gathered on the side. The fish ladies were smiling and laughing without a care in the world as if they were meeting with a friend instead of someone that could turn them to minced meat with a snap of his finger.

The scene was truly strange and perhaps one of the reasons was the tune that was playing. This enchanting music was similar to the one he encountered when he rescued Zhang Jin from the mermaids. It was a magnified version of it and would probably have enticed anyone else than him by this point. Along with the music, there was also a sweet smell that he instantly blocked out from entering his body. It was clear to him that this Empress here was some type of enchantress that was trying to brainwash him.

Her looks were astonishing and quite exotic. Her form was larger than that of the other mermaids and it was hard to see if she was an actual one. Her lower body was covered by some type of gown with only her upper body showing. This part was quite voluptuous and the lower part of her face was covered by a veil. She looked like some type of exotic dancer with that light pink dress she was wearing. Her belly button was exposed and so were her shoulders along with quite a bit of those breasts that jolted with vigor each time her body moved.

She was just sitting there while facing forward. Her elbows were forward and her fingers were in between each other. Her chin was resting on the back of her palms as she watched him enter. Those enhancing eyes that seemed to belong to an otherworldly succubus continued to be glued to his form. For some reason, it felt as if he was getting undressed by this person while the people on the side remained silent.

“Not bad, haven’t had such a great specimen in a while, you shall do quite nicely…”

“A specimen? I’m not sure if I understand.”

“Hoh? You seemed unaffected by my beauty. This makes things even more interesting, I might have rated you too low.”

Zhang Dong could feel her voice trying to penetrate through his defenses. It seemed this person was in control of some type of Charming Technique. The only reason that he was able to resist was thanks to his new cultivation method and his strong soul. Even when his body and brain were being affected by this strange technique, as long as his soul wasn’t penetrated through he would be able to retain his faculties.

‘If Qiang or Gramps were here they would probably already be licking this woman’s feet… that is if she has any, to begin with…’

The mysterious lower body was the least of his problems as it was clear that this person was constantly trying to control his mind. If they were up in the empire something like this would be considered extremely rude. Reacting with anger wouldn’t be strange as she was performing something similar to demonic arts.

However, before everything turned bloody he had to attempt a more pacifistic approach. The person was apparently the leader of these people and could end all of this animosity between their two parties. While killing her and absorbing the Daos she came equipped with was on his agenda, he would abandon the notions if peace was possible. Even without absorbing more Daos he felt that he would eventually break through and this fact had become more apparent after defeating his last foe where he earned multiple ones.

“It does seem so… Would you please stop that? It won’t work on someone like me, I’m also a happily married man with children of my own.”

“...You refuse to accept my offering of love?”

“Offering of love? You have a strange way of defining coercion.”

“He dares talk to the Empress this shamelessly as a male?”

“How could this be possible, is the Empress allowing him to talk?”

The other mermaids that were around here were shocked for some reason and so was their leader. From their whispers, he deducted that men didn’t really have a high standing here. Even now none of the males in the room dared to speak out, they were just acting like guards while the mermaids continued to speak. Perhaps this was the first time they even saw a man continue to speak without being allowed to. This was perhaps a matriarchal society where a man like him had no say in anything.

“You’re an interesting one, just wandering into my palace while destroying my toys, why should I listen to anything that you say?”

“By toys do you mean them?”

Zhang Dong pointed towards the clones of the generals that were all gathered here. The strongest of them were all here together and after the little conversation with their Leader, they were standing up at attention. In their hands, they had tridents of various shapes and sizes. Their power was tremendous and if all of them attacked at once even he wouldn’t get off scot-free.

‘Hey Bob, are you done with the analysis, I’m not sure how much time I have here.”

‘Calculating, 76% done…”

He did not just come here to have a talk. The bubble that blocked his people from entering here could still be broken. If he could just figure out what was powering this defensive formation and turn it off, then he would have a winning chance. If not then facing all of these people along with their leader would be difficult. Her true power level was unknown to him but considering that she was one of the Emperors, her strength had to be great.
“Those? No, I wouldn’t call those objects my toys… Nevertheless, why did you come here human? What is your desire?”

“My desire? I guess there is one.”

It was even worse than he anticipated, the Empress didn’t even consider these clone soldiers to be people. This meant that he would probably have a hard time talking about the current war effort. Normally a leader had to at least watch for their troop's approval rating or how much they were feared. But even fear had its limits and troops would abandon the fight if it was too inconvenient and the leader fell.

“I wish for you to halt your advances into the empire.”

“My advances?”

“Yes, the losses on our sides will just continue to pile up and you have also lost a lot of troops.”

“Troops?”

The woman looked bored and as if she didn’t understand where he was going with it. Just like he anticipated it was hard to work with a person that didn’t consider their army living beings. To her the masses of soldiers and sea creatures that were sent out to the empire were nothing. She probably considered them to just be cold weapons with no emotions that would never hold her responsible for their deaths and were loyal to a fault.

“Y-yes, I’m sure you wouldn’t want to waste your resources for a war that won’t amount to anything?”

“You want me to stop? It amounted to you coming here… can’t you see it? I’ve already won by you coming here~”

“Huh?”

A bomb was dropped during the conversation that he didn’t fully understand. What was the meaning behind those words and why was she looking at him like a juicy piece of meat?

“Yes my dear, all that I wanted was to find a toy like you. The next generation will be even stronger than the previous one, it will take some time to foster them…”

“Hello?”

“I can’t wait to see how well the first batch will come out… they will probably not be as ugly as this one…”

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what was going on but the woman started talking to herself as if he wasn’t there. For some reason, he was the prize and she started talking about another generation. Then suddenly it started dawning on him, this strange woman wanted to foster a new generation of clones and probably use his genes as some type of base.

While she was talking he took a good glance at all the clones and mermaids in here. While he wasn’t that great at interpreting bloodlines these people were eerily similar to each other. The same could be said for the mermaids. While at first glance they looked different it was due to the change of fashion, makeup, and hair styling. They had the same face, the same voice, and very similar body movements to their queen. It was as if all the mermaids were clones of the bigger one here.

‘Could this be why she feels so old… maybe that’s why her soul feels strange…’

There were demonic arts that allowed people to switch bodies but they were quite risky. First of all, a soul needed a vessel that fit it perfectly or during the transfer some of the energy would be lost. A person that attempted such an art would soon find themselves forgetting things and losing their mind. That’s why demonic cultivators that performed these arts just turned into soul-sucking monsters. These creatures were trying to get back the part of the soul that they lost but this was an impossible task.

‘But what if the body could be remade to be an exact copy of the original one… then it could be possible…’

This was his current theory. All the mermaids here were just clones of the Empress and perhaps if she started getting older she just switched to a new and younger body. There were quite a few of these fishy women here which could have meant a few things. Either the Empress needed to switch quite often or the procedure had a high failure rate. Perhaps it only succeeded once in a hundred or a thousand tries.

‘I don’t think I can reason with a person like this… Bob, are you done?’

‘Sending data to the user, updating the map with the coordinates.’

‘Nice.’

Zhang Dong looked at his minimap that now showed him the places that were most likely to have the off switch that he was looking for. It was lucky that this woman didn’t see him as much of a threat and decided to tell him her glorious plan of stealing his juices for her plans. However, this didn’t mean that it would be easy to bust his way into the forbidden areas of this castle.

‘Here goes nothing then…’

Chapter 645

“Hey what are you doing…”

“Oh… Don’t mind me, I’m just looking for the toilet…”

“The toilet?”

“Yeah…”

“...”

Zhang Dong showed a bright smile to the large mermaid in the throne room while moving to the side. She had been busy talking to herself and apparently while she was in that state the soldiers gathered here remained in a passive state. There was certainly something ingrained in the clone programming that made them freeze whenever their Empress was talking. This fact was used by him to begin his plan of sneaking away.

“Well then… I’ll be right back!”

“What!?”

He quickly shifted into his shadowy form that allowed him to pass through so many troublesome trials. While in it he could traverse through this room while evading the guards that were unable to pinpoint his position. This of course didn’t sit well with their leader that started thrashing about.

“What are you waiting for, CATCH HIM AND BRING HIM TO ME!”

“Yes, Empress!”

The group of mermaids that were in this room scattered to the side. They didn’t seem to have been made for combat. Their bodies seemed to be close to the levels of core formation but it didn’t seem that they had been tonight much. Perhaps their mother that had created them to act as vessels wanted to keep their bodies without any blemishes like scars. Instead, the cloned warriors with tridents tossed themselves his way as he sunk into the ground.

‘Are you sure you can’t limit it to the right one, Bob?’

‘Requires more data’

‘Any way to input more data? I’m not sure what we are looking for Bob.’

‘User must get closer to one of the locations to gather more data.’

‘I see…’

Bob gave him more than ten locations in this place that could have the power source for the grand formation outside. If he wanted to have a fighting chance he needed to let his people inside. Teleporting wasn’t an option and it also didn’t seem that this Empress wanted to talk. She had mumbled some obscenities while alluding to wanting his child making juices.

Apparently, she wanted to enhance her cloned troops from his DNA. For all he knew these men here had been cloned from some other system holder. There was a possibility that this was the way of going around this disaster but he was not Zhang Jin, his loyalties lay with his wife. Until he had exhausted all his options it was better to not go with her.

‘What if she sticks me into a test tube or starts draining my blood to make more clones? Yeah, not worth the hassle at all.’

The whole glorious palace which was even larger than his flying fortress was in an uproar. All of the soldiers that were stationed here were out looking for him. They had seen him dive into the shadows which had been a mistake. While they were cloned soldiers they did have reasoning, figuring out that they needed to turn on the lights to remove the shadowy spots was one of the first things that they decided to do.

‘Shit, they are turning on the lights everywhere…’

The biggest weakness of this traversing technique was light and soon enough there weren’t that many places for him to hide. This area that he arrived in was one of the rooms that contained a strange spiritual energy signature. It was a copy of the large kitchen he saved his sect members from and all the energy was radiating from the food that was gathered here.

“There he is, stop him!”

“I didn’t think that you’d be cannibals too, have some fish!”

One of the generals stormed into the area he was occupying. Just as he pushed through the door a large amount of fish flew his way. They were all quickly deflected by his weapon but while he was busy with the food fight, Zhang Dong began his escape. Sinking below the door frame where there was some shade was still possible but when he came outside there was too much light to keep his formless form.

‘Okay Bob, do your work, that was one of the spots you pointed out…’

When outside he witnessed a group of fishy people ruining his way. They were quick to toss themselves at him without seemingly caring for their wellbeing. Without much trouble, Zhang Dong sent them flying to the sides. The difference in power was substantial but they persisted. Even when their bones were shattered and blood was coming out of their orifices they kept crawling his way.

“Are you zombies or something?”

Bob removed two locations from his map while he continued running. Behind him, a conga line of angry fish people was quickly forming. Even when he turned around and blasted them with some spirit energy balls, they just ignored them. It was clear that they were forced to carry out the order that their leader gave them. The brainwashing was strong and even seeing some of their allies getting decapitated didn’t stop them for even one second.

After the kitchen, he punched his way through a closed door. Inside he spotted a lot of the same type of weapons. On the left there were tridents and on the right, there were also more tridents. There was no time to process why these people liked to use this type of weapon as he needed to continue running.

‘Another room down… there aren’t that many more left… I can do it!’

He pumped himself up while dodging all the attacks and groups of monster fishmen that were tossing themselves in his direction. Following the weapon chamber he arrived at one that was filled with precious metals and crystals. It was a large haul the size of a hill covered in spirit stones. If this was any other time then he would have just sucked them into his spatial ring yet with so many people behind him, even a second could cause his mission to fail.

‘Why is it always the last one…’

Just like he expected it was the deepest location on the map that he was given by Bob. All those treasures were radiating a lot of energy but this was still not the one that he was looking for. After blasting his way through a nearby wall he slid into a giant corridor with a gate at the end.

“That must be it!”

He shouted while propelling himself at the wall with his foot aimed at the large gate. His body was surrounded by lightning and the radiant energy made even the powerful masters behind him tremble. Yet even when his foot connected with the large door it didn’t open. His spiritual energy seemed to have been absorbed right as his attack connected. Arcs of golden lightning were forced to the sides and then quickly absorbed by the metal that this whole corridor and gate were made from.

“You fool, your powers won’t work here!”

His expectations weren’t met as he was still in the corridor and his path was being blocked. This place was composed of some strange materials that were able to absorb large amounts of spiritual energy. Yet even though the enemies were coming from behind he didn’t stop staring at his destination. Even though all of his energies were dispersed, there still was some damage on the spot that he hit.

“They won’t? Are you sure about that?”

After shouting at the man that was approaching from behind with some other cloned soldiers he pushed forward. His upper body became a blur as a massive barrage of punches connected with the metallic gate. The men that were chasing after him stopped for a moment as they couldn’t believe that he was producing holes in the high-quality material, this was not something that should have been a possibility.
Zhang Dong’s spiritual energy was great and all of his attacks could only be blocked by a handful of people in this world. Qi was perhaps his forte when it came to fighting but it was not his only weapon. His body had long since left the realms of humans, he was like a person made from metal and his strength was humongous. If his spiritual energy was absorbed by the materials here he just needed to change his approach. The indention that he left behind by his first attack was proof that he could break through with just his body alone. There was no need for fancy techniques or abilities, his fists were enough.

“I’ll be going through first, see ya!”

Even though he was punching like crazy, only a small hole was produced. This however was more than enough for him to get through. His enemies didn’t think that he could get through this barricade so they didn’t fully illuminate the room inside. Thanks to this he was able to slip into the shadows that were produced and get himself inside.

“So this is it?”

‘Large energy signature detected.’

Bob confirmed that they had found the source of power that lay right in the middle of this chamber. It was a mostly dark room with some light shindig at a lone dais. Right in the middle there was a floating object that was encased in a soap bubble. At first glance, it looked like a pink sea shell but it was not that simple. It contained a massive amount of water Qi that was on par or even superior to the engine from his flying fortress.

‘This is it!’

He could hear the fish soldiers pounding on the door. After he dent a hole into it, the opening mechanism was also destroyed, and squeezing through the small hole was not an easy task. This was the end of his mission, after grabbing the item inside of the soap bubble the outside soap bubble would pop. Zhang Dong nodded and sprinted forward with his eyes glued to the
prize.

“Hah, did you really think that I’d fall for a simple trap like this?”

Yet before his hand grasped for this treasure he pointed in another direction. A beam of light escaped from his fingers that sent his holy lightning at the being hidden in the shadows. During the charge he had realized that this was all a setup, if he grasped the treasure there it would be encased in a bubble.

“You figured it out? My my, you might actually be worthy of being my mate~”

The voice belonged to the Cerulean Empress and it echoed throughout the entire chamber. Yet even with his eyes being able to see through the darkness, he could not see the woman’s form, instead, there was something else.

“Why does it always have to be tentacles..”

Chapter 646

There he was, looking at a bunch of squiggly tendrils coming his way. Without much thought he instantly started dodging and throwing his holy energies around. To his surprise, the slimy appendages didn’t burn to cinders as they were supposed to. Instead of being demonic in nature as he expected them to be, they were filled with water energy.

‘So it’s a giant squid and not a demonic beast?’

“My my, you are a feisty one but how long can you last?”

“Could you stop talking like that? if my wife overhears she will think that I’m doing something bad.”

‘Where is that voice coming from, I don’t see her upper body.’

The Cerulean Empress’ voice echoed through this chamber. It was not coming from any particular direction which was confusing to his senses. While the tentacles thrashed about this room the voice continued to taunt him as if it was coming from the appendages themselves. Even after pulling out his sword and cutting a few, they quickly grew back while producing many thinner tendrils.

‘I need to find the core or main body, this thing is clearly just a part of this Empress… maybe this is part of her body?’

His new opponent had been hiding half of her body behind some carefully placed materials. Perhaps this was the form that was hiding under, a mass of ugly-looking tentacles. When he was cutting into them, he realized that they had a resemblance to the monster he met in the other pocket dimension. In contrast to that monster, this one didn’t seem to have any cores for him to pierce through.

‘Maybe the core is inside the humanoid part… Could these stretch through the entire palace?’

He wasn’t fighting something that he could defeat here and at this critical juncture, his focus needed to be on something else. Even though the tentacles were here to entrap him inside this chamber, this didn’t mean that there was no way out. The power source for the outside bubbly was still here and he just needed to get to it.

This item in question had been entangled by a large mass of squiggly tentacles. They needed all to go along with it and thus as time was running out, he raised his Qi to the zenith. His body started glowing with various lights as he tried to combine all the higher Daos that he knew. Gravitational force, Heavenly Lighting, Holy Energy, Wind Energy, and also Darkness were all combined to blast everything.

The soldiers that were chasing him were greeted by a massive explosion almost immediately after opening the gate. For a moment they could see Zhang Dong’s body blur from the spot to fly at a mass of tendrils. This was followed by a massive tremor before everything went white.

“That wasn’t the smartest move… but I got it somehow.”

Zhang Dong with part of his robe missing was hovering up in the air outside of the castle. In his right hand, he was holding a pink shell. He had plunged himself into the gross appendages and managed to grab this treasure during the explosion of spiritual energy. Instantly after grabbing it he utilized his teleportation escape to get to the save point he left outside. Now he was floating outside while looking at the castle before him and some sea creatures coming his way.

“HOW DARE YOU STEAL FROM ME!”

The voice of the Cerulean Empress echoed throughout the inside of this bubble as she had realized that her treasure was stolen. The shell that he was holding in his hand was more robust than he expected so he needed to act fast. Both of his hands pushed on it from both sides while increasing the gravity around it. Together with this Dao, he was able to shatter this power source and finally, the bubble popped.

“United Element Sect, your Patriarch orders you to attack!”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

Right on cue, a large group of cultivators started charging forward. A few large ships which were the size of the Argonaut moved in first and were followed by various large attacking formations. Some looked like golden serpents while others looked like blue turtles and were primed for defense.

A huge fortress that seemingly was made from pure gold was right behind them. It was floating in the air and already had its cannons pointing at the swarm of creatures coming Zhang Dong’s way. The way was finally clear for his sect and it was time for the final battle to commence.

“You took your time… and what’s with that smell.”

“Don’t ask…”

Zhang Liena appeared next to her husband that was covered in bodily juices from the tentacles. While teleporting some of them had gotten stuck to his body and even his hair. Luckily now that they were away from the main body they were quite easy to burn away. Within a few moments, he managed to cleanse the smell away and also change into something more battle ready.

His body started glowing like a radiant star as his transformation took place. Now that the last boss had revealed itself there was no need to hold his trump card. Just like Liena and Huo Qiang, he was in possession of his own armor set. Liena’s was green while Qiang’s had a crimson tint to it. Zhang Dong on the other hand had his two staple colors, white and gold.

The explosion of energy could be even felt by these mindless cloned soldiers. Their charge forward was interrupted by the appearance of an armored man. While the shiny white parts took up most of the design the gold outlines popped out a bit more thanks to it. For a moment a sect of shiny white wings appeared behind him and gave him the appearance of an archangel. A fitting appearance as soon after a large group of angelic puppets poured out of the golden fortress.

While his forces didn’t have large numbers they made it up with quality. The clash started and all hell broke loose. The cloned forces seemed to not care about their well-being as they tossed themselves into the lines of the Qi-powered attacks. It was as if they had gone berserk after their leader had become enraged. It was the same with the generals that were now swinging those tridents around with no care for their allies.

Usually, they had some type of personality and were even able to speak. The battles his people had with them a month ago were still vividly remembered by them. Now on the other hand every one of the clones was like a rabid beast. They had no care for their well-being and were clearly running on instinct alone. While a berserk rage increased their ferociousness and attacking power it was also easy to read.

The sect members here had gone through many battles now. They were quickly able to adapt to this type of blind charge and took their time in luring the crazed clones into a disadvantaged position. After dancing around them when the time was right, many techniques filled the sky to deliver devastating blows that even they couldn’t resist.

‘They seem to be doing fine, I’m probably not needed here but the last Boss isn’t showing herself or she might not be able to…’

The scene that was playing out before his eyes was favorable to him but this made him restless. Whenever things seemed too easy, there was something that always went wrong. The Empress also wasn’t showing herself; instead, he could see some of those tentacles wiggling around in the palace. Something was happening there and he didn’t like it.

“Are they getting bigger?”

“Watch out, something is coming.”

Zhang Dong called out to his two allies and Qiang instantly responded while appearing inside his armor.

“Let it come then!”

“I don’t usually agree with this fool but this time he is right, we shall face this enemy together.”

Zhang Dong nodded at his wife and friend while smiling. Normally he would face this threat alone and probably get himself injured in the process. After years of fighting, he was not alone anymore. Many sect brothers and sisters were fighting together with him. Even if they weren’t as powerful as he was, they still all found ways of helping out in times like this.

When glancing to the side he could see all of them giving their all to push back the maddened clones and sea monsters. Even without the three main elders, they would be fine or at least buy them enough time until they got rid of the main enemy. This was the Empress or whatever this mass of tentacles was before them. At this point in time, they were slowly lifting the entire large palace into the air.

“So this is our target? I don’t like it… why does it have all those squiggly things… Disgusting.”

Liena frowned as she saw the tendrils squirming around. They were attached to thicker black tentacles that wrapped around each other to form something that looked like flesh. It was forming into something strange, a monster with a long fishtail similar to a mermaid but with many smaller centipede-like legs on the sides.

“This form…”

Even Qiang was confused about the look the Empress took. She was composed of black tentacles with a body bigger than the dragon they met in the lava region. The backside was shaped like a very long insect while the top part was more similar to a sea monster. The mouth even had something similar to teeth but they were quite black and made of some hardened tentacles instead.

“Be careful, this monster isn’t the real Empress, her true body is still somewhere inside of that castle.”

“So someone needs to get in there to get to the beast’s core…”

Zhang Liena looked at the palace that the monster was now wearing like some type of breastplate. It was clear to Zhang Dong that his wife would probably not want to get anywhere near those squiggly tentacles.

“I’ll do it, both of you just keep the monster busy while I get to the real body.”

“Sounds good to me!”

They all nodded at each other and finally the last battle was upon them. Perhaps after this was over, he could finally relax and focus on more important things like figuring out if the Azure Emperor was his enemy or ally…

Chapter 647

A massive inferno rained down from the skies. Cyclones made up of flaming energy raged through the entire battlefield as two cultivators worked together. Zhang Liena was on one side and Huo Qiang was on the other. Both had managed to toss their differences aside to open a path for Zhang Dong.

The monster they were focusing on was really tremendous and composed mostly of water. This would leave Huo Qiang weakened by the extensive Dao of water swirling around. Only with Liena’s help who was able to fan the flames to the next level were the two able to compete with the monster’s defenses.

Those tentacles started crumbling and had the water trapped inside to evaporate. While Water was the weakness of fire it went both ways. With a high enough temperature, all water would evaporate and be unable to reform back into its old shape. This immense heat was affecting the monster’s regenerative capabilities as the withered tendrils were not being replaced by new ones.

This was all done to give him some time and open up the path. The monster’s size and tree trunk-sized tentacles had been wrapped around each other to form something resembling muscle fibers. These fibers were quite hard and would be almost impossible to break through. Now with the heat turned up Zhang Dong could attempt his plan of entering this creature’s body.

There was no reason to fight this outer shell, it was obvious to them all that this was nothing more than a distraction. The more time they spent fighting the outside of this monster the more energy they would just waste. It more than likely had a lot more Qi to power itself that it was siphoning from somewhere inside that tentacle-covered castle. The fastest way to end this would be by Zhang Dong facing the real Empress on the inside.

While it was perhaps possible to overpower this last boss from the outside with the help of his flying fortress, he didn’t want to prolong any of this. His current power level went above what the system should have been able to give to him. The seed inside of him had already absorbed multiple Daos which in his mind made him one of if not the strongest person in the world. He just needed to get in there to quickly finish all of this before any more of his sect members suffered critical injuries.

‘Keep it busy while I’m in there, I won’t take long.’

‘Take care and return to me.’

‘I will.’

Before shooting forward he sent one last message to his wife that was concentrating on the large centipede monster. Soon after he was shooting forward like an arrow drawn from a huge bow. His form was surrounded by swirling golden energy that was empowered by several others.

The creature before him reacted to the attack by defending itself with its many tentacles. The huge body was also surrounded by a strange dark blue haze of water energy. Luckily he was not alone as another man in flashy azure armor appeared to create a better path for him.

Zhang Zhi had also been boosted by his faction system and was in the possession of some powerful treasures. One of them was similar armor to those Huo Qiang and Zhang Liena were wearing. Coupled with a blade that could slice through almost anything he quickly let his attack fly.

A water dragon was formed from the piercing strike. It flew forwards to push the large amounts of tentacles and tendrils that were coming its way. Before it dispersed it even managed to create a small opening in the watery barrier the creature produced. This helped him tremendously as when he arrived he was already drilling into those huge muscle fibers with no resistance.

While he was surrounded by a lot of energy it began to slowly chip away the further he got inside the monster. This thing was really sturdy and even with the help from the heat on the outside he could feel the monster quickly regenerating this wound. If he didn’t make it inside in one go then he would be trapped inside by these tentacle parts.

‘Bob, are you sure there is an open space where I’m going for?’

‘Affirmative.’

Zhang Dong didn’t choose a random location to attack. Bob had previously scanned the palace for energy signatures. This allowed him to have a schematic of the entire place inside of his system. Then he just needed to let his Ai scan the whole creature to show him parts of the castle that weren’t covered in tentacles.

Normally the Empress should have covered her real body or the core in a mass of tentacles that would render her unkillable. Yet for some reason, there was a section of new tunnels inside of the castle the monster was now wearing. If he saw this as another game map created by a higher being then this made sense. He was probably supposed to find an entrance and go through it to find the weak point. The world was giving him a way to end it and there was no reason to refuse this help.

‘I might not make it… maybe I should have chosen a thinner area…’

This didn’t mean that he didn’t want to cheat the system slightly. There was one area that was quite thin and entering it wouldn't even need the help of his allies. Instead, he chose to attack a more robust section for the sole reason of hastening the whole process. That entrance point was directly at the start of the monster’s centipede section. He would need to travel through the whole length which was another maze of tunnels. Thus he chose to go right into the castle part that didn’t have that many of those passages.

‘Luckily it’s quite dark in here…’

His spiritual shield and swirling Qi that he covered himself was slowing down. The path that he created behind himself was already closed so there was no way of backtracking. Instead, he pointed out with his finger to generate one of his old attacks. A beam of concentrated light escaped creating a tiny opening to the chamber he wanted to arrive in.

‘I can see some light there.’

His body shifted into a shadowy form and quickly traveled through the finger-sized opening he created. The little passageway he created began to get smaller and smaller until it was the size of a needle right at the end. This was enough for him as his shadowy form didn’t need much space to squeeze through.

‘I made it… but where did I really make it in?’

His body changed into his armored form after he canceled his shadowy technique. The place he found himself looked like some sort of bed chamber that perhaps one of the mermaids had used before. The whole place was destroyed and some of the black tentacles had gone through the walls to trash everything. When looking at those pulsating things everywhere he put up his guard but just as he expected, there was no reaction.

‘It does seem like the walls will attack me at least…’

After taking this form the black tentacles shifted into something like muscles and had apparently lost their previous properties. They were now incapable of reacting to his presence and were nothing more than flesh that acted as a biological barrier. Even after giving them a few pokes with his finger he wasn’t getting any adverse reactions which meant that he could safely traverse through this place by himself.

‘Bob, search for the nearest route to this monster’s core or its true body.’

‘Scanning in progress…’

While going through this place he started looking around. There was actually some light on the side that was produced by some glowing pearls that replaced torches and candles. Most of this place was destroyed but some of the passages still remained. Now that he was walking through them he could examine some of them.

‘This looks like the picture of the Empress… and only her pictures…’

It was a bit strange to see her face is drawn and placed everywhere. It was as if she was the only real person living in this gigantic castle. The other people were just clones that she could control so perhaps she chose not to get them immortalized in the art here.

‘She might actually be some type of false immortal, there was mention of them inside some of the libraries.’

There was a distinction between a true immortal and a false immortal to the people living in this world. The former was someone that as the name stated, could live forever or at least had such a long lifespan that it felt like they lived for an eternity. The latter was someone that had to prolong their life through other means. If this woman had a way to insert her soul into cloned bodies without losing the essence in the process, then she would be in this category.

Zhang Dong didn’t really have the experience of living in this world for too long. More of his time was wasted in the other world as he had lost a whole five years in this one while not feeling the time pass him at all. Even though he had no experience with living that long he was sure that it would probably affect a person’s psyche.

‘Can’t live for hundreds of thousands of years and still be normal, it’s probably even worse if they have to continue passing into new clone shells… would the memories of the person she takes over mix with her own or would they be erased beforehand?’

He kind of knew how this process should work. After analyzing the cloning devices and some of his knowledge about souls he could bring a thesis to the forefront. The technique was probably flawed in a few spots which made this person believe that she was the only real being left alive. Perhaps these cloned soldiers were nothing more than life extenders in her eyes. Even when they actually grew up normally and had their own dreams it didn’t matter.

‘I wonder what will happen to them after their leader is dead… I guess I’ll find out soon enough…’

At first, he thought that making a deal with this creature would have been an option. After wandering through these tentacle-coveted halls his opinion had changed. It was better to let this false immortal fall before she ruined even more lives and the chamber that she was in had already been discovered.

‘So that’s where you are… it’s time to end this.’

Chapter 648

“She won’t just let me into the throne room without a fight huh?”

Zhang Dong commended while slicing open a strange creature made out of tentacles. One of them was dissolving into black goop after getting sliced in a hundred pieces by his blade. It wasn’t alone though as many more of its kind were quickly running in his direction.

They had a vaguely humanoid shape with tree-like characteristics. Their hands looked like long roots made of some type of black bark. On further examination, this was due to the previous tentacles hardening. This process must have taken place during the creation of the centipede monster's outer shell. These smaller monstrosities were something akin to an immune system response and he was being treated like a virus.

After finding a route to the last boss he started encountering these strange beings. They all were at the level of a weaker nascent soul master which made them not that much of an issue for him. They were more of a nuisance as he was slowly burning through some of his spiritual energy to get through.

There was also the problem of the path being lit exceptionally well. The Empress had clearly decided to counter his shadowy technique after he had started slipping past these monsters previously. All of them had strange glowing veins inside their bodies which made traversing these tunnels a lot harder. Thus he decided to take them out with melee attacks that conserved most of his spiritual energy.

“Are these supposed to be mobs before the last boss?”

Considering that he should have entered from another location to travel to this place, this wasn’t that troublesome. This place was made for one person to go through it and only thanks to all the experience he gained throughout years of training and battling was he able to move at a reasonable pace.

‘They don’t seem to be scaling to my level or I’ve just become too strong for this world…’

When beating up the various monsters and going through the tunnels he thought back to the encounter in the previous world. There when he showed off his nascent soul power that went above the limits of that location, the overseer appeared. It wouldn’t be strange if the same thing happened here, when he reached a new level of power his enemy would probably be there to snuff him out.

‘I need to be ready for that time, the only reason I defeated that other overseer was that he was limited to that world's upper limit.’

In this world of cultivators, the upper limit he was thinking about was much higher. The person he encountered was really powerful, much more than he was as he couldn’t tell. Then there was a problem with the whole time-stopping technique which he first needed to contend with. After all of this was over he needed to examine the special room that he ripped out of this pocket dimension. In there he hoped to find the secrets behind stopping time which would help him counter his next real foe.

‘This should be the place…’

His sword went through a few more monsters that quickly burst into smoke. Their bodies lacked the regenerative capabilities that the tentacles which made clearing waves of them out rather easy. Within fifteen minutes or so he arrived at a large broken gate. It looked like the same one that led into the Empress' Throne room. There was only one particular thing about it, a strange thick white mist was blocking him from peeking inside.

‘It isn’t toxic…This reminds me of one of those games…’

While holding his weapon he decided to traverse through the fog. It felt like he was walking through water and when he was on the other side he saw an area similar to the throne room the Empress had been in. The spot that she previously occupied was still there but now it was devoid of anyone, instead, there was an opening that he could probably go through.

‘Hm… I probably need to go in there but what’s with this fog, it became red and hard.’

The white mist that he went through had changed colors and became quite resistant to any impacts. Even his sword when he applied pressure wasn’t able to pierce through it. This whole place reminded him of certain video games that trapped the players in boss chambers. Unless the enemy within the place was defeated there would not by a way out.

‘A boss room huh? Well, as long as I defeat it, it should be fine.’

Zhang Dong moved forward while frowning. The moment he entered this place his teleportation function had been disabled. It was clear that this place was set up as a challenge for a system holder. Getting out of this place was only possible if he managed to survive which made him have even more questions about the person working in the shadows.

‘I’m not sure if they want the people that have these systems to survive or not…’

While the system would help him or anyone else survive through many hardships, it wasn’t perfect. It wouldn’t give anyone free points to spend or any lives either. When Wang Long died, that was it for him, there were no second chances. If this was a game, even if he lost then his life would not be ended and he would be able to try again. Here, on the other hand, the system was blocking his escape.

‘Could this person want to see me struggle? Would an easy victory not achieve the goal they were aiming for?’

Several theories were swirling around in his head but he needed to focus on the task at hand. The throne the woman was laying on was now empty and he could actually walk through it. It was clear that the Empress was several times larger than he was. She had previously been laying down on her belly here and the tunnel was three times his height.

On the sides, he could see many smaller tunnels leading in various directions. Previously he thought that the Empress possessed a fishtail like the other mermaids but now it was clear that she was more similar to the tentacle creature he encountered with his grandfather and Huo Qiang. All those openings were previously filled out by those black tentacles. They went all through the castle and probably connected to everything.

‘Maybe instead of taking out the barrier, I should have just attacked her when I had the chance.’

Considering that he had previously encountered the Cerulean Empress in this room, he had missed his chance. She was babbling on and not ready to take an attack if he actually went through with it. Back then he didn’t want to get attacked by her armies which made him go with the other option. Now that he was here, it was perhaps the wrong decision.

‘That should be the place… it’s huge.’

After walking for a minute he finally reached the end of the main tunnel. The first thing that he noticed was a strange thumping noise that was akin to a heartbeat. There was also a strange blue glow coming from that area that got brighter along with the slow heartbeat.

‘It’s a large tree?’

To his surprise, he came out in a large chamber that was the size of several football fields put together. Right in the middle was something that looked like a tree. It was not made from wood though, instead, it was some type of strange biomass created from those tentacles. They continued to pulsate like veins along to the heartbeat sound coming from within that huge tree.

“It’S yOu.”

The moment he ventured through the threshold he heard the Cerulean Empress’ voice echo through the entirety of it all. At first, he thought that it was coming from the huge pulsating tree but he was wrong. The entire place was covered in those tree-tentacles that were pulsating. It was as if the Empress was this whole room and all of her soul energy was infused into everything here.

“Yes it is me but it’s probably too late to talk this over, right?”

“yOu wIlL dIe aNd bEcOmE oNe wItH mE…”

“I guess not.”

The voices continued to echo from all directions but soon started to focus on one spot which was the huge tree in the middle. When glancing at it he discovered that a somewhat feminine figure was protruding from the bark that resembled the Cerulean Empress he saw before. Her upper torso was there under the dark blue bark and the heartbeat was coming from within her chest.

‘That must be her weak point, perhaps if I pierce it then she will die…’

There were a lot of glowing spots on the tree but the most intense one was coming from that humanoid part within the tree. This strange tree had its roots shoved into the ground and ceiling. His gaze fell on the upper part right after noticing a strange occurrence. From within the many branches that continued to glow something akin to a fruit was taking form. Within those cerulean fruits, he could see various shapes that were reaching the power level of nascent soul masters.

‘Are those cloned soldiers?’

Not much time had passed since he entered here but with the help of his Dao of the Souls, he could feel beings being formed inside of those fruits. They were not like the mindless drones that he was fighting outside. These were more similar to the cloned soldiers that his people were fighting outside. Their strength was also quite superior and around the level of the trident-wielding generals.

“bEcOmE oooNNNNeeee…”

Yet before they could form he decided to act. The Cerulean Empress that had become a tree started to mindlessly repeat the same sentence while creating those cloned beings. Before she would form them he would act. His finger pointed at the humanoid shape on the tree and soon after a beam of condensed light escaped. It traveled with immense speed and aimed at the heart that was beating inside this tree monster.

Suddenly just as this beam of light was about to collide with the glowing parts the humanoid shape twitched. She moved to the side to protect the weak point as the beam drilled inside of the bark. The strange bluish wood started to quickly regenerate while also encasing the weak point in more wood.

“yOu dArE?”

“It was worth a try.”

Zhang Dong shrugged while jumping forward. It wouldn’t be that easy to defeat this new enemy. If he couldn’t hit the weak point from range then he just needed to get in close to stab his blade into this tree woman’s heart. The battle that could potentially end this whole war had finally started and only one of them would be walking out of this alive.

Chapter 649

Zhang Dong dodged to the side while evading a sharp object from the left. Right after he was greeted by multiple projectiles that looked like seeds from the other side. His body twirled around and turned into multiple blurs as he attempted to confuse the thing that was shooting at him.

After arriving at this place he didn’t think that he would be fighting a sentient tree but here he was. This strange tree started producing fruits that quickly landed on the ground and turned into strange monstrosities. If this wasn’t enough it continued to fire off various projectiles from its many branches. They looked like seeds and when they collided with something they started to quickly germinate into small spider-like beings.

‘If I get hit by one of those things, would it burst from inside my body or something?’

The strange creatures reminded him of an old horror movie involving monsters and he was not willing to test out his theory. Luckily with his white and gold armor on, he wasn’t afraid of taking some hits. Also with his current skills, none of the attacks were able to really land on his body, instead, the area was becoming more and more covered in many strange-looking creatures.

“You know Empress, this isn’t really fair, I left my Bahamut at home and you're just summoning more and more of your own pets…”

“...bEcOmE oooNNNNeeee…”

“I see, great talk…”

He gave out a sigh as the Cerulean Empress had turned into a mindless monster. There was no way of reasoning with her and the longer he spent trying the more people would die outside. Even though his wife and Huo Qiang were turning up the heat they would probably not be able to defeat that monster outside. It was his fault for bringing his forces into an area that was meant for a solo battle and the faster he finished this, the sooner all of them would go home.

‘After I kill this thing, some way will probably become open but I can’t really feel a connection to the outside yet… Bob, did you finish your analysis?’

‘76% Done…77%...’

One of the reasons that he was taking his time was the nature of this battle. If this was supposed to be an encounter that he was to face alone, what would happen after he won? They were inside a strange fish that had multiple pocket dimensions inside of it. Would this creature collapse onto itself after the Cerulean Empress was defeated?

It wasn’t strange to believe that something in this main pocket dimension was controlling the angler fish outside. There was a possibility that the Empress was this control feature and after she was defeated the whole place would become unstable. If this was the case then he would need to get back to his people and quickly evacuate.

This is why he was dodging and weaving in all directions to evade the smaller cloned monsters here while gathering more data. The only problem with this approach was that there was no end to these beings. The more time was wasted the more of them appeared even if he killed one, two new ones appeared in its place.

After slicing one of the humanoid tree beings its body would turn into some type of gelatinous mass. It would then quickly seep into the ground and then roots that were spread everywhere. He followed the pathways this goop followed and it was clear that it ended up in those fruits once more. This coupled with the Empress tree also generated its own resources it only increased the mobs that he needed to clear out.

‘I need to start attacking it soon or I’ll be overrun… Hm, maybe I can use that to clear out a wave…’

When looking back he remembered the tunnel in which the original body of the Empress was previously in. This part of the chamber was not sealed out yet. Some of those large roots were quickly creeping to shut off but for now, he had enough space to wiggle through. Just as he expected the small army of creatures chased were quick to chase after him.

‘At least they aren’t too intelligent, their elements are wood and water…’

Zhang Dong smirked as he had just the Dao that would work on this combination. His holy element wouldn’t do much but it didn’t matter, lightning energy was enough to destroy these monsters. Thus after arriving at the end he gathered his heavenly lightning energy into both his arms and then quickly slammed his palms together to generate an orb of lightning.

This orb started increasing in the side before being shot forward. Its size encompassed the entire tunnel and the small space that it didn’t was covered in massive amounts of lightning energy. Crackling noises of this sphere of electricity echoed through the entire place and were combined with the strange wails of these monstrous creatures.

Electricity traveled through water quite well and began charring the monsters from the inside. There was enough juice in there to quickly evaporate all of the water that they were composed of and even the wooden parts. The sphere of concentrated lightning energy made short work of the creatures that were mindlessly pouring into the tunnel.

It was to the point of Zhang Dong needing to change his technique into a beam. The ball of light was beginning to get pushed back by the blue gelatinous mass on the other end. Even when the creatures were defeated they bound to each other to form some type of slime monster that just didn’t want to let up on the push. However, it just wasn’t powerful enough to fight against the energy beam that he was producing.

Everything was bathed in a deep blue hue of his lightning beam that shot forward. The roots that were blocking some of the path on the other side were blasted away. His attack traveled far and wide to finally collide with the Empress tree inside the initial chamber he escaped from. Right on cue he heard Bob’s monotonous voice call out to him to give him more info about his enemy.

‘Analisiz complete, sending data to the user.’

‘Took you long enough, let me see…So that’s how it is, good that I waited.’

A part of his theory was confirmed after he read through the log that Bob gave him. It would have not been the wisest move to just destroy this massive tree without making the right preparations. Now that he knew what would happen afterward he could safely make the calculations.

‘This is going to be close… I need to tell them not to spread out too much…’

Now that he knew about what would happen he contacted his wife to send forward his order. Luckily the system’s audio options were in working order and he was only being kept from teleporting outside of this boss room and not from talking.

“You wish for me to retreat to the Golden Dong Palace?”

“Yes, make sure that everyone is in range of the outer shields, I’m going to end this and we won’t have much time afterward, evacuate the people from the large ships into the palace if you have to.”

“Are you going to be fine?”

“Don’t worry, I won’t vanish this time.”

“I won’t you forgive if you don’t not this time…”

“I’ll keep that in mind…”

Zhang Dong cut off the feed to his wife and left the rest up to her. He was not planning on getting blown away into another world again. Perhaps he was lucky that only five years passed that time around. It was possible that if the same thing happened that he would arrive at an era where his kids were already grown-ups or had already died.

The sludge that was created after his attack wasn’t recovering as fast as before. During the large attack, he made sure to bathe his enemies in his heavenly lightning Qi. With the spiritual energy infused into this gelatinous mass, it was having a hard time reforming itself. This time could of course be used to launch a counterattack at the Empress inside.

He shot forward while surrounding his whole body with lightning energy. This torrent of blue light took the form of a dragon and flew forward while roaring. The puddle of goop that was trying to reform itself was electrocuted once more. The energy dragon that he surrounded himself with bulldozed through the roots that were trying to close off the entrance and when back inside the chamber it exploded.

The whole area was covered in his energy that spread in all directions. The Empress that had taken the form of a tree tried to fight against his might but there was a difference between their battle prowess. It was clear that his cultivation had become something slightly above the limitations of this world. He did not really need to find the weak point as an area of effect technique was enough to win this battle.

“wHaT aRe yOu? hhhhOOOwwww…”

To no surprise, his opponent could not figure out why they were losing. They were in their own territory where they should have been invincible. Yet with all this electrical Qi flying around everywhere, she just couldn’t regenerate all of the damage that was being produced.

‘I see you…’

Within the torrent of lightning energy that was electrifying everything his form emerged. He shot forward at a lone little vine that was trying to make its escape. This was the true core of the being that he was fighting. It looked like some type of hideous worm with tiny tendrils and a toothy mouth at the end.

It was some type of tiny parasite that probably attached itself to the clone mermaids in an attempt to prolong its life. The soul energy it was carrying around was easy to spot by someone like him. Without much thought behind it, his sword was utilized to sever this strange thing's life. Along with its true body, the soul was also dispersed in one quick move.

A tiny shriek escaped from this thing as it perished. Perhaps if he failed to learn any soul arts then he would have been able to escape. The moment the thing perished the large tree behind him that was trying to resist the electricity started to wither. The fruits all turned to dust and the goop that was the clones evaporated.

Where he sliced the strange small parasite an item appeared. It was a pink shell that contained two Daos. The Dao of wood and the Dao of water was clearly radiating from this time that he quickly stored into his spatial ring.

‘Good… now I need to make it back…’

The moment he grasped the shell to put it away he could feel the whole space rumbling. This shell that was created was collapsing but this wasn’t all. The whole pocket dimension and all the others connected to them were crumbling just like this tree. He needed to get out of here now, if he didn’t then becoming trapped between these dimensions was a possibility.

Chapter 650

“The Patriarch ordered us to evacuate, what are you doing? Get moving if you don’t want to be left behind, this place is collapsing!”

A large group of cultivators was quickly flying back into their golden palace for protection. Luckily their elders had informed them of the impending doom before they got too far away from their golden fortress. At the moment the massive army of clones was getting pushed back but after the order was given they started retreating.

Some of the warriors were saddened by this decision but their trust in the leaders was unbreakable, they must have had a reason for ordering them to stand down. The huge monster that was before them that looked like a black centipede continued to produce shockwaves while battling with multiple nascent soul masters. They too started retreating which brought the attention of this monster to the flying golden fortress.

This exposed it to more danger and damage as all the enemy forces that had been previously spread out throughout the battlefield started concentrating on one location. There were a lot more of them there but at least the angelic automatons didn’t seem to be going back. They aided the cultivators in retreating while taking the brunt of the counterattack. Soon the whole area started rumbling and finally, everyone realized why their leaders ordered them to retreat.

“The pocket dimension… it’s collapsing!”

A ripple shot through the entire area and came from within the huge monster. The moment this shift took place this large being stopped in its tracks and started crumbling. It wasn’t the only one that stopped, the same happened to the cloned troops that just remained stationary. It was as if there was some type of off switch in their brains that was triggered and now they didn’t know what to do anymore.

Some of the creatures started crumbling into dust just like the rest but the humanoid clones just remained there. They seemed confused by the situation as if a veil was lifted from their heads for the first time. Even when the whole place was collapsing they just stared at it all while not knowing what to do. Some of them even started crashing to the ground as if they forgot how to utilize their spiritual energy to keep them afloat.

Everyone previously saw the Patriarch charge into the beast not that long ago. Now that it was crumbling it was clear to them that he had managed to destroy what was keeping it alive. The bonus of the clone armies becoming disoriented was a fortunate boon as it allowed them to quickly rendezvous at the golden palace.

“Everyone, hurry up, we don't have much time.”

To their surprise, the man that they were just thinking about suddenly appeared right above the golden palace. The blue light that shone before his appearance informed them about the teleportation technique that he used. Before they could give out a resounding cheer of praise to their leader they felt a strange force surrounding them.

It didn’t feel dangerous or out of place, instead, it actually felt quite warm and welcoming. It looked like a veil of golden light wrapping around their bodies. The energy was very reminiscent of something familiar so they didn’t defend against it. Soon after though, this warm force quickly yanked the people that were still outside of the golden palace towards it.

Even the large ships that were slowly floating back into the range of the golden palace’s shields started speeding up. It was as if there was a black hole created in the middle that was sucking them all in. Soon enough all of them were in range of the outer shields and Zhang Dong gave out the next order.

“Everyone, grab onto something and close your eyes, this won’t be pleasant!”

The soldiers weren’t sure what to make of it but before they closed their eyes they could see the world around them crumbling into pieces. It was as if even the air was disintegrating into nothingness before them. This was the moment when they realized why their leader was forcing them within the confines of the golden palace. Right before the world crumbled they were teleported somewhere.

“Ugh…”

“Blergh…”

Some of the people that were caught in the teleportation technique started vomiting the moment it finished. It was a lot rougher than what they remembered from before but they were safe. Now that they could open their eyes they saw darkness everywhere. They were under the dark sea again through which they traversed before. The silence was quickly broken through as something started to rumble in the distance.

“Isn’t that the chasm that we dove into before? It’s collapsing…”

There was a strange scene playing out before them. The large gash on the sea floor was vanishing before their eyes. It was surrounded by a strange dark glow as it began to close onto itself.

“Was this some type of spatial anomaly?”

Some of the elders called out as they could feel various energy fluctuations coming from that spot. It seemed that the angler fish that they were swallowed by before wasn’t the real entrance to the pocket dimension. This was this large chasm and now it was collapsing unto itself.

“Does this mean that even if we escaped from that beast, we would be stuck in a crumbling pocket dimension?”

The elder cultivators started sweating while thinking of what would have become of them if they were stuck in there. Only thanks to their Patriarch that were able to teleport them out of the crumbling dimension were they able to survive. It was either a miracle or his knowledge that allowed for this miracle. They could see themselves escaping outside of the large fish only to be then greeted by nothingness and no way home.

“The Patriarch is great…How did he know?”

“I don’t know but it’s over now…”

Everyone looked up to where a man covered in shiny white armor was floating. This was the leader that had brought them victory once more. Even though this trip didn’t bring them many treasures they had gotten rid of the underwater bearings plaguing their lands. Now they could claim this territory and its riches as their own. This was enough as there were still many undiscovered locations down there, even being able to harvest the fish living down here was worthwhile.

Their eyes started sparkling almost as much as their leader was. They all quickly clasped their hands together while bowing before him. It started with one person and quickly turned to thousands of soldiers honoring their leader.

“Long live the Patriarch, Long live the United Element’s Sect!”

…

‘Whew, that was close, glad that I had Bob make an analysis or this could have gone really wrong.’

Just as some of his elders assumed he was going to attempt teleportation that took the shop into the chasm. His first thought was to get out of the large angler fish before escaping back up. However, this was a trap in itself as all of them would be caught in another pocket dimension that was now going through self-destruction.

‘Who would have thought that the chasm was the entrance to another dimension, I didn’t feel anything at all when going through it…’

Bob was able to present him with the full scope of the pocket dimensions they were all trapped in. He knew that after defeating the Empress a chain reaction would be started. The smaller dimensions would start imploding while also generating a strange effect.

‘This was really a mission for one person.’

The calculations presented him with the truth. He was a system holder and would have been affected by these pocket dimensions in a different way. Others would be torn to shreds but he would be sucked into another teleportation gate. It was hard to pinpoint where he would come out but it was just a setup to force him to go down a certain path.

‘Perhaps I’d end up in another Empire and have to make my way back home again? Or it could have been another hidden area that I haven’t discovered… I need to analyze this room first.’

He was not sure what was in store for him but for now, he decided to gather more information. The shell that would allow him to absorb two new Daos was not used yet. Zhang Dong wasn’t sure what would happen after adding the two. Perhaps he would manage to germinate this seed that was stuck inside of him. If that happened it would be better to prepare for a confrontation with the Overseer as they would probably become aware of his change.

‘I might become more powerful than her but it might not be enough… The transformation to the next level could also take longer than I expect…’

There were too many variables for now so he decided to let it rest. Three out of the four Empires were now dealt with and the last one was part of his allies. Argus and Lucious weren’t around for this journey and he had also not discovered any new parts of their secret armor. However, they didn’t pose much of a threat to him at this point. Even if they decided to point their swords in his direction, they weren’t capable of defeating him.

After destroying the Cerulean Empress he realized that his power had risen tremendously. The Emperor level enemies he faced were all around the same level with the transformed Phoenix Emperor being the strongest of the bunch. Their power level seemed to correlate to the number of Daos that he could get from them. This would put this Empress somewhere in the middle of the other two.

“Is everything all right? Are there enemies somewhere?”

“Enemies? No, I was just thinking about some things, we are safe here.”

While the chasm was collapsing Liena approached him. Her form was clad in the armor that he created for her with the help of the system. Right behind her was Huo Qiang as well as Zhang Zhi in similar ones that allowed them all to be closer to his level. Thanks to these four people he was able to somehow get the larger group outside. Now that it was finally over he decided to deactivate his own armored garb and look at his friends and family that had gathered here.

“Let’s go home, everyone.”

The others nodded back and removed the armored pieces just like he did. The battle was over and the war was almost over, now only one real threat existed that he needed to prepare for…

Chapter 651

“The sect warriors, they have returned!”

“Are they really back?”

“Yes, we must quickly depart, maybe we can witness the Patriarch!”

“Is the Patriarch going to appear!?”

A group of kids was screaming through the streets while charging forward. Not so long they heard that their army had been victorious. The pride in the sect that resided in this grand city was at the zenith. It was victory after another victory without them ever having to back down.

It started with the strange demi-human monsters that plagued the borders. The United Element Sect was the only large force that fully defended their lands. Everyone else had fled back into the central regions of the empire where the Azure Emperor resided. To their surprise he was not the one they should have relied on, the one to save them was his brother the Golden Dragon.

This was the start of his legend which continued to this very day. People were quickly turning away from the previous Emperor that didn’t do anything to help them. Even to this day, there was no word from the capital city. During the whole evacuation not much had been done as the people were left stranded in front of the large walls leading into the Lands of the Long Clan.

It became painfully obvious that the citizens of this empire didn’t matter to the Azure Emperor at all. Some even speculated that they would do nothing unless they were directly attacked themselves. Others claimed that the Golden Dragon had been sent by his elder brother to take care of the situation. These rumors could not be confirmed as the Emperor never spoke out nor did his brother. Thus most assumed that Zhang Dong was acting on his own accord.

Spirit Spring City was quickly becoming the hottest new tourist attraction in this empire. Some even decided to create new settlements inside this region after what had transpired. It was clear to many that it was better to seek shelter with the Golden Dragon that actually defended his lands and the others instead of begging the Azure Dragon for some mercy.

This wasn’t all good, a lot of the cultivators in which direction this was all heading. Now after another victory, Zhang Dong had proven yet again that he was one of the strongest within the Empire. No one really knew how he could stack up against his brother but they were convinced that a day might arise when the two would clash swords against each other.

Two Emperors could not exist at the same time and it was clear that the United Element Sect had full control of the whole western region of the empire. Even the West was rumored to have fallen to his power. The Heavenly Crane Sect had taken aid from Zhang Dong who participated in their counterattack against the Emerald Phoenix Empire. The tide quickly shifted after he joined up and the rest was history.

“It’s grand elder Huo Qiang!”
“I can see some other elders but it’s hard to see…”

“Idiots, just look at the spirit screen it shows a much better image!”

Some of the onlookers tried to sneak a peek at the large golden palace in the sky. It was tremendous in size and radiated an aura of power. Within it, their Patriarch could possibly be inside. He rarely showed himself out in the open and was rumored to reside mostly inside his own home in secluded cultivation. Only when the time to battle other powerful masters was right, did he show himself to the public.

Instead, most people could see some other prominent figures. One of the was the elder that was famous for controlling flames or the Patriarch’s grandfather that enjoyed the company of many ladies. Both of them were flying through the air while people waved. Soon a line of flying masters filled the entire area as they arrived.

…

“They sure are jolly.”

“Why wouldn’t they be? They are able to witness the creation of a new legend.”

“A new Legend huh?”

“Is everything okay? You don’t seem too happy, is there a new battle awaiting us?”

“I’m not sure, probably if I don’t seek it out, we’ll be content for many years… maybe even for a thousand.”

“My dear husband, I think you have earned a break, If you’re afraid of that Azure Dragon then don’t, we have grown too much for him and the Long Clan to be an issue. If they try anything, we will just crush them!”

“Haha, my dear wife, you sure can be ferocious.”

Zhang Liena smiled while clenching her fist. Zhang Dong looked at her and knew that after all that they went through her power had skyrocketed. It was the same for everyone else that had participated in the battles down in the north. With time they would get even more powerful and perhaps it would have even been possible to get some people up to Emperor levels of power within a couple of hundred years.

“Don’t worry, I’m not planning any wars for now, we do have to keep an eye out for my dear brother but I don’t think he will try anything.”

“It does seem so, he had the perfect opportunity to raid our sect while we were all gone.”

Zhang Dong nodded as this was the case. Their spies never sent any signs that the Long Clan was attacking. He had a few theories about why this was the case, one of them involved the scenario that was taking place. It was possible that the Azure Emperor was never meant to be an obstacle. Instead, he had given him the tools to fight against the other leaders. Only thanks to the Golden Palace was he able to take care of three emperors within a year's time.

“It is so, this is a time to rejoice we have earned this peace.”

Zhang Dong nodded again while he and Liena were sitting in the secret chamber away from the others. His wife liked this spot as no one besides them could enter it to bother them. They had spent a lot of the trip back in here just relaxing. Even though they could have used a teleport back home there was no reason. Their children were cared for and it was better to conserve the spirit points.

Even though he didn’t know if he could relax, there wasn’t really much else that was left to be done. The main enemies that plagued these lands were gone and only Argus with Lucius remained here. Unless they were hellbent on getting into the lands of the Long Clan then he could relax. Their search for the armor pieces would probably take a while as the Azure Empire was a huge place. Considering that he had grabbed their secret sword from the Azure Palace, the other items were probably scattered elsewhere.

The Demi-Human Emperor had been defeated and his forces were driven back to the West. There were still two active bridges there that connected him to their lands but he had no intention of letting anyone cross them. Instead, his people continued to build up massive walls and defensive structures for any potential invaders. If for some reason another Demi-Human Emperor was created within a hundred years, his forces would be ready to drive him back even without his help.

To the East, things were looking similar. With the help of the Heavenly Crane Sect and his angel automatons, he built up a defensive fortress near the bridge that existed there. There was only a single bridge there so it would be easier to defend and whoever decided to wander in would be pelted by spirit canons of huge sizes.

Then last was the underwater empire that had just vanished along with their bridge. Right after the collapse of the dimensional abnormality there, the connection vanished from the map. It was as if it never existed, to begin with, and any red areas vanished along with it. The undersea creatures that remained in the sea were cut from the connection they had with their Empress and were now not even seen as part of that Empire.

When Zhang Dong looked at his minimap there wasn’t really much left for him to do. It was easy to keep Argus and Lucius in check thanks to this map he lifted from his older brother. He needed to make a decision now, would he try to absorb the Dao of water and wood that he received from the Empress or was it better to wait?

‘I might be able to ascend now but it might not be enough…’

He wasn’t sure how the other system holders did it but perhaps he needed to take out all four enemies before it was all over. However, there was a small problem with that plan as the King from the magical kingdom Argus came from wasn’t here. It was possible for him to enter these lands but this didn’t mean that it would come to blows.
‘If that’s the case I might have to spend some time preparing by myself. Bob, I need you to calculate the probability of me reaching a new realm after absorbing that seashell. I don’t care how long it takes, we have some wiggle room.’

‘Affirmative, beginning calculations…’

“Shall we depart?”

“Sure, I bet those two are waiting for us.”

Zhang Dong smiled at Liena who gently grasped his hand. When looking at his lovely wife he could feel some of that stress moving away. He didn’t need to make a decision right away, this day was one to celebrate. His quest of minimizing casualties was close to ending and he had earned a small break. Perhaps if he put more thought into it he would arrive at the proper answer to his next task.

When he arrived outside he was greeted by many cheers from millions of people. He did not expect this many eyes to be on him as he was floating through the air. There were just so many living humans down there and all of them were ecstatic to see him. Considering that just a few years ago he had been nothing more than a regular person living in a small apartment, this felt a bit surreal.

However, even when they cheered he didn’t really care that much. This was not really why he was doing this, the real reason was in the distance. He could see the large floating structure that housed his children within. They were waiting for his return and together with his wife, he would finally have some time to relax.

Chapter 652

“Congratulations!”

“Happy Birthday!”

“Can we eat the cake now?”

“Xiu’er what did you learn?”

“Uh… can we eat the cake now, please?”

“That’s not what I meant…”

“Ouch, my cheeks. Mother stop pulling on them!”

Zhang Dong was sitting to the side while looking at his wife stretching Xiu’s cheeks out. It was a joyous occasion as his son had reached the age of six. As a father, he was feeling proud but also sad. He had missed five of these birthdays already, previously he was teleported away into another world and this was the first time he was here.

The attention was pulled away from his son by his drooling sister. Apparently, the cake that was made from various delicacies was something that she desired. Cultivators teeth weren’t really affected by caries so there was no reason to deny his children from eating sweets. Before she could dig in the birthday boy still needed to make a wish.

“I should make a wish?”

“That’s right but you need to blow out the candles in one go first or it won’t work!”

To everyone's surprise, the ceremony was changed this year around. When Xiu was younger there wasn’t really any cake as people here celebrated things differently. Shoveling chocolate cake into a toddler was also something that he was concerned about. Now on the other hand when the kids were a bit older, it was fine for them to gobble down all these sweets.

This reminded him of when he was younger. His mother tended to always make a large cake that was usually made with a lot of chocolate. Cooking wasn’t one of his best skills so he just left it up to the sect chef instead. After describing to him what the cake should look like or taste he was given something that tasted quite similar.

Zhang Jun looked at the six candles in front of him as if they were some legendary treasure. It was clear to his father that the little boy was still reserved about their interactions. However, it was much better than when he first arrived in this world. Soon enough he was leaning over and blowing out the six candles in one go. It wasn’t really hard for someone like him who had a natural martial physique. His lung capacity was a lot higher than normal and almost caused the top part of the cake to fly away.

“Happy Sixth Birthday Jun.”

“Happy Birthday!”

People started cheering as all of the candles were blown out in one fell swoop. Jun smiled while looking at the people around him but his gaze mostly fell on his father which Zhang Dong noticed. Even though they had a rough start he could see that his child was interested in him. Probably being the Golden Dragon who was the most powerful cultivator around helped move things along.

“Good job my Son, now you can eat the cake.”

“Yay, cake!”

Jun’s sister saw that as a signal for her to get some of that yummy-looking cake. Liena that was next to her delivered some divine justice by bonking her on the head before she could get her hands on it.

“Calm down young lady, a daughter of mine will not eat with her hands, wait for the cook to put it on the plate!”

“I’m sorry mother…”

People laughed at his daughter that started rubbing her head. There were a lot of people from their inner circle here but they tried to contain everything. Zhang Zhi and his family were here, his wife had delivered two boys that were seven and five years old. Both of them were sitting to the side and eyeballing the chocolate cake that was getting passed around.

‘I hope they can form a relationship with my son but I don’t like how they are treating him…’

Zhang Dong had a few concerns with his children. Everyone was treating them a bit too well as if they were from some type of royal family that wasn’t that far off. He would have preferred it if his children were treated equally to the others but this was probably too much to ask from the cultivator nuts living in this world. Even though he tried to strip the cast system it wasn’t such an easy task to remove it.

Even now a group of kids was surrounding his son that was eating cake and unpacking some gifts. He was showered with expensive toys and adoration from his peers. It seemed that the parents of the other children had told their offspring to get closer to Jun. This was normal as being close to the child of the Patriarch was an obvious thing that could get them ahead in life. Pushing their daughters that were of similar age as him close was also something they were already thinking of.

‘What’s with those girls… there are so many of them there, did those sneaky elders talk them into it? This feels wrong.’

Zhang Jun was already surrounded by young girls. Some of them were smiling at him in an awkward fashion as if they were told to go along with whatever he desired. This was the part that he was worried about that could cause his son to go down an erroneous path. He was a young master now with the most powerful person in the sect as his father. It wouldn’t be strange if he started thinking that he was better than others or that he was some type of destined being.

‘I can’t let him become like those other idiot young masters… the same thing goes for my daughter…’

When looking at Xiu with cake on her face his sour mood quickly went away. However, soon he was thinking about the same thing. Many other kids were gathering around her as well. For the time being he was leaving his daughter up to her mother. She had informed him about some elders showing interest in presenting suitors for her but for the time being she denied them all. There were apparently even some that attempted to tie her into a political marriage with the Huo Clan. Perhaps this was one of the reasons that she seemed to dislike Qiang even more now than before.

Luckily for his offspring, he was not planning on letting them marry anytime soon. The two wouldn’t be burdened with a political marriage as long as he was in power. While his bond with his own wife was somewhat political and it worked out, he couldn’t imagine a life where no love existed. Liena was luckily interested in him beforehand which initiated a spark in him that continued to burn brightly to this very day.

“Is everything fine?”

“Yes? Why wouldn’t it be?”

“You do have that look on your face, my husband.”

“I can’t hide anything from you, can I?”

“No, you can not and you should stop trying.”

Liena approached him while he was staring at his children. Luckily his position was so high that he could forgo any mingling with the other elders. Being forced to converse with old farts about the state of the empire was not something he wished to do now. Thus he was left sitting in his throne-like chair with a good view of his kids that had gone away from the table to play.

“I was just thinking about the future of our children, sooner or later they will grow up and need to fend for themselves.”

“Oh? I’m not sure if there is anything to worry about, with how their father is now, no one would dare to stand in their way.”

“I guess you’re not wrong…”

While Liena knew somewhat about his real origin she was not informed about everything. After winning so many recent battles she might have assumed that her husband was an invincible master that not even the Azure Emperor could face. This would still need to be confirmed but as it stood now, there wouldn’t be any chance to prove this theory.
The war between empires was over now and the refugees poured back to the lands that were once in turmoil. People were singing praises of the Golden Dragon who was now the savior of the empire. His sect was now considered the owner of the western region with the Long Clan owning the middle and the Heavenly Crane Sect the east.

This didn’t mean that the way his sect acted didn’t have a greater impact on the population. Besides the old residents from the west, others from the east and even central regions started pouring in. The way Zhang Dong’s name was elevated to be on the same level as the Azure Emperor caused this.

The Emperor was an age-old name that no one could really touch. He on the other hand was more palpable and accessible. Spirit Spring City was his home ground and many people rushed over with hopes of joining his sect. The next time the sect pushed for a recruitment drive he expected the candidates to multiply by at least ten times. He was the hottest name on the tongues of everyone and would probably remain

“There is nothing to worry about, not even the Azure Emperor would be brazen enough!”

“Hey, it would be better if you didn’t say such things out loud…”

“What is there to fear?”

Liena shrugged as she was convinced of the power their sect had. In her and the elders minds, they had become a mountain amongst pebbles. The Heavenly Crane Sect was no match for them so they assumed that the Long Clan wouldn’t be that much of a problem either.

Some of them were even hoping that they continue on their warpath. Taking out three powerful beings skyrocketed their confidence. They were willing to believe that they could gain control over the whole Empire and become a new dynasty. The only reason they wouldn’t was due to their Patriarch not seeming to be interested in such a thing.

‘I hope they won’t try to plot something in the background…”

While the war was over it could be restarted at any time. The borders in the west weren’t really drawn out as there wasn’t anything done in an official fashion. The old sect that controlled the West was gone which would usually mean that the spot had become vacant. While the Heavenly Crane Sect accepted the United Element Sect as their equal, the Long Clan had reminded silent.

‘I hope days like this could continue for a bit longer… but sooner or later I’ll have to act.’

Zhang Dong peeked at his system screen where he could see a percentage counter that was slowly going up. The scanning process of the room she took from the water empress would still take some time, before it was completed he could only hope that peace would reign.

Chapter 653

‘This isn’t as easy as I expected it to be… but nothing that matters ever is.’

Zhang Dong was sitting in something that looked like a room that was lifted from an apartment. The back of it was missing and instead of walls, it was surrounded by a bubble made of energy. The outside was in an empty space covered by thick cement-looking rocks. It was illuminated from all sides and floated directly in the middle. The lack of any windows and doors was on purpose as only he could get in here through the help of his system.

This place was hidden away in the Dimensional Regalia that housed a continent-sized pocket dimension. It was the best place to hide away such an important treasure and perhaps enough to keep the overseer away. Considering that it was an immortal grade treasure, perhaps the one pretending to be the Azure Emperor’s wife would not be able to get in.

What he wanted to do here was figure out how time worked. The Dao of time was mostly unknown to him but after seeing the creatures that were frozen in time, he hoped to figure some things out. Bob had been able to somewhat hack himself into the room to present him with a few things. It was now somewhat possible for him to recreate the effect through this machine but he didn’t really understand the concept of it.

For the test, he brought over a lone creature from the outside. It was just a little spirit mouse that had been put on hold. The time around it had been slowed down but not really frozen as it was still moving. Through the machine, he could somewhat slow down or speed up the passage of time around this little creature. However, stopping it outright wasn’t that easy, first of all, it required him to use spirit points and a lot of them.

‘So, if I wanted to stop time for one second with this thing, I’d need a year's worth of spirit points?’

‘Affirmative.’

‘That’s quite something and I can’t even activate it unless it’s outside of this chamber…’

To be frank, the plan to learn the Dao of Time to counter the time-stopping effect of the Azure Empress was looking grim. With his current understanding, he would not be able to speed up or slow down everything by more than a fraction of a second. He did not even know if he would be able to move at all if the same thing happened again.

‘It’s better than nothing though…’

There were a few ways of using this thing and at least he was able to go through the tip of the iceberg. There was a chance that he could protect himself against the time-stopping effect if he did things right. Luring the woman over here would be one thing and something that he even thought about.

The sea shell that he took from the Cerulean Empress was still in his possession but he decided not to use it yet. He worried that the moment he did something would happen to his mutated seed. It could attract the Azure Empress to this location which he wanted to postpone.

‘Maybe it would be possible to trap her here and ask her some questions… But will I be strong enough to tackle her by myself?’

By analyzing the Overseer from the other world he knew that his next opponent should be above the nascent soul level. After revisiting the secret ground that he was forced to go through he became aware of one truth. Something that created this world was keeping people from reaching the immortal realm through regular means.

Qi Condensation, Foundation Establishment, Core Formation, and last Nascent Soul. These were the first four realms that were freely accessible to the people of this world. However, there was a new realm above the Nascent Soul that was still below the immortal realm.

After going through the research of his predecessor, he came to a conclusion. The realm above the nascent soul level should have been easily reached by him. All clues pointed to mastering a greater Dao and he had mastered multiple ones already. Dao of Heavenly Lightning, Dao of Holy, Dao of Darkness, Dao of Flames, Dao of Wind, and Dao of Gravity were the ones that he had fully mastered.

There were ones that he had not yet fully comprehended as the Dao of Swords that he was also very proficient at. Yet this should have already been enough for him or anyone else to break through into the next realm. He could even conclude that fully mastering a greater Dao was not really needed for the stage above the nascent soul.

‘He names the stage after this Dao Enlightenment stage, then after it would be the Dao Mastering stage or Dao Merging stage. The first one was probably where you mastered one greater Dao and in the next one you had to do the same with multiple ones, maybe even combine them into something greater…’

This was his theory that he came up with and also ran through Bob which gave him a high probability of it being true. There were at least two new realms that this world was stripped of. Without getting into those stages a person’s spirit sense would not be able to evolve either. Their understanding would reach a bottleneck that could never be broken.

The same thing was happening to him, without the help of the system he would not have been able to gather so many new greater Daos. Even though he knew so many it was still not possible for him to get into the true immortal stage and perhaps even if he absorbed the Dao of Water and Wood that he was given, not much would change.

‘If the stage before the Immortal realm is the Dao Merging stage, it might require me to combine at least two Greater Dao’s with each other in some way…’

Zhang Dong had tried this theory already and it wasn’t that hard to complete with his attacks. Combining the Dao of Wind with the Dao of Fire to create a Firestorm technique wasn’t that hard but this didn’t seem to be the issue. There was something missing, it was more likely that he needed to create a grand Dao of something by merging the greater Daos together with each other.

‘The main elemental Daos are wind, earth, water, and fire. Then there is also wood, holy, and darkness that sometimes are accounted for… Do I have to combine them all into something to reach the Immortal stage? Maybe it would be enough to combine the four base ones?’

He was not sure what he should do or if it was even possible. If he was supposed to combine greater Daos into a grand one then they all had to be connected to some type of source. Just like there was a lesser Dao of Rainwater that connected to the greater Dao of Water, all of these elements had to come from something.

‘There could be something that all of them came from… like a point of origin, something like a Prime element that they all stem from… In theory, if I could figure out what this Prime element is, then I’d be able to open up this seed and enter the Immortal realm.’

Now came the focal point of the issue. For him to start his research he would need to analyze all of these various elements to find a connection. Perhaps it was enough to analyze the paths that he already knew but maybe he needed the two others that were for now inside the seashell.

‘This might take a while, I wonder how long other masters took to get through this…’

He started considering the life spawn increase after reaching a realm above the nascent soul one. Perhaps it reached something like then thousand years for the first one and a hundred thousand for the next one. It was unclear but it probably gave each master a lot of time to ponder their Daos in peace and tranquility.

‘Well, I should have some time to do it…The Empire has gotten quite peaceful and if that woman hasn’t appeared I should be able to continue.’

For a moment he deliberated about hiding himself in one of the spawn zones that appeared as black circles on his map. The walls were made from an incredibly hard substance that he couldn’t break. However, after Bob informed him about them being connected to the world’s system he decided to not go with that option.

All his attempts to cultivate safety didn’t go to fruition. He had convinced himself that the moment he began a transformation into the immortal realm or one of the other two realms that were blocked, the Overseer would be at his doorstep. He was not sure how strong his next opponent was but she had to at least be in the next realm but also could be in the other one right before the immortal realm.

‘Well, I’m not in a rush for now… maybe this is for the best…’

With peace somewhat returning to the empire he finally had some time on his hands. His children were continuing to grow and he hoped to be there to witness everything. Perhaps he was being a bit selfish but he wanted to at least take some time off and enjoy the current state of things.

His lifespan would be around a millennium and his current age was not even forty years old. The body that he currently had would not age and even if it did it wouldn’t really matter. His soul was tremendous and would allow his Qi to remain almost as powerful until the moment he died.

With this in mind, he decided to make a few moves. It would be one of the first times that he actually went into a state of closed cultivation. He needed to focus on examining all of the various Daos that he had and connecting them to the others. Only after learning what he could learn from the paths he already had would he attempt to use the sea shell because when he did that, the end of this world might be upon him.

His shoulders felt heavy as he had to wrestle with a moral conundrum. Was it really fine to allow this world to perish if he failed? Like in the other world, the Overseer was trying to wipe it clean and the same thing could happen here. Perhaps it was better to live out his long life with his family and let it all go, who was he to decide their fate?

Even with those thoughts clouding his judgment he needed to push forward. The possibility of this unknown being wiping this world clean even without his involvement was also probable. When that time came, he just needed to be ready and give it his all. If there was something he could do to protect the people that he cared about, he would work tirelessly to achieve this goal.

Chapter 654

“Ah… this is the life…”

“Isn’t it? Everything has calmed down!”

“Haven’t been able to enjoy spirit wine in a while, things really did improve now…”

“Yeah, even the prices have actually gone down! Did you hear why?”

“No, but I’m assuming that you won’t rest until you inform me about it.”

“You know me well my friend, listen to this. Apparently, the United Element Sect is spending some of their wealth on helping the areas that have been affected by those strange creatures.”

“They did? Why would they do that? This makes no sense, they won’t get much in return for their generosity.”

“Haha, that’s where you are wrong my friend, people are flocking to the western region! Now is the time to spend those spirit stones and coins!”

“Now that you mention it, I have seen a lot of merchants and new businesses opening up everywhere, so that’s it!”

“Indeed, they'll attract new people to settle down and reap the rewards later!’

“But… will the others take this lying down…They must have noticed the drop in population.”

“Perhaps but what can they do? The United Element Sect is like a meteor, would they dare to stir up trouble? The Heavenly Crane Sect already made everything clear, they won’t touch the West, would the Long Clan dare?”

“This is the Long Clan we are talking about… When was the last time that they weren’t the rulers? I don’t think the history books go back that long…”

“Do you think that they won’t take it lying down? Come to think of it, they haven’t been active that much only the outer sects have been active. What if they have been preparing?”

“Hey now, preparing for what?”

“Another war…”

“Uh…”

Two old men were having a conversation while sipping on some red wine and eating chicken drumsticks. They were inside an inn that was bustling with people. Everyone seemed to be in a good mood after the three emperors had been slain. Some of the people here had been forced to retreat but most just knew things through rumors.

While to the uninformed it seemed like everything was fine to the ones that knew the dynamics between powerful sects, it looked like a powder keg waiting to explode. The whole war seemed like a slap to the face of the Long Clan. It made them look incompetent to the entire population of the Empire. Even though they might have been capable of the same feat, it didn’t matter. They didn’t do anything during the one-year war period and it made them look weak.

To other sects, the Long Clan’s movements weren’t strange. It was normal for them to prioritize the central region to which the fights didn’t reach. Both the Heavenly Crane Sect and the United Element Sect performed well during this period. No enemies went up to their doorstep which didn’t give them a reason to act.

The cultivators that resided in the smaller sects understood what the Long Clan did but this didn’t mean that they didn’t feel some type of way about the whole thing. Even though they would have probably made the same decision, there was a problem. The United Element Sect appeared out of nowhere. They were like some type of saints, helping people without asking for much. Even now after they had taken over the western region, there was a stark difference.

The previous owners that were the Soaring Dragon Sect, were different. They acted similarly to the Long Clan in a more oppressive manner. The taxes were steep and they didn’t really do much to protect the lands. Unless a powerful demonic cultivator appeared they left everything up to the smaller sects.

The replacements were different though, they even cleared up the massive concentration of demonic sects up in the northwest. Crime was at an all-time low and they were even trying to recruit people to go to the demonic island. It was a new frontier that some saw as a chance to put their mark on the world.

With the decrease in the population came a lot of possibilities. New clans and sects were popping out left and right to fill the holes. Cities that had been destroyed by the demi-humans were being rebuilt and needed new management. Under the watchful eye of the new powerhouse in the region, everything was proceeding nicely.

Usually, everyone expected territory battles between the remnants of old powers and the new ones to occur. However, there existed a new policing force in the region, a strange group of mechanical beings called the Archangels. They wouldn’t allow for much bloodshed to occur between the larger groups and would pop out if the fighting got too drastic. Already many new and old clan leaders were apprehended and taken to the mines.

Usually, none of the great three powers bothered to minimize the infighting inside of their lands. As long as they were given their share of the pie everything was fine. No one really counted all the deaths or how many small clans perished. This policing force caused them to handle things differently and in a more peaceful fashion.

However, this didn’t mean that everything was all and well, instead of open conflict it was just hidden in the background. People expected a lot more silent assassinations and the growth of those types of underground forces if things continued.
“Stop trying to scare me, you drunk bastard.”

“Haha, calm down.”

One of the two men rose up from his seat in anger at the one that was insinuating that a war would occur. Soon the two were back to laughing but in the back of their heads, they weren’t sure about that possibility. The Long Clan had a reason to move in as some people were spreading bad rumors around them. There just needed a spark to light the fuse and another conflict could be upon them.

“Long Live the Golden Dragon! He is the true savior and true ruler!”

“You dare make light of the Azure Emperor?”

“What if I do, what are you going to do about it?”

The people in the in went quiet as they felt an oppressive force wash over them. The voices of people that were outside could be heard by everyone and drew their attention.

“Did you hear that?”

“Yeah, what’s happening outside?”

These two drunk men that were foundation establishment cultivators were able to feel a power greater than themselves. They both slowly rose up from their seats to go towards the opened window. There, not that far up in the air they saw two groups of people shouting at each other.

“What sect or clan do those people belong to?”

“I think the ones on the left are from the Yan Clan… but I don’t recognize the ones on the right, probably a newly formed force.”

The two men nodded at each other as they belonged to a smaller family that only had foundation establishment experts within their ranks. They kept their voices hidden just like everyone else here as it seemed that a fight was about to break out.

“Yan Clan… I think I’ve heard that name… Oh I know, that man that is arguing, his daughter was married off to someone from the Long Clan.”

“Didn’t they flee the moment the west became chaotic, they have a lot of nerve coming back now…”

“Did they come back to reclaim their lands? Hmph, they hid behind the Long Clan walls for all this time and now they just want everything to return to how it was?”

“Hey… this doesn’t look good…”

“What do they think they are doing?”

This city was a special one, it was on the border of the West and Central regions. Previously it was divided between the Soaring Dragon Sect’s and Long Clan’s sub-clans. Wang Long's appearance and destruction of that Sect made the Long Clan’s sub-clan the true owner. However, soon after they left in fright of the Demi-Human Emperor’s forces that were destroying everything.

After things had settled down the United Element Sect lay claim to this land. This location was quite far from their original region so none of their people had yet been stationed there. This left it up to the people that remained to claim it instead. The two old men assumed that the residing new clan had achieved some type of deal with the current Western giant.

“They are really going at it… we need to get out of here before something terrible happens!’

“You are right, we should try to lay low, nothing good can come from this.”

The two men that were watching over the fight with the other people gathered here started to slowly back away. The sky above them was starting to turn into a bloodbath as the two sides started to fight. They both knew that something terrible could come from this confrontation and were quick to jump out through one of the windows.

“Look, they are already here!”

“I think we should split up here my old friend, I wish you luck.”

“You too, stay safe.”

Soon the two men were running in two different directions while glancing up. They saw flying beings surrounded by a golden aura flying toward the city. They were the angelic beings that were left to patrol the skies by the United Element Sect. There weren’t that many of them as there was just too much space to cover in this vast Empire.

“I have a bad feeling about this, I must get everyone out of this city…”

The man was sweating all over as he had been living in this place for a while. He knew that the clan head of the people that were related to the Long Clan was a hot head. The man would certainly not let things go as for him the family name was everything.

“Quickly, pack your things, and let's depart, we need to get to a safe location!’

“Grandfather, what is happening?”

When he arrived at his home he was greeted by his son's wife. Before he could give her an explanation a massive explosion erupted behind him. When he glanced back he could only see a torrent of energy that could only be created by a nascent soul master or a costly treasure.

“Quick stop talking, get everyone together, we must leave this place before it becomes a battlefield…”

He could only dread while looking at the mangled angel automation being flung out of the explosion. A confrontation between the Long Clan and the United Element Sect was something everyone was dreading and this could have been the spark to set it off. Even though it could have been resolved with money he was not willing to wait around for another war between sects.

Chapter 655

“Something seemed to happen to the angel units at this location, could there have been some demi-human stragglers?”

“At this location? They should not be able to reach that far and the elders should have chased every one of them down…”

“The Emerald Phoenix Empire?”

“Why would they start things now that their two Emperors are dead? And how would they even get here from the Eastern region, do you have a brain in that head?”

“My apologies Senior brother, but who would dare attack us?”

“I don’t know but that city, isn’t it located near the Central Area?”

“The central area? Could the Long Clan be involved? But why would they…”

“I don’t know but we have to report this to the elder immediately, go tell them that something happened in the Azure Basin City.”

“Leave it to me, senior brother!”

A man that looked to be in his early twenties clasped his hands before running out from the large room they were in. Inside a large map of the whole empire was visible in the background. It wasn’t the only one as many smaller ones were placed at booths with sect members.

This was something that was created by the elders and used to monitor the whole western region. The youths here were sect disciples and seniors that were working for their merits. The Empire as well as the Western region was gigantic and it required a lot of manpower to monitor along with the angelic automatons that could be ordered to take care of the situation.

When something was discovered a person here could send out one of those automatons or relay the information to the nearest sect location. It was similar to the police force with this being a command center. Thanks to this system a certain Patriarch could turn his brain off and focus on cultivating to reach the next level.

Thanks to this in place it was possible to intercept an SOS signal and one of the people that caught it was already running. The young man made his way to the elder's office which he sprinted into. His hand didn’t need to reach for the door handle as it was one that could slide open to the side. What he needed to do was to inject a specific spiritual energy pattern and it would perform the task for him

“Elder, I bring bad news!”

“Yes, bad news for you if you don’t explain yourself, how many times do I have to tell you juniors not to rush into my office like this!”

There was a lone man behind a large desk made of dark wood. On the desk, he had several marked communication jades through which he could call other sections of this large building. Due to him being responsible for the monitoring department whenever something bad happened, he was the first to know. Then if the situation was truly dire he would inform people in higher positions that could move a greater amount of people and even reach the one on top, the Patriarch.

“Of course, it’s dire news, three lesser anger units have been destroyed and we have lost contact with them.”

“Three whole units? Hm… that is bad but the weaker ones can be defeated by weaker cultivators, what were they doing before the signal was lost?”

“I have brought the report.”

The young man gave him a memory jade with the information. After plugging this item into the nearby monitor he could go through some of the footage that the angel units recorded. It was similar to policemen wearing cameras on their bodies. The image quality was limited and the framerate was bad but it was a necessity to conserve more information.

“This looks familiar…oh now, is it really… the Long Clan?”

The old man started squinting while going through the image. He couldn’t make the mistake as the situation was dire. Even though a lot of people considered their sect to be one of the great three, this man was a person that survived the old era of the Zhang Clan. He remembered the days of struggling and the meteoritic rise to power was only recent. The fear of the Long Clan had been ingrained since birth.

Even though he saw the youngsters being boisterous and proud, he was not of the same mind. The Patriarch was strong but even he sometimes vanished and faltered. His disappearance for five years was an indication of this. It was never really clear how well the greater elders were doing only during a full-scale war would everything become apparent.

“Are they finally making a move?”

“Making a move? What are you even talking about?”

“The Long Clan has remained silent for so long, there were rumors that they were just gathering their forces.”

“That baseless rumor?”

“Is it baseless elder? It seems that they have shown their fangs and attacked one of our cities. What will we do, should we notify the supreme elders or have the Patriarch…”

“You want to involve the great leader? Are you stupid or something!”

“Ow…”
The old man started frowning before smacking the youth over the head with his palm. If they sent out the nascent soul elders there then the Long Clan could respond in a similar fashion. This could lead to another war that could end very badly for their rising sect. The elder here knew of the dangers and was positive that the Long Clan was just waiting for an excuse to show themselves. It was strange for them to throw the first stone, there had to be something else to it.

“No, I will relay this information to the proper department, sending a small unit of experts should be enough. Nevertheless, this involves the Long Clan so I’m not someone that can make this decision, now get out and keep your mouth shut. If I hear that anyone is spreading rumors that a war with the Long Clan is upon us, I’ll come looking for you!”

“Yes, Elder…”

The youth walked out with a lump on his head while the elder contacted another department. Soon a lot more calls were going through as many people were trying to make the correct decision. Even though no one wanted this information quickly reached some of the supreme elders as the potential involvement with the Long Clan was a big risk.

“Hm… So the decision is mine to make… Very well, we will send a small force there with one nascent master which will be me. I haven’t had anything to do for a while. This might be a good occasion to stretch the old bones and see some new sights, this must be some type of misunderstanding. I can’t leave this up to the youngsters.

The word reached the ear of Zhang Jin, the Patriarch’s grandfather. After achieving the nascent soul level his complexion got better and he now looked to be in his fifties. Over a year had passed since his last involvement with the Golden Dong palace he was now at another location. He was now stuck tending to the main sect which was a boring endeavor.
With this incident popping out it was a good chance to do something about that boredom.

“Dong’er is in closed-door secluded cultivation, he must not be disturbed before it’s truly necessary.”

Zhang Jin rose up while dining a special robe with the United Element Sect’s emblem on the back. Around this Emblem, it had smaller different colored circles that represented the four base elements of fire, water, wind, and earth. With this appearance, he would have no problem showing where he came from.

“Gather up everyone, I want a team to assemble within fifteen minutes by the great teleportation gate, and prepare the middle-sized battle Crouser for transport.”

“As you wish, Supreme Elder.”

“Ah… life sure is great when your grandchild is so successful.”

Thanks to his current position there were a lot of resources at his disposal. With the help of the angelic automatons and lesser versions of them, a whole production line was created. Now these puppets were the ones making flying ships made of precious metal that he could order around. For this small expedition, he decided to take one of the fastest ships at their disposal. It had a sleek design and didn’t even use a sail as the models that came before it. Instead, the ship had its own spirit engine that generated thrust from the back as well as an anti-gravitational field.

“It should be able to even outrun a fully ascended nascent soul master unless the Azure Emperor decides to come out, there should be enough time to escape.”

While the other sect members made the preparations Zhang Jin examined some of the treasures at his disposal. This mission’s intent was not to start a fight but to prevent it. Cultivators loved pricey treasures so the spirit herbs, pills, and divine treasures that he had at his disposal could be used as bartering chips.

It didn’t take a long time for everything to be prepared. Everyone that was on his crew was someone that had previously participated in the war. They were all veterans and were good at using the tools that the Patriarch provided for them. With his status, Zhang Jin could make everyone else wait while he was allowed to initiate the teleportation gate.

“Let us head out! If everything goes well we will remain for the day and visit the sites.”

Soon Zhang Jin was seated on the captain's chair. No one commented on the latter part as they knew what kind of person he was. Normally they would all love to return to their jobs and homes as soon as possible. The old man on the other hand loved hanging out in new locations where new lovely beauties could be discovered. There he would try to entice them and without his wives being there, no one could stop him.

The large circular gate that could fit a massive battleship through it was activated. The Crouser which was made from the same material as the Golden Palace was quite eye-catching. It was a calling card to the sect and to its leader. With it, as a shield, no one in the Western regions would raise a tone.

The propulsion system that was on the back started glowing in a red light. Just as soon as the gate materialized the quick-flying vessel started moving forward. Before them was a juncture city through which they could arrive at the Azure Basin City within a day’s time. If they tried doing it from here it would take him a week but with this little shortcut, they would soon arrive at the answer to their question about the Long Clan and their true motives.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 656

“Elder Jin, we will be approaching the Azure Basin City soon.”

“Are those why they call it the basin city?”

“I’m not sure…”

Zhang Jin yawned while looking out the window. There large steady circular pools of water were everywhere. Around them was nice green grass along with some peaceful animals drinking from them. There was a noticeable lack of fish and plant life inside these pools of water which probably meant that they weren’t lakes.

“What do you mean you’re not sure, why haven’t you informed yourself? Did you become lazy after my grandson elevated the sect?”

Zhang Jin shook his head while squinting at one of the people from his squad. He had brought along a few people that he knew. Normally when going out on missions, people from the sect personnel would get all the information they could about the target. Their sect was still in the building phase which didn’t always allow them to get to everything.

“W-we managed to inform ourselves about the clans and sects that reside in this city.”

“Well, at least you aren’t totally useless, was about to send you to the demonic sect region.”

“Please, anything but that Grand Elder!’

“Haha, well who are we facing here and what are their connections?”

After a little joke, Zhang Jin started listening to the crewmate. There weren’t that many things of note besides the two feuding clans. One had ties with the Soaring Dragon Sect that used to rule the Western region and the other one was connected to the Long Clan. It was somewhat of a proxy war without the main two forces getting involved. However this was enough to paint a picture in Zhang Jin’s mind of what was happening here.

“Hm… I see, so this branching clan with ties to the Long Clan could have seen it as a chance. Now that the Soaring Dragon Sect doesn’t exist anymore, it makes sense. This complicates things…”

It didn’t take a genius to figure out what had happened. In actuality, this wasn’t something that they should have been that involved with. He didn’t even think that anyone would mind losing it to the branching clan. The problems were the angelic automatons that belonged to the United Element’s Sect.

“Perhaps it was not a good idea to leave things like this to soulless automatons.”

“I agree, if a person from our sect was here it would have been possible to diffuse the situation. The puppets are a strong deterrent but they aren’t without their faults.”

The other sect members that were in the command booth of this golden cruiser all nodded. This territory had some strategic value but their sect was already spread thin. It would take many years to gain full control over the whole Western region. There was no reason for them to start territorial disputes if this place was connected to the Long Clan.

‘This will be a hassle, hope whoever is leading that branch clan isn’t stupid. Maybe I should have gotten Zhi to come with me…’

Zhang Jin shook his head while trying to ignore the bad thoughts. He was a nascent soul master from a prestigious sect and should be strong enough for this mission. If all things failed he had a few ways of getting out of trouble. If he allowed some hotheads like Huo Qiang or stoic fools like Zhang Zhi to come along, whenever a chance presented itself they would approach an issue with their weapons drawn.

“Grand Elder, we are close to the city. There are unknown cultivators approaching us, all core formation experts.”

“Slow down, have a talk with them, and inform them about our issues.”

“Yes, Grand Elder.”

While Zhang Jin was here to talk it wouldn’t be proper for a nascent soul master to come greet core formation juniors. Instead, one of the senior members of the crew that he could trust to do a good job was asked to perform this task. Soon their golden ship was coming to a halt right before the walls of this large city.

It was filled to the brim with millions of residents and had some signs of struggle. When spreading his spirit sense and also looking at the camera image on the panels he could see destroyed buildings. Some of the large pagodas had holes in them. The fires were already put out but it was clear that a fight took place.

“Whoever did this doesn’t care much for the people in this city, this would have never happened in Spirit Spring City.”

Zhang Jin recalled the effort of evacuating the citizens when Wang Long appeared. Here on the other hand he could tell that some commoners had perished in the battle. With people at higher realms involved, it wasn’t hard to kill a lesser cultivator. Even an aura of a nascent soul master would be enough to kill if not contained by them.

“Grand Elder, they told us that we can venture into the city but we must leave our ship outside.”

“How brazen, who do they think they are? They are just from a branching clan!”

“Calm down now, we are not here to start any fights. There is a reason for their behavior, there are multiple masters within the city.”

“Multiple?”
Zhang Jin could feel someone else's spirit sense interacting with his own when he tried to scan the city. It was not alone as he could feel at least two more trying to measure his power level.

“One should be a late stage, the other two were early stage so be careful, I won’t be able to protect you all.”

“Yes, Grand Elder but should we inform the sect about this and ask for help?”

“No, that won’t be necessary but … at least give them a heads up and keep even though they told us to not fly into the city, leave the ship on standby and ready for any occasion.”

“Yes, Grand Elder, we will wait for your return.”

He nodded at the group of people here and decided to leave with ten core formation experts at the great circle level. While he hovered in the middle they surrounded him while standing on large crystalline swords. They were similar to the one Zhang Dong used in his earlier days and had become a must-have for people trying to follow in his footsteps. They were actually an improvement on the old design but remained similar in appearance.

“Grand Elder…”

“Yes, we don’t seem to be welcome here.”

This was clear from the moment they entered the city. First of all the common people were all huddling up in their homes. The city that should have been bustling with life was devoid of any noise. The streets were empty and the booths that should have been filled with vendors were empty. He could feel them looking at his small group flying through the air through their windows.

“I will guide the envoys from the United Element Sect, please follow me, the Clan head wishes to speak to you.”

“I see, guide us then young friend.”

Zhang Jin started thinking that it was a good idea to come instead of the other elders. It was clear by the way these people acted that they didn’t fear them. The man that approached him was a young core formation expert in a lavish-looking robe. On the back, it had the clan name that he didn’t recognize.

‘Yan Clan, huh?’

On the sides, there were many more core formation experts looking at them and closing down the perimeter. He came with just ten people but the other side had fifty of them and they were all at the pinnacle of power.

‘If I look at even one of these experts, they would be able to destroy the old Zhang Clan even if the old Patriarch was still alive. Oh, how much things have changed.’
These experts that would previously tower over him could not really intimidate his little group. Even with it being ten against fifty he had confidence that his people would be victorious. The cultivation methods his sect used were above anything that this empire could offer. The only ones that could come close were the Long Clan and the Heavenly Crane sect. These were not them, they were only from a branch clan that would have a lesser version taught to their people.

‘It’s not a matter of quantity, it’s the quality that matters…’

His grandson was a prime example of this saying. Even when he was an early-stage core formation expert his power was closer to the Late stage. While his people could not jump three realms at once they could at least go past a single one. This was enough to make them capable of defeating any other great circle practitioner in the same realm as them.

‘Everyone, be careful and try not to speak without me, I’m not sure what they are planning but let us get out of this in one piece.’

They were finally at the end of their journey. A large lavish palace was right in the middle of this city. It looked to have been newly assembled with two smaller ones being at the edges of the city. Zhang Jin was sure that one of those lesser castles was the previous headquarters of this clan. Now that their competitor was no more they created a larger building right in the middle.

Soon the whole group was in front of a huge gate. Next to it, even more, cultivators appeared; it didn't seem that they were that welcome here. Zhang Jin floated down along with his small squad of core formation experts. The crystalline swords that they were standing on were quickly placed into their spatial rings and just in time for the large gate
to open for them.

“Please, enter the Clan Head is expecting your arrival.”

The man that exited looked old and not amused. His eyes looked at the ten core formation experts that were standing behind Zhang Jin.

“The Head has asked for the elder to enter, the rest are to stay here and wait.”

“You…!”

Before one of the core formation experts could say anything Zhang Jin raised his hand to stop him. The other people that were here were somewhat on edge as they were quick to go towards their weapons.

“It’s fine, this won’t take long.”

Soon he turned to face the man that insulted his men. He wanted to do nothing more than to slap his face and storm in but the stakes here were great. If something happened the Long Clan could seek revenge. Thus without much hesitation, he decided to go along with this clan head but he could not make himself and the sect look weak. If this Clan Head pushed things too far, then he wasn’t sure what he would do…

Chapter 657

“Hm… should I take a break? I have made some progress but it’s not going as fast as I had hoped for.”

Zhang Dong looked at his palm where a tiny little dot of dark brownish energy was bouncing around. This little dot contained the combined energies of fire, wind, and lightning. He was able to combine these three elements without them rejecting themselves but there was something missing. The dark color of this combination made him worry as he expected it to go in the opposite direction.

“But maybe I’m going in the right direction? Would the element of origin be pure black or pure white?”

If he identified the elements as colors then putting them all together would produce a darkened color from all the combined saturation. However, what he was trying to find out was a combined energy that all of these elements had in common. If he looked at it from that angle the color should have been getting brighter.

“It should be like an empty canvas that is easy to draw on and not a black patch that needs to be sieved through.”

This made sense to him as otherwise, the practitioner would have to siphon their element from this dark energy while also blocking out all the other ones. How would they do this without generating all of the other elements in the first place? It made more sense for the point of origin to be simpler than harder. Probably after finding this original element, he would be able to fashion it into all of them at once instead.

“This doesn’t mean that it was all for nothing, finding out what all of these elements have in common and how they fuse with each other should give me some insight.”

If he imagined all the basic elements like fire and water to be a part of a chain, then what he was looking for was the big one in the middle that all these elements were connected to. By bonding them with each other he was coming closer to understanding their base which he was looking for.

“Would be easier if I absorbed the water and wood element…”

His progress was slowly ramping up but there were many questions that he needed to answer. First of all his elemental Dao was also limited, at the moment he knew two of the basic elements which were fire and wind. Water was close to him but he hadn’t trouly mastered this part yet.

Then there were more advanced elements like holy, darkness, and lightning that didn’t necessarily connect to the base four. However, if there existed an origin energy that connected all of them, there was a possibility to use them for his research. His only hope was that he would be undisturbed in his secluded cultivation for at least a bit more until he got all the bugs sorted out.

“Bob, run a few more simulations for this and try finding something that binds these three elements.”

“Affirmative.”

Luckily for him, he was not alone in this endeavor. With the help of Bob’s computing power, he was able to run various simulations without having to do it himself. His Ai was integrated into his very being, his soul that had become massive. With all this computing power he would be able to shave off hundreds of years of bumbling around on his own. It would make up for the loss in longevity that was being blocked by the world’s rules. Otherwise, if he was able to reach the age of ten thousand, then it might have been possible to do it the long way.

“Should I take a break and check up on the kids?”

The spot that he decided to cultivate in was the dimensional regalia. He had hopes in the immortal treasure to shield him from the overseer. This meant that he could freely leave this place and get back to the sect. Sometimes he would take walks through the city to get his mind off things. When in a disguise he could listen in to some rumors going through the world without them being filtered by others.

People tended to hide their true selves whenever a person of power was next to them. He was the Patriarch of a great sect, the whole city would come to a halt if they spotted him taking a walk. His status was that of a King or an Emperor. Considering that the regions were so huge, he owned more land than the planet from which he originated.

“They seem to be doing fine at least, probably better not to interrupt their training…”

Instead of going out to see them, he decided to just take a peek through one of the monitor screens. His children were growing fast and his son was approaching the age of seven. His daughter that was around ten was also becoming an even bigger troublemaker. At this very moment, she was terrorizing the teenage disciples in a training facility. Her strength was above any child of her age and it was clear to everyone that she was a prodigy.

It brought a small smirk onto his face to see his own flesh and blood jumping around the stage. The others weren’t even holding back as she was just too skillful to be caught by any attacks. Her fighting style was very similar to her mother’s but it also integrated some of his own skills. She was trained by one of his own disciples that were trained in the Dao of Lightning. It seemed that she would combine this with wind energies that she also had a good affinity for.

His son on the other hand was good at fire energy just like Huo Qiang and also lightning. It was a strange combination as he didn’t really have that fiery attitude that practitioners of the Dao of fire usually had. After going through some of his training sessions he could see that he was prone to overworking himself. It was as if he loved seeing himself progress to the new stage, it brought him joy to win little battles, even if he didn’t show it on the outside.

“Everyone seems to be doing fine… Hm… That’s odd, where did that old fart go, wasn’t he supposed to be performing the grand elder duties?”
While glancing through the many screens he noticed that one of his family members was missing. Zhang Jin, who was supposed to act as a decision-maker, wasn't there. Liena, just like him, was doing some closed-door training. Even though his grandfather wasn’t the strongest out there he usually was able to make the right decision. He had one fault though, whenever a new pretty face appeared from somewhere his IQ would plummet.

“Did some new beauty appear somewhere in the empire? I told him not to use the sect teleportation gates for things like those.”

Zhang Dong quickly started going through the various screens before him. Thanks to the system that he implemented in the sect he could know everything that the people in his factions did. Things had to be logged and it was very easy for him to identify teleportation gate usage.

“He used the golden cruiser and jumped through the main gate, this is odd…”

He knew that his grandfather was a hornball but he wouldn’t go through the official gate to seek out a new lover. This had to be some kind of official mission that he decided to carry out. There weren’t many things that could force him out of the city.

“He traveled to the outermost gate…”

After checking where Zhang Jin teleported to he started getting a bad feeling about it. The gate he used was the closest to the central region. Their sect was steadily expanding its influence but building all those large structures came at a big cost. It was possible to use the old gates that other sects built but some of them weren’t up to their standards. Most weren’t large enough to let ships sail through them and were not power efficient in the slightest. The ones that his sect was using were much safer and also allowed him to track everything through his faction system.

“He probably had a good reason for not informing me about it … but not like I have to.”

“Hey Bob, bring up the mission records, they should be somewhere inside of the database.”

Zhang Dong liked to keep a watch over all of the dealings inside his sect. This also meant that he set up everything so that he could take a peek at everything if he wanted to. Bob was integrated into the system and could be used as a search tool. All of the mission data would be infused into the system and kept for storage, similar to a big library just without any books. Instead, they used items similar to communication jades that were able to use storage that cultivators could use.

“Lesser angle units were destroyed?”

He quickly looked through his autonomous army logs to confirm the mission claim. It wasn’t unusual for some of the core formation-level puppets to be destroyed. They were not invincible and he also didn’t want to scare the populace by having the stronger ones flying around everywhere.

Peace gained through an iron fist was not something he was aiming for. They were mostly there to be helpful and diffuse the situation, not murder anyone in sight who performed a crime. After confirming that the two units were destroyed in the battle and their location he concluded what his grandfather was aiming for.

“Well, it wasn’t a bad decision if the Long Clan is involv…!?”

“ALERT! ALERT! The health of a family member is critically low. Activating safety measures.”

“Huh?”

At first, he wanted to praise his grandfather for not involving him in a bothersome trip like this. Before he could close the window a red one appeared before his face. There was an alert option in his system window that could notify him if certain terms were met. This one for instance would instantly trigger if one of his family members was low on health.

“It’s gramps? What is happening there?”

Without thinking much about it he pointed his finger at the red screen before him. He was sure to rig it like this so that he could teleport to the injured family member that was under attack. With one click his body started glowing blue before vanishing within one second he was brought to where Zhang Jin had gone to.

When he appeared on the other side it was hard to not see the glowing pillar of lightning surrounding his grandfather. His body was bruised and he was out cold. The safety measure of his system had been activated to create this effect and push everyone in the vicinity to the sides. His eyes started darting around to find the perpetrator of this act. There was a lot that he could stomach but hurting his family was not one of them.

Chapter 658

“There was a hidden master among them, quickly before he can act!”

“You won’t even give me time to ask a question? Very well…”

Zhang Dong was somewhat shocked at the scene that was playing out before him. Zhang Jin was encased in golden lightning. Through the system, he could place defensive seals on people from his faction. These hidden seals could be given various attributes depending on his capabilities. It was a standard one that every one of his family members was equipped with. After sustaining enough damage it would trigger a pillar of holy lightning that would act as a shield and also recover their health back to full.

After he popped out of the teleport he was greeted by quite the scene. His grandfather was inside this column of lightning with many unknown cultivators around it. They were throwing various techniques toward it and clearly trying to deliver the finishing blow. Perhaps they had noticed that the energy was healing their target and wanted to deliver the final blow before it could finish.

Thanks to his cultivation level he could see everything very clearly. The people coming his way were moving in slow motion and trying to strike him before he got his bearings. It was a known fact that after a teleportation technique was used the user was usually disoriented for a moment. It was a great chance to land an attack before the fight even started and this was probably what they were aiming for.

‘Two early stage nascent soul masters? They are taking me lightly…’

A sword clad in spiritual energy flew at his head. It was aimed right between his eyes with the intent to kill. Then to make things worse the other man came in from behind and aimed for his blindspot. They were doing a standard combination attack, when he dodged the sword from the front the spear from behind would get him.

He wasn’t sure who these people were but they had angered the wrong person. To him, these two people were like mosquitos, not even worth moving. Without reacting at all he let the sword fly forward to connect with a thin veil of electrical energy. The moment the weapon touched the energy it absorbed a massive charge of lightning Qi onto the person that was holding the weapon.

The man’s whole body started convulsing before getting shot back in the direction he came from. It was the same for the spear user that flew forward like a madman into his blind spot. The aim was for the backside of his heart but the only thing he received was a gigaton of voltage. Both men were repelled by a simple Qi shield that he generated without moving. There was no real reason for him to move as none of the people here were qualified to be his opponents.

“You dare attack me, do you know who I am?”

Zhang Dong wanted to let his aura explode to show off his power but he decided against it for now. If he overpowered everyone instantly then he wouldn’t know what these people here were truly thinking. Force was still the number one way of clearing out problems in this world and it seemed that these people were still content with their capabilities.

“White hair and a golden aura, you are the fake from the West, or probably someone masquerading as him.”

“Fake from the West?”

While the two nascent masters were propelled into some walls his attention was pulled towards the direction of a voice. He could sense that this person was quite strong for this world's standards. He was a great circle nascent soul master and next to him was someone at the later stage as well.

“Did you think you could take over what belongs to the Long Clan and get away with it? Until the Emperor accepts your claim you hold no power here.”

“Hoh? So this is what this is all about? You deny the claim of the United Element Sect to the western region even after all that has happened?”

“You dare speak in such a tone? Grandfather, let me take care of this pretender!”

“It would be wise if you don’t proceed with whatever you think you are doing, this will only end badly for you…”

“Empty threats! You might have bested those elders but I’m not like them.”

‘Hm, so he intends his grandson to fight it out? Is he one of those types?’

As the conversation continued it seemed that a fight was imminent. He was not sure what Zhang Jin had told them but if his grandfather wasn’t able to convince them with words, then he probably wouldn’t either. When looking around he could also feel the presence of some United Element Sect’s members. They were covered in wounds and some of them had even lost their lives. It was clear that Zhang Jin had misjudged this mission’s parameters.

His next enemy was a late-stage nascent soul master. He was a lot stronger than the ones he encountered in the middle regions but he didn’t really pose a threat either. What he was more interested in was the man sitting in the large chair in the back. Ever since he arrived his gaze remained planted on his form. It was clear that he realized the threat to some degree.

Sending the stronger fighter after him was probably a means of measuring his threat level. His robe was also different, it belonged to the Long Clan while the others were part of something else, a branch family perhaps. This was probably why they were so haughty, with the backing of the Azure Emperor they expected total submission.

‘They lived hundreds of years without anyone being able to call them out on their bullshit… I guess I’ll have to wake them up from their dream.’

Before more people died he needed to end it. After the short conversation, he got the answer to his question so there was no reason for the act. His power exploded and the man that was charging at him found a fist right next to his jaw. Before he could even react his face was caved in and his body flew to the side. The explosion of speed didn’t finish there as he rocketed directly to the man sitting on the large chair.

Just like he expected, there was a purpose in sitting at that location. The area they found themselves in had a large formation inside of it. The moment he tried approaching this sitting elder its defenses had been triggered. This was perhaps the reason why the man was this confident and the smile on his face confirmed his hypothesis.

“Hah, so predictable.”

“Predictable you say?”

“What do you hope to achieve with this?”

“You are a blemish that needs to be taken care of.”

“It really worked, he took the bait.”

“His power is tremendous but he won’t be able to free himself!”

“Haha, I knew this was a grand opportunity.”

The moment he was entrapped in this formation more people started coming out of the woodwork. All of them were wearing robes from the Long Clan and consisted of four other masters at the nascent soul level. Zhang Dong had already been aware of their presence and decided to give them a chance to show themselves. If he just devastated this one old man that was before him, the others would just flee or imply that they had been blackmailed.

‘This does complicate things…’

While they gloated he was trying to figure out a way to avoid more conflict. While he was mad about what happened to his people and his grandfather there was a bigger issue here. Multiple members of the Long Clan had raised their weapons at his head. This was more or less a declaration of war. Even if he didn’t want to go that far the people from his sect would see it otherwise.

These people had planned to lure their leader into a trapping formation after attacking Zhang Jin. There was a motif and there was also no idea how many people were all behind it. Some would claim that they were acting on their own, and others would say that it was a scheme to kill the competitor for the seat on the top.

The Azure Emperor didn’t show himself though neither were any of his kids involved either. On the surface, it seemed that this was a scheme created by one of these elders that showed themselves. One of them he even knew as he was part of those three supreme elders that he interacted with.
“Long Yingjie of the Grand Elders, I didn’t expect you to be part of this.”

“I’m just performing my duties, this is all for the Long Clan.”

“I’m sure that it is…”

Long Yingjie was the oldest of the three elders that he met a few years ago. It was clear that he didn’t want the status quo to be affected by the powers in the West shifting. While the United Element’s power base grew, the one established by the Long Clan was decreasing. Their decision to not get themselves involved backfired greatly. They seemed weak in the face of danger while their competition looked very competent.

“Let me ask you, did Long Qing order this, does he even know what you are attempting to do?”

“How brazen, you dare call the Azure Emperor by his name? Elder Yingjie, we should take care of this now, we must not let him get a second chance!’

“I… agree.”

Before he was given an answer the group of nascent elders surrounded him from all sides. The trapping formation looked like a prison made from blue shackles. The moment this small group started acting the formation started getting smaller until he was stuck in a rectangle of one meter in width and two meters in height. He continued to resist while trying to fish for more answers but it didn’t seem that they would say anything else.

“I see, so that’s about it… You felt your clan to be endangered by my presence so you either orchestrated this encounter or just grasped at it when the occasion presented itself. You probably knew that I would rush to save my grandfather.”

“You’re wise for your age and would have been a powerful member of the clan if you accepted our invitation, such a shame.”

“Yes it is a shame… that I have to do this.”

While the elders were assured of their victory something unexpected happened. The trapping formation burst into many tiny flames as if it was never there, to begin with. There was no massive torrent of Qi needed to free himself as things like this were already below his level.

“Okay then, we can do this the easy way or the hard way, I don’t really care but in the end all of you will come with me…”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Patreon | Discord

Chapter 659

“How is he doing this? Does he know the secrets of the Azure Shackle formation?”

“H-he is breaking out, we must stop him, concentrate before he is free, we can’t let him escape!”

The group of elders stretched their hands out along with a few supportive core formation experts on the side. They all infused their spiritual energy into the trap that they prepared for their greatest enemy. This was a once-in-a-lifetime chance of taking care of their biggest problem. Without the Golden Dragon around their dynasty could not be questioned and the status quo would remain.

To protect the longevity of their clan they were ready to kill anyone that got in their way but today they would have a rude awakening. Even though they strained with all of their might the shackles keeping their enemy at bay started dissolving. It was as if he knew the weakness of this formation that had been specifically created to suppress powerful cultivators.

“Just give up, this won’t work on me, surrender and I will promise not to kill you.”

“You want us to give up, preposterous!”

One of the elders called their soul beast to his aid. It looked like a massive bear made of some sort of earth-aligned Qi. It tossed itself at Zhang Dong that was just standing there with his arms crossed over one another. All the other elders did the same, massive legendary animals started popping up everywhere made out of different elemental energies. They all quickly tossed themselves at the white-haired man who didn’t seem to perturbed by the gesture.

“I guess I’ll have to be more convincing, such things won’t work on me…”

Without even moving or raising his arms he produced a spike of spiritual energy before him. It was a wide-area attack that targeted everything in the vicinity. Right when it collided with a large number of soul beasts, all of them were instantly eradicated. This of course caused a backlash to the owners that started coughing up blood in mid-air.

“W-what’s with this power… is he really the Emperor’s equal?”

Long Yingjie, who didn’t call up his soul beast for help, was stunned. He was preparing his own contingency but after seeing how much power Zhang Dong could wield it became clear. There was no way this group that he procured to win against this man, there were just not enough elders gathered here for a powerful combination attack. Without the trapping formation, they couldn’t suppress Zhang Dong enough for a critical blow to land.

“The Emperor’s equal? I’m not sure if he is my equal.”

“That’s absurd how could someone so young eclipse the Azure Emperor, this doesn’t make any sense… h-he must have used some trick…”

“It’s no trick, he is truly powerful too powerful, he must not confront the Emperor.”

“Grand Elder?”

Long Yingjie gave out a sigh while lowering his hands. Zhang Dong looked at the man as if he expected him to surrender. The old man had realized that opposing him was worthless, anything they threw at him would not work.

“I see that you realized it.”

“It is as you say, we can not oppose you, the rumors were not exaggerated. To think that someone so young could be this powerful…”

To these people, it was an unfathomable amount of power resting in the fingers of such a youth. Zhang Dong was in his early forties now, this was usually the moment when people just entered the core formation stage. He on the other hand had already reached the pinnacle of power and could potentially eclipse all the experts that came before him, including the Azure Emperor.

“What are you saying Grand Elder, this was your idea! Do you want us to surrender to the pretender?”

He remained standing in his spot while sometimes glancing at Zhang Jin. His body had managed to get healed by the holy pillar of light. The defensive measure was now quickly weakening so he wanted to get this over with. If it continued for too long then he might have to retreat. It was possible for these people to use the surviving members of his sect as shields before trying to escape.

“If you understand then surrender.”

“We will not surrender to the likes of you! Isn’t that right Grand Elder Long Yingjie?”

The nascent soul masters looked to their leader for support. Probably if the man told them to give up they would listen to them. If he could get this over without any more bloodshed then it was fine. They were inside a large city with millions of people around them. If multiple nascent soul masters started blasting away and causing a ruckus thousands of them could die.

Even though this was not his city, they were not part of this entrapment. He was aware that everyone feared the Long Clan, it was ingrained into their very souls. This dynasty had lasted for hundreds of thousands of years and no one had any reason to believe that it would end now.

The people that were here would be tried and stripped of their cultivation base. They had killed members of his sect and needed to be held responsible for it. Even if this would create friction with the Long Clan, they were the ones to start it.

“Surrender? No, we will not surrender…”

“Huh? I thought you’d be the reasonable one, save yourself some face in front of your juniors and come quietly, I’ll even promise to leave them be.”

“That is truly a magnanimous offer but I will have to refuse. You are too dangerous to be left alive and for this reason… I must apologize to all of you, my brothers and sisters…”

“What are you?”

“You don’t mean? Please Grand Elder reconsider!”

“This is for the dynasty, it must survive and this man can not leave here alive, please understand.”

Zhang Dong, who was just standing there like a pillar, was confused about the conversation. It was as if they had some sort of trump card but he didn’t notice anything powerful enough to take him out. However, in his attempt to reduce bloodshed, he had miscalculated just how crazy about their prestige these people were. When he realized what the Grand Elder here was planning, it was already too late.

“You… Do you intend to take the city with you?”

“The Long Clan must survive! Let it be known, Long Dong had conspired with the Demonic beings in an attempt to usurp the throne, in a fit of rage he decided to destroy this city with all its inhabitants!”

Long Yingjie shouted out while pointing at the ground. It was as if he was sending a message about how to resolve this issue when people started asking questions. Even if Zhang Dong survived he would be branded as a demonic cultivator that destroyed a whole city by himself. It was a clear attempt of swaying public opinion against his newly created image. Some would believe it, others would not but as long as some doubt existed the Long Clan would be able to retain their prestige.

“You madman, stop!”

Even though his cultivation base roared he was a second too late. The cascading effect that had been triggered by Long Yingjie could not be stopped. Strange letters started appearing under them which triggered a reaction in all directions. The grand formation that was used to protect the city from harm was given an order, one of self-destruction.

In the distance, citizens of the city gazed at a large blue pillar of light shooting up into the sky. Tiny particles of light started gathering everywhere as this energy wave pushed itself in all directions. Before they could even muster a scream they were all engulfed by this massive explosion of spiritual energy. Everything turned to white and soon their consciousness faded as they were all burned to ashes.

The earth rumbled and the heavens trembled. The energy pillar reached the skies and parted the clouds. Hurricane-level winds descended on the entirety of this place while people tried to flee. Even the ones that were outside the city were scorched by the massive amounts of charred air and energy. The lucky ones that found themselves on flying vessels could only quickly evacuate while looking at the event with horror in their eyes.

‘These maniacs really did it…’

Zhang Dong found himself in the middle of the torrent of energy. In his hands was Zhang Jin and to the sides were four surviving members from the party that arrived at this location. All of them were shielded by his energies and remained uninjured.

‘He had to know that this wouldn’t kill me… this was all just to give them an excuse…’

As the light subsided he saw nothing more than rubble remaining. The nascent soul elders that were just floating in the air had turned into bones with most of their skeletons missing. Even their nascent divinities had been damaged and erased in the blast. However this was not what he was concerned with as his gaze peeked further.

The Azure Basin City was no more and all of those pools filled with water were nothing more than steam. He could not feel anything, the only people that were alive were the six remaining here. Zhang Dong could not understand how a person could do such a thing. Long Yingjie was offered mercy but he chose strife instead. With this event being skewed by the Long Clan this would mean war.

‘If this is how the Long Clan handles things… then perhaps it’s better if they stop existing…’

In the distance, he could see nothing more than dust-filled streets where millions of people once lived. The buildings had been blown to nothingness and not even the bodies of the citizens remained. A rage was building up in his gut and he didn’t know who to aim it at.

The whole city had been rigged to explode from the start. There must have been such a function inside of this protective formation. Without it, Long Yingjie would not have been able to activate it as fast. This meant that any of the other large cities in the Central Empire were potential nukes just waiting to explode.

‘I can’t let this go on but I’m not really ready to face that woman yet…’

With his grandfather in hand, he raised himself up into the air. In the distance, he could see a tingling of light. It was a reflection coming from the golden cruiser that Zhang Jin arrived in. The ship was fast enough to escape from the predicament after he quickly informed them to fly away. Now what remained was to ask his grandfather some questions as his brows were starting to tingle.

‘I need to get some answers and then make a decision…’

Chapter 660

“So that’s what happened?”

“Yes, I made a grave error…”

“It’s not your fault gramps, who could have expected the Long Clan to plot something like this.”

“I should have known that something was fishy after they delayed me so much.”

“They sure did their homework to keep you there… when will you grow up?”

“Hoho, can’t blame an old man for having some fun!”

“Sure I can!”

Zhang Jin gave out a sigh as he explained what had transpired after his arrival at Azure Basin City. After reaching the large castle he was escorted into a fine room and given some entertainment. This consisted of a group of beautiful women tending to all of his needs. It was obvious that while he was having fun people were working in the background to set up a trap for Zhang Dong.

‘Did they expect me to teleport there by myself? I guess my movements have become a bit obvious…’

It was possible that they took a shot in the dark. He was known for appearing out of the blue whenever his family members were involved. With strange powerful treasures existing everywhere, it was very probable for Zhang Jin of having some type of beacon to tell him his location. If he didn’t arrive alone they would have probably switched to a different ploy to get their way. Blowing up the city might have been that and would certainly take out almost everyone from his sect.

“Nevermind that, we need to get to the bottom of this.”

“Yes, what are those Long Clan bastards planning? If they decided to go this far, they might already have an army ready for deployment.”

“That could be true but I’m not sure if my ‘older brother’ had anything to do with it. The way that Grand Elder spoke about it, it seemed as if he was doing it on his own accord.”

“Could it be another faction within the Long Clan?”

“That’s a possibility and with this, we might have given them an excuse to hook in all the other factions from their clan.”

The Long Clan was as large as any sect and also had many branches all around the central region. In name, they were one entity ruled over by their Azure Emperor but in reality, they were divided just as any other large organization. It was the same with the United Element Sect who started out with three separate factions like the Zhang, Huo, and Feng Clans.

This event could give the faction that faked the events a reason to dirty his name. Long Yingjie during his last moments implied that Zhang Dong was part of a demonic sect. Orthodox cultivators that were on the surface just could use that as an excuse to attack. It wouldn’t be strange if they went even further than that and tried to pin all the atrocities that happened during this war on him.

“Yes… I’m sorry Dong’er this is all my fault, I knew that I was dealing with the Long Clan.”

“It’s fine, you couldn’t have known that they would go to such an extreme after such a long period of silence.”

He couldn’t really blame his grandfather for all of this. There were many ways for the Long Clan to find a justifiable cause for a counter-attack. It was known that Zhang Dong and his sect had already cleared out the northern demonic island. They were in the process of turning that place into something new and that was enough cause. The Long Clan didn’t necessarily need to get the people on their side but it would look better on their record. If they managed to win the new war then this would probably become the truth.

“We need to inform everyone, send an order to move closer to our teleportation gates.”

“Yes, Patriarch.”

At the moment both Zhang Jin and Zhang Dong were flying through the air in the golden cruiser. With his help, he was able to move it faster and they would arrive at the nearest gate to get back to the sect soon. Everyone needed to get informed about the new ploy, it was possible for a push from the Long Clan to occur at any moment. While it was not probable there could have been a force created to attack the cities bordering the central regions already. It was best to have his sect members retreat as they didn’t really have any high value besides the spirit points they generated.

‘So they intend to push into a new scenario where the ally becomes the new enemy…’

Zhang Dong expected something like this to happen after the war between Empires ended prematurely. He had control of all the bridges and no one could enter these lands anymore. He hoped that by not clearing out Argu and his people he would be granted at least a hundred years of peace. It was like saving one boss for later without having the plot advance further.

‘Not everything is lost though, the Long Clan is more of a defensive superpower, they might be unable to muster up the forces to push into our lands.’

From what he knew, the Long Clan had quite a stronghold in the middle of the empire. The playing city he visited had a defensive formation that even he wouldn’t be able to break through. Attacking them would not be easy and they had several strongholds down on the ground to make things a lot more difficult. Yet unless they decided to move that flying city out of the region they were entrenched in, he couldn’t see them posing that much of a threat. While their relations had perhaps been soured by this event, it might not lead to an all-out war just yet.

Thus along with Zhang Jin he finally reached the closest teleporter and got everyone home. When arriving back at the sect he showed off the recording of Long Yingjie’s last words that he made sure to save as evidence. While the Long Clan would deny those claims it didn’t really matter. They just needed to push their own narrative to get people to believe in their cause. If they didn’t defend themselves against the claims then their morale would plummet.

…

“The Golden Dragon is a fake and a demonic cultivator, this all makes sense, why would such atrocities suddenly befall our peaceful empire, we must stand with the Azure Emperor and defeat this villain!”

“What nonsense, the Azure Emperor is a coward. He remained in his little castle build on everyone's labor and left everyone to die! The only reason my sister is alive is thanks to the Golden Dragon, he should be the Emperor… no he is the real Emperor of this Empire!”

“How dare you!”

“I dare!”

A fight between cultivators erupted in a restaurant. Scenes like this played out throughout the whole empire after the news was dropped. People were on the fence and didn’t know who to believe in. On one side was the old Azure dynasty that survived through hundreds and thousands of years. They were the one firm pillar that allowed this Empire to survive to this day.

On the other was the United Element sect and the Emperor of the West. When people needed someone to save them, he arrived. Some saw him as the dawn of change and the new rightful owner who actually cherished their wellbeing. They denied all rumors about the demi-human attack being orchestrated by the United Elements sect. To a lot, this new upstart sect had been a beacon of light in the darkness of night.

Quickly factions were being created and sides were being joined. Back at a large auditorium a group of elders along with their leader Zhang Dong were analyzing all the data they received in the past month.

“This is surprising.”

“Is it my husband?”

“Yes, I expected a lot more people to take the Azure Emperor’s side than this.”

Zhang Liena smiled while watching the large map on the interactive screen. There as always, puddles of red were used as mapping points. Most of the Western region was covered in green and blue coloring to represent people that were on their side. Green with their support being massive and then switching to blue to areas that were more on the neutral side.

“Everyone knows that our Patriarch is magnanimous, no one with an inkling of intelligence would believe in that nonsense the Long Clan is pushing!”

“That’s right, the people aren’t dumb, they know that we are not with the demonic sects.”

Zhang Dong nodded while looking at the patch of red in the middle of the Empire. The concentration was quite high there. People were moving to their border cities in hopes of being on the winning side. To a lot the old Dynasty was a dragon that could never be beaten. Even if they disliked the way they acted, there was no way of competing with the strongest.

When it came to the Eastern region where the Heavenly Crane Sect resided things were a lot more colorful. There were dots and regions of orange, red, and magenta. Others were lime green, blue, and sapphire. It was clear that they were divided in an almost identical way and would probably stay away from the battle between the two.

Zhang Dong had no plans of getting the East regions involved and hoped that they would remain neutral for the entirety of this fight. The people that he had aided in the fight against the Emerald Phoenix Emperor were still grateful and delivered some aid in the form of cultivation resources. All of those were delivered through hidden means so that the Long Clan wouldn’t be aware of it.

“Has there been any movement from the Long Clan?”

“They have occupied the borders and destroyed many of the automatons that attempted to move in closer. We have managed to assemble a perimeter and transferred some of our manpower to counter any potential assaults.”

“Hm…”

He nodded while looking at the map. There was no immediate attack coming after the predicament at Azure Basin City. Everything had been somewhat anti-climatic and they had enough time to set up a defensive parameter on the borders. Even though the Long Clan forces had gathered together, they weren’t really attacking, just staying in their own region as if they were not allowed to leave it.

‘Could this be some type of limiting factor in their setting or are they planning something?’

There was no way of knowing but a decision had to be made. Was it better to just get this over with and move in or give his enemy time to strategize? There was a lot of things about the Long Clan that he didn’t know and perhaps twiddling his thumbs while they got ready for an offensive was not the best…

Chapter 661

‘It doesn’t seem like this will turn into a cold war of attrition. I could have probably waited this out until the last moment…’

Zhang Dong was looking at the map of the Empire. All the red blobs that were previously there were now non-existent. His previous advantage over the other Empires could not be used against the Long Clan. The map he copied from their city was not created to follow their movements. Without knowing where his new enemies were it was a lot harder to prepare counterstrategies.

For a moment before the Long Clan started advancing, he hoped for a stalemate. His older brother wasn’t the youngest. Even though he looked like a young man, he was several hundred years of age. Considering the gap in age of around one thousand years, it would have been possible to just wait until he became a decrepit old man. It would probably be a lot easier to face the Emperor when he wasn’t in his prime. Then his replacement, who was one of his sons, would probably be somewhat weaker in comparison.

He didn’t really care about owning the whole empire as he needed to look at the bigger picture. The Long Clan wasn’t his true opponent, that was the Overseer lady that was the Emperor’s wife. If they could stall this out his forces would slowly overwhelm the Long Clan’s as there was something that he had that they didn’t.

This was of course his system and the constant supply of spirit points. With the help of those points, he would be able to bolster his forces. Numerous amounts of nascent soul masters had already ascended thanks to these spirit points and his faction system. If he was allowed to wait for a hundred years, overwhelming the Long Clan with sheer numbers of nascent soul masters would have been an easy task. There would be no way of stopping their advance and that would be it.

‘Could they know something about that? They probably don’t know about the system but perhaps think that I have some type of treasure that does the task for me. It wouldn’t be wrong for them to conclude that they need to strike now or perish in the future… I guess that makes sense.’

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh of indignation. His daughter was about to turn eleven and the new war had just started. He hoped for at least ten more years of peace until his children went through puberty and became somewhat competent fighters. While he wouldn’t integrate them into the army they would at least have enough power to run away.

‘We might have spread out too much into the western region, this won’t be as easy as the other Empires.’

When looking at the map he could see some points where the battle had started. Some of the elders like Huo Qiang were already at the main front. The biggest problem was the vastness of the border region. Now that his sect was the de facto owner of the lands they should be the ones to defend them. However, this became problematic as they needed to thin out their forces without being able to gain much ground.

Small skirmishes between groups of cultivators soon erupted. The Long Clan won some while his others. It was surprising that both sides were this equal. Considering this reveal, if this group had decided to help out during the other battles, the Azure Empire would have easily been able to defend their lands and people.

‘They are claiming that we started the wars ourselves, nice excuse.’

The premise was simple, the Long Clan claimed that he was trying to take away the mantle of the emperor from his brother. The fights that were created were part of the ploy of destroying the Soaring Dragon Sect that was the previous ruler. They even claimed that Wang Long was working together with them from the start. Then after the deed was done they went north to silence him along with the demonic cultivators. Afterward, it was as easy as just disguising their sect members as demi-humans to cause chaos throughout the lends.

‘This doesn’t explain the state of things in the east but not like the Heavenly Crane Sect will decide on anything with that council of theirs. As long as they continue to remain neutral it's fine.’

His new friends weren’t willing to help either side which was understandable. The Long Clan wouldn’t pursue their borders as long as they didn’t aid their new enemies. This didn’t mean that he wasn’t getting a little bit of help from this sect. Their borders were right on the other side. Even though they presented themselves as natural forces, the Long Clan couldn’t just ignore them.

They needed to post some of their masters on that side as a safety measure. The borders needed to at least last out for a few weeks if for some reason they decided to attack. There was no real trust between cultivators, might was all that mattered and they knew this. The moment the Heavenly Crane Sect saw an opening it wouldn’t be strange for them to push to gain more lands and resources. Just like any other sect or clan, they wanted to rule over all to gain access to all of the cultivation resources this world had.

To counter the claim that his sect were demonic cultivators hell-bent on world domination they spread their own agenda. It was more or less the truth, they presented the Emperor as weak and too scared to battle for the western regions that had been partially destroyed. His sect painted them as opportunists that wanted to gain all the glory after everything was already resolved. The only reason they wanted to attack was the growth of the United Element Sect which was threatening their dynasty.

‘I think most people realize what it’s all about but their fear of the Azure Emperor is very real. Only if we can show that we are truly able to stand up to them, will the people follow without fear.’

The Long Clan was an old monster that had lasted through ages long past. To a lot of people, this clan was the Azure Empire. It had existed for so long that no one could imagine them not existing forever. Forces like the Soaring Dragon Sect and the Heavenly Crane Sect weren’t ones that lasted. Sooner or later they always deteriorated and were taken over by another faction. To many people, the United Element Sect was just like them, with time their spark would die down and only the Long Clan would remain.

‘I guess we’ll have to prove that we are here to stay.’

For the time being he needed to remain home as his forces took care of everything else. As the leader, it was better for him to only appear when the Azure Emperor decided to strike. Otherwise, there was a possibility of him getting lured into another trap. Long Qing was a more fearsome opponent than the grand elder, the fight might not be as easy.

‘It’s possible that he never showed me his true capabilities back at the city, even though in theory I should be stronger now, I can’t discount that Overseer…’

Zhang Dong would have loved to just ask his older brother for a duel to clear things out. His clan would probably ignore the challenge while giving some type of excuse of them trying to set up some sort of trap. A battle between leaders would have been the best and least bloody solution to the problem. Yet, after what the Long Clan had attempted he couldn’t really trust them anymore.

‘They would probably only accept if the competition was held within their borders, then they will just try to entrap me in some type of formation or just outright attack me with multiple people at once.’

After having a good chuckle he decided to sit himself down in the cultivation room he was using. Contemplating the Dao of time was still coming along slowly and combining the elements wasn’t getting anywhere. Only thanks to Bob was he actually able to grasp some of it and this was somewhat of a problem. Relying on the hacked system might prove to be his downfall.

‘I need to get a grasp of the logic behind it, if that being created the original system then perhaps it could disable mine…’

There were a few possibilities for the confrontation in the future and he needed to account for all of them. He saw two possibilities, either try to make the system that he was given something that couldn’t be removed or go above it and become a true immortal being of unfathomable power. The problem was that he didn’t really have an idea how he should do either of those.

‘The only thing I can think of… would be binding Bob to my soul but he already should be.’

The Ai was freed when he first escaped from this world. At that time he was nothing more than a soul without a proper fleshy body. It was possible that Bob had already integrated itself into his soul and was a part of it. It was possible that his system had become part of everything but it was also something created by a mysterious being.

This brought several questions up to the forefront that he didn’t have an answer for. Perhaps only after discovering more about the truths of this world would he be finally able to grasp it all. Firstly he needed to take care of the Long Clan problem. Even if he defeated the Azure Emperor and become the new leader, the Overseer might not get triggered.

‘Well then, time to oversee a brand new war… or at least that's what everyone else will think.’

Everyone from his sect was in agreement that the Patriarch should not involve himself in the fighting unless the Azure Emperor appeared. They all wanted to show that they could handle things without his supervision. While he understood the sentiment he did not want more of his people to die.

‘Hiring mercenaries and solo cultivators is also getting prepared… I guess it’s time to join my own army as an outsider, this might be interesting.’

His face started changing into an old man with a nice gray beard and hair to fit. His robe started shifting into something black and gruff. His handsome face was replaced by one covered in many scars to fill the role of masterful warrior.

“It’s time for the demon hunter to appear again!”

Chapter 662

“Master Lei Yinglo, the elders will see you now.”

“Mhm.”

A rough-looking man dressed in a dark robe nodded at the lady that greeted him. The woman’s eyes focused on his face which had a lot of scarred tissue. It was as if he was mauled by some beast and barely came out on top. There were ways of removing such wounds but perhaps the injuries were done by a ferocious demonic being which would hinder healing.

“Good day, Demon hunter Lei Yinglo, your reputation precedes you…”

“Is there a problem?”

The man was led into a smaller chamber where five elders were waiting. Four of them were at the early stage of the nascent soul level but the one in the middle was a lot stronger. His demeanor was cold and for some reason, he didn’t seem to favor the man that just entered through the door.

“You might not recall it but I was there when you faced off against our Patriarch… you seem to have gotten stronger since then.”

“Is that so? I feel we resolved that dispute a long time ago.”

The scared man tried not to react to the question too much but on the inside, he was in a state of slight panic. Lei Yinglo was Zhang Dong’s alter ego, a famous demon hunter that once traveled through the lower regions to help him gain resources without involving his clan. His notoriety among the smaller clans was something real but after ascending to the nascent soul level, he didn’t really use this name much.

‘Why is Zhang Zhi here, wasn’t someone else doing the interview? Should I inform him about this… but those four elders might find it odd…’

Zhang Dong found himself in a job interview for his own sect. The war for the Empire had started and a decision was made to recruit people from the outside. Integrating people from clans or sects from the outside was normal. The Long Clan was doing the same thing and offering the cultivators resources for their help. It was a big chance for them to be accepted as an outer elder or disciple of a large superpower.

To not make it too obvious Zhang Dong decided to hide his true identity. Some people were aware of this persona’s real identity but it didn’t really matter. This was just to let him participate out on the field without his identity being known to the enemy. His aids weren’t totally against it as long as everyone thought that he was back at the sect and ready, it was fine.

The danger of him hanging around the battlegrounds came from giving away his true position. His enemies would certainly send out a powerful force to take him down if his position was exposed. While he was confident in defeating everyone besides the Overseer, he was not invincible. There was also a possibility of some immortal-level weapons being in the hands of the Long Clan. If a trump card like that was ever used, then even his slightly above nascent soul level power wouldn’t help him.

To remedy this problem he initiated a new scheme. The council of elders brought up the issue of the Long Clan recruitment drive and he sanctioned it all. Now his people were allowing masters from the whole empire to come to them and fight with them. While there was usually a chance of a spy making their way in, thanks to his faction system it could be seen through. Already they had a handful of pretenders rotting in the dungeon for attempting this feat.

‘Well, not like I’ll fail the check.’

“Senior Zhi, is there a problem with Master Lei Yinglo? Our records show that he is a reputable senior who had lived to fight demons.”

“Reputable? A man that sells his sword for money.”

“S-senior Zhi?”

One of the side elders started panicking as he was looking between Zhang Dong in his disguise and Zhang Zhi. In the past, his demon-hunter persona partook in a little squabble against himself. The recollection of the scene was something that could make him blush. Back then he pretended to have a battle with Lei Yinglo that ended in a stalemate. Zhi was his biggest fanboy and was there during the confrontation. He probably felt a certain way when confronting the man that raised his weapon against his leader.

“Please Master, Yinglo place your hand on the measuring device.”

“This orb? What does it do?”

“It will measure your aptitude for battle, it’s a simple Qi measuring device.”

This was of course a big fat lie. The orb had a connection to the system and could measure a person’s natural alignment. It would present the elders with a page with his stats as well as his alliance. If he was a member of a demonic sect or the Long Clan would also show up. The people that were untrustworthy or too weak had two fates. They would either get kicked out or be led to a room with a trapping formation. After getting suppressed they would end up at the correctional facility. There they would be interrogated to reveal their secrets.

“If it’s just for that…”

His hand landed on the device that was connected to his own system. Before anything appeared for this group of elders he was able to alter everything. What would normally show his true name of Zhang Dong and position of Patriarch was changed.

Name:

|

Lei Yinglo

Cultivation Level:

|

Nascent Soul (Great Circle)

Faction:

|

None

Alignment:

|

True Neutral

Power Rating:

|

S

Main Weapon:

|

Sword

Animosity Rating:

|

Neutral

Risk of betrayal:

|

Very Low

It was a bit more basic compared to what he could see himself but it gave the people an idea of where his alliance lay. This was what he was aiming for, to seem like someone that was more neutral in his approach. From the statistics, they could see that he was not part of the Long Clan and not part of any faction either. That was his persona, a sellsword with some values. The risk of betraying them implied that he wouldn’t go against the people that hired him and stayed true to the contract. This coupled with his power rating of S, his employment was guaranteed.

‘Do you see this brothers… I haven’t seen such high numbers on any of the other participants

‘This man… he will be a great asset to our army and the whole sect, we should recruit him before he wanders over to the Long Clan… this is a chance!’

‘What you say is true but what does senior brother Zhi think?’

‘I don’t trust him fully but the device was made by the Patriarch and was never wrong before…’

‘You speak the truth senior Zhi, this is a big chance!’

If they knew that their Patriarch was listening to their hidden conversation they would probably lay an egg. It was clear that he would be a strong ally but also a ferocious enemy. He made his neutrality obvious which would push them to make a decision faster. Someone with these kinds of stats could potentially go to their enemy if they denied his involvement.

“We have made a decision.”

“You have? This fast?”

“Indeed, for such an expert like yourself, the decision is obvious, we welcome you within the ranks of the United Element’s sect.”

While Zhang Zhi remained seated the other elders began to stand up and talk. All of them had access to the faction rating system to an extent so they knew that a Power Rating of S was not a simple feat. That he was a nascent soul master at the great circle stage also added to his prestige. To these early-stage masters, this was something that was commendable. All of them hoped to reach this stage one day and become pillars for their sect.

“I see…”

“Please come this way, one of the juniors will escort you to your new accommodations and explain everything in detail. They will present you with the proper paperwork as well.”

“Then I shall excuse myself.”

Finally, after getting stared down by Zhang Zhi he was able to leave this testing chamber. While other participants didn’t know, this chamber connected to a separate location through a hidden teleportation gate. Once a person stepped through they were far outside the sect's premises. It was a safety measure that would guarantee the safety of the juniors and regular city residents. Even if a fight broke out and the chamber was destroyed it would not injure anyone that wasn’t involved.

‘I’m lucky to be a nascent soul master, the others will be judged in a harsher manner.’

When outside he found himself in a corridor that led to his temporary quarters. A good-looking woman guided him towards them while he peeked through the walls where some of the tests continued. He could feel some of the core formation experts and foundation establishment juniors giving their best. Only if they proved themselves to have the minimum required strength for their position would they be accepted just like he was.

Stats and systems were a fine way to get a general idea of a person’s capabilities but they weren’t everything. Only when going through hard tasks that pushed a person to their limits would their true character emerge. They needed to pit people against ferocious beasts to see if they wouldn’t crumble under pressure. Some of the candidates had the assumption of this being an easy gig. They just wanted to reach a new level with the help of an established sect without putting in the proper work.

He couldn’t really fault them for their reasons but he couldn’t accept people like that either. Where people could die from a mistake or due to a cowardly decision, he needed to minimize the window of mistakes. While he was asking people to potentially die for his sect, they were given a chance to walk away. Only after they finally chose to join up this choice would be taken away as they were now part of their army.

‘Hm… this isn’t bad… They really gave me the VVIP suite.’

Finally, he had joined up and now needed to wait for his first assignment. Soon someone would walk through that large door to take him to his first mission. Even though he was the Patriarch he had no idea what that mission would be nor did he have a reason to affect the outcome. It was now up to his people to show him how they progressed through the years and show that they could survive without him making all the decisions for them.

Chapter 663

“Get your asses into gear, the new elder will be arriving soon, if you don’t want to be doing laps for the rest of the day, you better be on your best behavior.”

“But Senior sister Fei, we are always on our best behavior!”

“That we are.”

“I don’t want to hear that from you Yang Rong, if I catch you sneaking into the junior sister’s side again, I’ll lob off those jewels of yours.”

“No, anything but that Senior sister Fei, I’ll be sure to behave.”

“You better, I might have been lenient with you but this elder isn’t part of the sect, he might not be as pleasant.”

“Uh… I can take thousands of beatings from you Senior sister but it loses meaning if the beatings are coming from some old man…”

“What did you say?”

“Oh… nothing Senior Sister!”

The group of young cultivators laughed while watching Yang Rong getting bonked on the head by an angry-looking Senior sister Fei. Their group was composed of people that didn’t originally belong to the United Element sect but had all integrated through the first recruitment drive. They had finished all of the basic training and were now part of the army that would set out to one of the border regions.

Their group was composed of many foundation establishment practitioners that numbered in the hundreds. They were divided into smaller squads of around twenty people with one senior core formation expert leading them. This group was the same and Lan Fei here was the leader of these dysfunctional individuals.

“Haha, Len Fei you need to learn to control your juniors, what if we get punished by the elder for your sloppy squadron?”

“It won’t happen, Senior Teng…”

“I hope it won’t!”

‘Why did I get stuck with this idiot again? Am I cursed or something, did that weird guy put something on me that one time?’

The woman recalled a moment from the past when she was kidnaped by a strange demonic cultivator. That time her life was at risk as the weirdo was performing some strange ritual. Her life was spared by a certain individual that she kept buried in her heart. After this event, she joined up with this powerful sect and managed to even reach the core formation stage.

At this stage in her life, it was possible to create her own clan or help out her father. However, there was no reason to leave this sect. Her power continued to increase and the more merits she gained, so did her position. At the moment she was considered to be an outer disciple with senior privileges.

To change her fate and prove once and for all that she was worthy, the decision to join the war had been made. The recruitment drive was very appealing and the risks weren’t that high. Some people might have not known but she knew how overprotective the Patriarch of this sect was. The places where her group would be sent would probably be easily tamable.

‘I will become an inner sect disciple and then elder, then I need to join one of the great clans to solidify my position…’

This was her thought process. Her beauty was well known and she had many suitors through which she could progress even faster. Yet she wanted to prove that she had enough talent to make it on her own. Thanks to the merits system a person could join the inner sect and integrate into one of the three great clans. The best fit for her was the Feng clan but considering that it was led by the Matriarch, she wasn’t sure if she shouldn’t go with another choice.

‘I shouldn’t get ahead of myself, this could take a few years but afterward, it’s smooth sailing for me! I’ll get a few cute disciples and live a happy life.’

She tried smiling at the person that scolded her for not keeping her people in check. The person was called Zhang Teng and was part of one of the great clans. It was the strongest faction with their Patriarch being the leader of their entire sect. This man with a face of a snake was not someone that she liked. First of all, it seemed that he had a stick up his ass with how properly he conducted himself.

Then there were the swarms of Feng Clan women around him that always gave her death glares. Even now his entire group was composed of young and beautiful women. She didn’t know what she did to get into this position but as long as she lasted through this war then her time would come. Without having any family backing she needed to depend on her own capabilities.

“All of you gather up, the new elder is coming!”

“The new elder, do you know who he is?”

“Yes, listen to this, apparently he was a famous demon hunter in the past.”

“A demon hunter? Was he a mercenary?”

“It seems so.”

The reaction was mild, the people here started frowning as they realized that their leader was from outside the clan. An elder that didn’t have any family or sect was always suspicious. That he was forced to work as a sellsword said a few things about his character. In short, he didn’t work well with others, either through being a lone wolf or through character flaws that made him into a bad leader. Now they were stuck with a person like that, their future didn’t look good.

“Damn… why couldn’t we have gotten someone like Elder Zhi…”

“Why would he take in outer disciples like us, it was a given that we would get the dregs of the sect.”

“Hey be quiet, what if that elder hears you and decides to discipline us all…”

“Stop talking and get into formation!”

Zhang Teng shouted out which made everyone quiet down. Even though he was also only a squadron leader there was a proper pecking order for everyone. Lan Fei along with all the other leaders needed to listen to this man. Everyone took up their positions and waited for the elder to arrive. Finally, after around ten minutes the man of the hour arrived along with another nascent soul master that some of the people here were accustomed to.

“Greetings juniors, I won’t take up much of your time. Let me introduce you all to Elder Lei Yinglo, he will be the leader of this company of troops. I expect everyone to show him the proper respect.”

“Yes, Elder!”

Everyone clasped their hands while bowing, everyone except one person that was Lan Fei. Her eyes started bulging out the moment she saw that scared-up face. Was this some type of joke that the man there was trying to pull on her? It didn’t seem that anyone really knew who he was but she remembered him from the past.

‘Is it really him? Why would he hide his presence in the sect? Or… could this be the real demon hunter?’

Lan Fei recalled the white-haired man that saved her all those years before. He had revealed that Lei Yinglo was a persona that he was using. The man was able to alter his appearance so she didn’t really know what he looked like. It was possible that the man called Zhang Dong was a lot older than anyone expected. Yet the shines that he presented during that one steamy night, was not something an experienced man would be capable off.

“Senior Sister, you are staring.”

“Uh, I…”

She was poked from the side by one of her squad members that noticed that she wasn’t doing her bow properly. Even the other leaders were starting to side-eye her. All sorts of questions were going through her head now. She wanted to do nothing more than shout out his real name to see if he was really the man she knew before. Even after spending many years in this sect, there was never a time when he looked her way. Could this be some type of coincidence or was there more to it?

……

‘She is looking at me…’

Zhang Dong had gone through with his secret mission. His demon-hunter persona had been assigned to mostly a company composed of outer sect disciples. There were only a few members from the inner sect like Zhang Teng here. The plan was to join such a group where his presence was not that known, the plan was perfect but an unforeseen variable appeared.

Lan Fei, a woman that he had a fling with and the person that took his first time. He had almost forgotten of her existence in the sect that she joined almost the moment it was created. This wouldn’t really be much of a problem at all if he had decided to create a whole new image for himself.

His choice of going with Lei Yinglo was due to his notoriety. People from the Zhang Clan knew his exploits and this heightened the chances of him getting included in the war effort. There was one problem, the one person that knew his identity was here and this was Lan Fei. Even now he could see her trying to glance his way, she had clearly remembered this scar-covered face that was just a disguise.

‘Well, this certainly complicates things… I didn’t even know she was taking part in this mission.’

A patriarch didn’t really look down that much. There was no way for him to keep track of all the people from his sect. While he had the faction system this didn’t give him insights into every person in the sect. It was more of a generalized tool that allowed him to farm some spirit points and call it up for help here and there.

‘I can’t let Liena know of this… she might get a stupid idea…’

Going on a secret mission with an old girlfriend was quite suspicious. He was disguising himself while pretending to be in secluded training. If his wife noticed that he was gone on a mission it would already be bad enough, but his life would be at risk if she thought that he was cheating on her.

‘I need to calm down… I’m the Patriarch, I’ll just ignore her…’

There wasn’t much that he could do now. After arriving here with one of the other nascent soul elders he was given the reins to the company. They would all be soon sent out through the teleportation gate for their first assignment. The details of the mission were already known to him, a search and rescue.

‘I can’t worry about things like this when lives are at stake…’

He nodded while trying to evade the piercing gaze the woman was giving him. It was clear that she wanted to ask him a lot of questions but he wasn’t sure if he had the right answers for them. Thus soon their group departed for their first mission and he would again be placed into a tight bind.

Chapter 664

“Elder please let me help you with that…”

“No it’s fine…”

“I insist! We can’t have such a man as yourself tend to such things, leave it up to our squad.”

“Ah… sure…”

‘This girl, she knows… Making my face this ferocious has no meaning if she acts like this.’

Zhang Dong frowned while looking at Lan Fei. She had clearly discovered his true identity and was now pestering him. The other cultivators were far too afraid to say anything to him but she, on the other hand, had no qualms about it. It all started out slowly with her offering to open up the door or hand him something but now, she was making the people from her squad massage his shoulders and even play some music during the trip.

‘Why do we have to be stuck on this ship for so long, when will we reach the next destination?’

‘It will take exactly six hours, twenty-one minutes, and thirty-four seconds to reach the destination.’

‘Thanks, Bob, I forgot that you were there.’

After the introduction to this group of people, he was taken to a large ship. This company consisted of close to two hundred people, twelve of them were core formation experts and the rest were foundation establishment practitioners. Lan Fei was one of the experts that led a small squadron of sixteen people.

He had hoped to ignore the girl after reaching the ship yet his accommodations were different. His presence in the central control room was a requirement. He was to sit on the side and give out orders to the captain who was one of the core formation experts from the other groups. This forced him to stay together with everyone and allowed Lan Fei to bother him with her hijinks.

At first, it was only her but soon the others started crawling up behind. It seemed that they got the wrong idea and interpreted Lan Fei’s actions as a blueprint. Any junior loved to get themselves under the wing of a nascent soul master. Gaining a master like him would have been a way of sending them into the inner sect. Due to him not giving Lan Fei a stern scolding they believed that he actually liked this sort of behavior.

‘The only ones not trying to crawl up my ass are people from the main clans, some of them made it on this mission with me. At least they took my orders to heart, a lot of them were against this, luckily I’ve gained enough trust now.’

Zhang Teng was one of the people from the inner sect. He was even related to one of the new nascent soul elders directly. Normally in any other sect such a person would never be caught around outer sect disciples and elders like here. He was a young master with a bright future and the proper backing to make something of himself. This fact usually gave people in his position an inflated ego, it was what made young masters into what they were, a menace.

To avoid this from repeating in his own sect he gave out an order. People from the inner sect had to interact with the outer sects. He wanted the divide to slowly be closed between these two camps and finally after enough time had passed, it would be time to abolish this system. He hoped to not have any inner, outer, or core disciples and it turned into one unified sect where people of different backgrounds were equal.

“ENOUGH! I do not need my shoulders to be rubbed! I will take a stroll through the ship… you there!”

“Me Elder?”

“Yes you, give me a tour of this vessel. I'm still unfamiliar with the ways of your sect.”

“Of course elder!”

“Is it because of her looks…”

“So lucky, the powerful elder took an interest in Lan Fei.”

He could hear the others whispering around after he singled Lan Fei out from the group. After having to listen to terrible music and puns for a few hours he needed a change of scenery. If this continued he even considered teleporting away and then back when they reached their destination. After getting up from the throne-like chair that he occupied he followed after the woman that was all smiles. The other cultivators looked with longing eyes while thinking that she would be given special treatment.

“Great Elder if you’ll allow me…”

“Just come with me and stop with that way of speaking, its starring to get on my nerves.”

“Ah, if that’s the Elders' wish.”

Lan Fei gave him the nicest smile as if she didn’t know what this was about and followed after. He did not need a tour of this flying ship as he was one of the people that went through the schematics of this model. He knew what all was used for and this was just an excuse to get the woman into a secluded cabin which he soon guided her to.

“We can talk here…”

“Oh my, why did the Elder bring me to this empty cabin… Is it for that reason?”

She gave him a wink while looking at the large bed inside the room. This place was reserved for any potential guests that arrived and kept empty for such an occasion. Before he could start talking the woman gave him a seductive look while trying to get on top of the bed.
“Hey, could you knock it off, I’m not my grandfather and I already know that you know who I am.”

“Was it that obvious?”

“Yes, quite obvious.”

“I have to apologize for my actions, this junior has been rude to the sect’s Patriarch.”

Soon Lan Fei’s tone had changed, her expression became a bit less playful as she removed herself from the bed. It was the usual behavior of a junior around a senior member or at least it looked to be on the surface. Considering how much of a fox this woman was those years in the past, it wouldn’t be strange if she was plotting something.

Maybe she wouldn’t even drop the act if he actually pushed her down on the bed and would have accepted any advances knowing well that he was Zhang Dong, the sect’s Patriarch. She took away his first experience before his wife came into the picture so it wasn’t such an odd trade-off. Becoming a mistress of the sect’s leader wouldn’t have even raised any eyebrows. His grandfather who had multiple wives was proof of it.

He was even asked to take in a few to spread his seed as babies from nascent soul masters were already rare. Considering that it got more and more dangerous for the wife the more children they received, to some this was an obvious resolution. Just get more wives close to his level and sire more children that would probably become the pillars of the future sect.

“It’s fine, I’ll let it slide but try not to do this again, I’ve put on this face for a reason.”

“Oh my, is this mission actually dangerous?”

“Not that I’m aware of…”

Zhang Dong looked at the woman before him. She already knew too much for her own good but salvaging the situation was possible. His main reason to be here was to aid his sect without giving up his true identity. He did not want people tip-toeing around his presence as their big leader. This was the reason for playing a renegade master that didn’t belong here. It was much more probable that they would let something slip if he wasn’t seen as a true member yet.

He still wanted to be in a leadership position though, if something went wrong he needed to be able to take care of the situation. If he pretended to be a foundation establishment junior, there could arise a moment of confusion when he revealed his true power. It was better to not have another nascent soul master undermine his status during a critical situation.

“I assume by your confused face that you wish to know what I’m doing here in this old disguise.”

Lan Fei nodded while trying to produce the largest puppy dog eyes she could. Regretfully what might have worked for the old Zhang Dong who once identified as a person called Matt, was ineffective. After coming to this world he had somewhat decided to ditch his old persona and assimilate with the cultivator called Zhang Dong. While he would never forget about his roots or morals, he needed to change his mindset at least slightly to survive in a world like this.

“Maybe that would have worked on me ten years ago, but I’m not the old me anymore.”

“Haaa… you’re making me doubt my womanly charms.”

“If you are interested, I can introduce you to a certain grandfather of mine, I’m sure he’ll take you under his wing.”

“Elder Zhang Jin? I think I’ll have to refuse, that old man has a very bad reputation with the women in the sect… then there are also his many wives, those women are ferocious… You’re not actually going to send me to him for punishment, are you?”

Lan Fei chuckled while shrugging, her impression of his grandfather wasn’t good and he was aware of that. No good-looking woman in the sect was safe and his wealth had its limits. After he passed on the battle for the assets he left behind would probably be tremendous. Zhang Dong was already scared as he would probably need to take care of his extended family then and not let them kill themselves over cultivation resources.

“Haha, no I was just joking. I wouldn’t give my worst enemy away to that perverted old man… But let’s get back to the problem at hand…”

“My lips are sealed.”

“Good, I guess this could work my… new potential disciple.”

“Potential disciple?”

“Yes… this will be the role that you will play… Don’t worry, it’s just temporary but now that you have figured me out, I’ll have you do some work for your Patriarch.”

Lan Fei wasn’t sure what he meant but she at least seemed happy to work with him. The others already thought that she made a good impression so it worked out for him. She would be his middleman in all of this while he did his thing. Having someone on the inside that acted this casually around him wasn’t that bad…

Chapter 665

“How could senior sister do this, does she have a thing for old ugly men?”

“How about you shut up before Elder Lei Yinglo hears you, do you want to get crippled or something?”

“But… Senior sister Lei Fan… what is she doing with that man, this isn’t normal! He must have cast some kind of demonic technique on our fairy, we must set her free!”

“What do you mean with, our? Stop involving me with your delusions!”

“Ow, how could you hit me!”

Yang Rong held the lump on his head that appeared after his friend, Cheng Yun gave him a smack. Both of them came from the same little village and once were at odds with each other. After being recruited by the United Element sect they fostered somewhat of a bond with each other. Cheng Yun got the short end of the stick with this relationship as his friend usually got himself into trouble. This led him into multiple fights and demerits throughout the ten or so years that they had been in this sect.

“Listen to me Rong, if you go out there, you’re on your own, I’m not getting tossed down from this ship with you!’

“Don’t worry my friend, I won’t cause any trouble!”

Cheng Yun rolled his eyes while looking at his friend sprinting off somewhere. He wasn’t sure how that elder would react but at least Rong’s life should be secure. They were still part of the United Element Sect. The elders of this group were much more lenient than usual, if this Lei Yinglo was allowed to take part in this mission, then he had to be a man of at least some character. Most sect members knew how the recruitment methods worked and it was impossible for a demonic cultivator to become part of their group.

“Oh, Senior sister? I was about to… AGH”

“About to what? Get back in line and finish setting up our camp! You were supposed to be done by now, what were you all doing?”

Lan Fei appeared from behind a tree to deliver a kick to Yang Rong’s shin. The young man winced in pain and instantly dropped down to the ground. Even though tears were rolling down his eyes he seemed rather content after receiving the hit. Cheng Yun recoiled in disgust as his old friend had gained some weird tastes throughout the years. It seemed that he liked to be punished by their senior sister. He did seem quite happy whenever she decided to pull out her whip to discipline him.

‘Luckily after a while, she switched to punishing just him and not the entire squad… otherwise Yang would have probably never survived but not like he is the only one … ‘

The young foundation establishment practitioner that wanted nothing more than to just train had a hard time focusing within this group. It was populated only by men with senior sister Lan Fei being the only woman around. Some of the other brothers, just like Yang Rong, gained a similar taste to his. Though some preferred to be praised than punished, others loved getting assigned chores, it was quite a strange group of individuals.

‘At least we aren’t alone here, the elder is keeping watch over us so the others haven’t been causing any problems.’

Some time had passed since they left their sect. After arriving at their destination they set out to a nearby settlement. To not get the common citizens involved too much their sect decided to create their own outposts. If any Long Clan attacks arrived at this location, then they wouldn’t involve the city nor would any damage spread. They just required the city to provide some necessities but were mostly self-sufficient.

“Get a move on, spread out the pylons as you have learned.”

The group nodded as this was their main reason for being here. They didn’t possess much fighting power on their own but had learned a lot of new things. The pylons were strange rods that they just needed to assemble in the correct way. When connected together they would form the basis for their main structure.

It was quite the sight, after everything was connected the thick rods started shining. The light pushed to the side and produced floor tiles as well as walls. What they assembled was something akin to a framework. In the middle were the base materials that consisted of things like spirit iron and building blocks. When surrounded by these pylons it created a chain reaction.

“How did they create this technology…”

“No one really knows, it is rumored that it was thanks to our Patriarch…”

All of them stopped and looked as if the base materials disappeared before them. They filled out the empty spaces between the framework and connected to the thick rods. Soon a structure that looked like a large castle fort was created. The walls were made out of special stones and reinforced by metal. On the outside, it looked like a medieval castle surrounded by twelve large towers. Each one was occupied and assembled by another squad with their being the last one to finish their project.

“This actually worked…?”

“What do you mean, did you think they would send us out here for nothing?”

“Well… I thought it wouldn’t look as magnificent, it even has our sect’s symbol on the main gate!”

It was understandable for Yang Rong to doubt the procedure as during their training they only assembled smaller structures. No one wanted to waste many materials so they usually just practiced by assembling smaller walls. The person that was responsible for this technology was hovering above them and had the actual keys himself.
All of the people that were gathered here spotted them looking over from a distance. His form was shrouded in some type of dark veil that had expanded over the whole construction. It created a strange dark dome that didn’t allow any light to get inside.

Everyone was stunned at first but soon they realised that it was some type of hiding technique. Even if people were flying over them no one would be able to find them. This was confirmed after they spotted a few strange cultivators patrolling the skies.

“I know that symbol, it’s a branch clan associated with the Long Clan, they actually appeared!”

“Yes… but they really can’t see us here. This new elder must specialize in illusory techniques!”

“This is great, we won’t have to fight them!”

The soldiers cheered as they saw the group of people move along. Normally they would have probably attacked them and called for reinforcements.

“They must have been a scout unit, does this mean that they are trying to create their own base nearby?”

“It could be possible but they won’t be able to beat us!’

……

“It does look like a quick assembly in a strategy game… and that scout unit, I should use a tracking technique on them.”

While the castle was being assembled he performed a tiny technique that attached a symbol to one of the robes of the people that were scouting. With this, he would be able to follow after them to their own hidden base and remove any potential threats almost instantly.

After finishing up his technique he glanced back to what was being created. Everything was done through his faction system. The first requirement was the location, it needed to be close to a settlement and within the limits of his faction. The next one was the resources that needed to be placed within the range of the construction. Lastly, someone needed to create a hollow scaffolding for the large structure.

‘Thanks to Bob I don’t need to be there for the creation but it won’t be assembled without involving some spirit points.’

Thanks to his lands becoming really massive he was given a lot of passive spirit point income. This was a quick-build faction feature. It was actually possible to create a structure by only involving spirit points but the cost would skyrocket. By having his people perform the outline for creation everything was minimized.

‘Good, now the cities won’t get involved and the Long Clan will have no excuse to pillage them for resources.’

He nodded while flying down into the castle. Usually in wars like this people would use an excuse to rob others of their valuables. It was far less costly to fortify a position in an existing city which usually also had its own defensive formations. While he cloaked the whole castle with his darkness technique, he wouldn’t always be here.

The task of creating a proper defensive formation along with the power source belonged to the core formation experts and him. It would take at least a day until everything was done properly and he would see to it that it did. Thus the minutes turned into hours and he continued to work.

‘This is actually a bit more relaxing than I anticipated…’

After spending years cultivating without much else going on he had grown a bit weary. This was a nice change of pace, performing techniques and tasks that weren’t all that hard was a breath of fresh air. It actually felt like his mind was clearing out and perhaps if he managed to focus on the things here then his next cultivation session would offer him a breakthrough.

‘That about does it…’

“Everyone, please stand still and don’t move until the formation takes effect…”

“Yes, Elder!”

Everyone had gathered in the courtyard while the formation was activated. On the first run, it would scan everyone from this fort and input them into something like a database. Only the people from this company with the proper clearance would be able to leisurely traverse the barrier now. Everyone else would be forced to remain outside until someone from inside opened a path. This allowed them to protect themselves from potential spies or infiltrators that tried impersonating their own people. Even if they managed to imitate a clearance from another stronghold, they wouldn’t be able to just get into this one.

“Well then, I think that completes the main mission but a new special one will soon commence.”

“A special mission, Elder?”

“Yes, that scouting unit that was here the other day hasn’t moved much.”

“Does that mean?”

“Yes, you are fast to catch on Lan Fei, they must have a base there and we will attack it…”

He proclaimed while everyone nodded. Their eyes had a certain passion, all of them wanted to move and confront the boogieman of the empire. The Long Clan was a force that everyone knew and everyone wanted to beat. The chance for the young cultivators here to gain some glory had come and they would take it.